{'question': 'What did they traverse without?', 'source': 'In this state they traversed without change, except of horses and pace, all the mire-deep leagues that lay between them and the capital.', 'answer': 'without change'}
{'question': 'Who did he deliver to?', 'source': 'Then he delivered to the escort, drunk and sober, a receipt for the escorted, and requested him to dismount.', 'answer': 'to the escort'}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner obey?', 'source': 'The prisoner obeyed, and a guard of two armed patriots attended them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would it be elsewhere?', 'source': "It would be an impertinence elsewhere, but it is not so here, to ask your name and condition?''", 'answer': 'an impertinence'}
{'question': 'Who will see?', 'source': '``You will see.', 'answer': 'Charles Darnay'}
{'question': 'What did his new charge accompany him by locking behind them?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'by corridor and staircase'}
{'question': 'What shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': 'a few'}
{'question': "Are such not Charles Darnay's orders?", 'source': '``Such are not my orders.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner walk to and fro in his cell?', 'source': 'The prisoner walked to and fro in his cell, counting its measurement, and the roar of the city arose like muffled drums with a wild swell of voices added to them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Indeed am Charles Darnay lost here?', 'source': '``Indeed I am lost here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who turned their heads?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': 'a few passers'}
{'question': 'What were these refinements by the prison manners and gloom?', 'source': 'So strangely clouded were these refinements by the prison manners and gloom, so spectral did they become in the inappropriate squalor and misery through which they were seen, that Charles Darnay seemed to stand in a company of the dead.', 'answer': 'strangely clouded'}
{'question': "Who started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning?", 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who could he not conceal from that the aspect of affairs was very alarming?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': 'from himself'}
{'question': 'Did and condemn as a traitor?', 'source': "and condemned as a traitor.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do an excited orator dread nothing distinctly of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child?', 'source': 'Of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child, he foreshadowed the likelihood, or the certainty; but, beyond this, he dreaded nothing distinctly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his new charge accompany him by clanging?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'by corridor and staircase'}
{'question': 'Did all strike the new-comer motionless?', 'source': 'It struck him motionless.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the traveller fare slowly on one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two?', 'source': 'The traveller fared slowly on his way, who fared towards Paris from England in the autumn of the year one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two.', 'answer': 'on his way'}
{'question': 'Where is my duty?', 'source': 'My duty is to my country and the People.', 'answer': 'to my country and the People'}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner count the measurement again?', 'source': 'The prisoner counted the measurement again, and paced faster, to draw his mind with him from that latter repetition.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was observable on familiar things which made this wild ride unreal the seeming rarity of sleep among the many wild changes?', 'source': 'Among the many wild changes observable on familiar things which made this wild ride unreal, not the least was the seeming rarity of sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who could an escort not conceal from that the aspect of affairs was very alarming?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': 'from himself'}
{'question': 'Did an escort stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle say:?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he take note of?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': 'of these things'}
{'question': 'Did Charles Darnay cross the room to a grated door where many voices gave him good wishes and encouragement?', 'source': 'There was a murmur of commiseration as Charles Darnay crossed the room to a grated door where the gaoler awaited him, and many voices-- among which, the soft and compassionate voices of women were conspicuous-- gave him good wishes and encouragement.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the silence the fainter hope?', 'source': 'The deeper he sank into this silence, the fainter hope there was-- or so Darnay thought-- of his softening in any slight degree.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they come to when the streets were filled with people?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': 'to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide,'}
{'question': 'Did the travel in the night?', 'source': 'They traveled in the night, halting an hour or two after daybreak, and lying by until the twilight fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did some of these people know their turn for to be so far off?', 'source': 'Some of these people knew their turn for examination to be so far off, that they lay down on the ground to sleep or smoke, while others talked together, or loitered about.', 'answer': 'for examination'}
{'question': 'What did he stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle resume as his safest place?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did the set forth with driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'with the sharp rain'}
{'question': 'Who did his new charge accompany by corridor and staircase locking behind them?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What accompanied him by corridor and staircase locking behind them?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'his new charge'}
{'question': 'Who had completely isolated him?', 'source': 'The escort and the universal watchfulness had completely isolated him.', 'answer': 'the escort and the universal watchfulness'}
{'question': 'What is what he meant when he said your life was not your own?', 'source': "That is what he meant when he said your life was not your own.''", 'answer': 'that'}
{'question': 'What did the crowd roar at this?', 'source': 'At this the crowd roared approval.', 'answer': 'approval'}
{'question': 'Was the future the unknown future?', 'source': 'Troubled as the future was, it was the unknown future, and in its obscurity there was ignorant hope.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who came to your house to reclaim her father?', 'source': '``My wife came to your house to reclaim her father?', 'answer': 'my wife'}
{'question': 'Did an officer go on writing?', 'source': 'He said it with a hard smile, and went on writing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is the smith's life forfeit to the people?", 'source': 'His life is forfeit to the people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had read over to himself what he had written?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'an officer'}
{'question': 'When did they travel?', 'source': 'They traveled in the night, halting an hour or two after daybreak, and lying by until the twilight fell.', 'answer': 'in the night'}
{'question': 'What did Citizen Defarge sink into this silence?', 'source': 'The deeper he sank into this silence, the fainter hope there was-- or so Darnay thought-- of his softening in any slight degree.', 'answer': 'there was Darnay thought'}
{'question': 'What cursed life is not his own!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'his'}
{'question': 'Who had them in his cap?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': 'the drunken patriot'}
{'question': 'Who did his new charge accompany him by corridor and staircase locking behind?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'behind them'}
{'question': 'Who could I dispense with?', 'source': "``Citizen, I desire nothing more than to get to Paris, though I could dispense with the escort.''", 'answer': 'with the escort'}
{'question': 'What did he accompany his conductor into?', 'source': 'He accompanied his conductor into a guard-room, smelling of common wine and tobacco, where certain soldiers and patriots, asleep and awake, drunk and sober, and in various neutral states between sleeping and waking, drunkenness and sobriety, were standing and lying about.', 'answer': 'into a guard-room'}
{'question': 'Who did he leave?', 'source': 'He left escort and escorted without saying a word, however, and went into the guard-room; meanwhile, they sat upon their horses outside the gate.', 'answer': 'escort'}
{'question': 'What did he stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle resume it as?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': 'as his safest place'}
{'question': 'When may you buy your food, and nothing more?', 'source': "At present, you may buy your food, and nothing more.''", 'answer': 'at present'}
{'question': 'What did he turn at?', 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': 'at the grated door'}
{'question': 'What may you buy at present?', 'source': "At present, you may buy your food, and nothing more.''", 'answer': 'your food, and nothing more'}
{'question': 'What did his new charge accompany him by corridor and staircase locking behind?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'behind them'}
{'question': 'Was an aristocrat; otherwise no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the barrier closed?', 'source': 'The barrier was closed and strongly guarded when they rode up to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he go into?', 'source': 'He left escort and escorted without saying a word, however, and went into the guard-room; meanwhile, they sat upon their horses outside the gate.', 'answer': 'into the guard-room'}
{'question': 'Was the traveller as little surprised as a man could be?', 'source': 'And he was, therefore, as little surprised as a man could be, to find himself awakened at the small inn to which he had been remitted until morning, in the middle of the night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the wicket lead upward?', 'source': 'The wicket opened on a stone staircase, leading upward.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was corridor and staircase many doors?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who had handed it to Defarge ``In secret''?", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the two patriots turn?', 'source': 'He did so, and the two patriots, leading his tired horse, turned and rode away without entering the city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where did they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'in this state'}
{'question': 'What is of my own will?', 'source': "Do you not see me here, in France, of my own will?''", 'answer': 'France'}
{'question': 'Who set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had he been days upon?', 'source': 'He had been days upon his journey in France alone, when he went to bed tired out, in a little town on the high road, still a long way from Paris.', 'answer': 'upon his journey in France alone'}
{'question': 'What so encompassed him?', 'source': 'The universal watchfulness so encompassed him, that if he had been taken in a net, or were being forwarded to his destination in a cage, he could not have felt his freedom more completely gone.', 'answer': 'the universal watchfulness'}
{'question': 'What had he heard on the road?', 'source': 'On the road (except at Beauvais) he had heard absolutely nothing.', 'answer': 'absolutely nothing'}
{'question': 'Who scarcely noticed him?', 'source': 'The very children scarcely noticed him.', 'answer': 'the very children'}
{'question': 'Who traveled in the night?', 'source': 'They traveled in the night, halting an hour or two after daybreak, and lying by until the twilight fell.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who is a cursed aristocrat?', 'source': "``You are a cursed emigrant,'' cried a farrier, making at him in a furious manner through the press, hammer in hand; ``and you are a cursed aristocrat!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Was the strong wicket not dark?', 'source': 'It struck cold and damp, but was not dark.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner pace faster?', 'source': 'The prisoner counted the measurement again, and paced faster, to draw his mind with him from that latter repetition.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did my wife come to your house to reclaim?', 'source': '``My wife came to your house to reclaim her father?', 'answer': 'her father'}
{'question': 'What do he dread nothing distinctly of?', 'source': 'Of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child, he foreshadowed the likelihood, or the certainty; but, beyond this, he dreaded nothing distinctly.', 'answer': 'of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child'}
{'question': 'Who is the sworn servant?', 'source': 'I am the sworn servant of both, against you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do I keep a wine-shop in the Quarter Saint Antoine?', 'source': '``My name is Defarge, and I keep a wine-shop in the Quarter Saint Antoine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he make to say:?', 'source': 'He, therefore, made haste to say:', 'answer': 'haste'}
{'question': 'What did the smith curse life is not!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'his own'}
{'question': 'When has it lasted?', 'source': "But take courage; several members of our society have been in secret, at first, and it has lasted but a short time.''", 'answer': 'but a short time'}
{'question': 'Who are you a cursed?', 'source': "``You are a cursed emigrant,'' cried a farrier, making at him in a furious manner through the press, hammer in hand; ``and you are a cursed aristocrat!''", 'answer': 'aristocrat'}
{'question': 'Did both walk on in silence?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was no more done?', 'source': 'The farrier struck a blow upon them with his hammer, and the crowd groaned; but, no more was done.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the previous identification so strict?', 'source': 'A numerous medley of men and women, not to mention beasts and vehicles of various sorts, was waiting to issue forth; but, the previous identification was so strict, that they filtered through the barrier very slowly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did he start with on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning?", 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': 'with it'}
{'question': 'What did he pay for his escort?', 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': 'a heavy price'}
{'question': 'Who did the drunken patriot produce?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who produced them?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': 'the drunken patriot'}
{'question': 'What did he request him to?', 'source': 'Then he delivered to the escort, drunk and sober, a receipt for the escorted, and requested him to dismount.', 'answer': 'to dismount'}
{'question': 'Was the half five paces?', 'source': "``Five paces by four and a half, five paces by four and a half, five paces by four and a half.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had ascended forty steps?', 'source': 'When they had ascended forty steps (the prisoner of half an hour already counted them), the gaoler opened a low black door, and they passed into a solitary cell.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Who wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge ``In secret?''", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'the officer'}
{'question': 'What has lasted but a short time?', 'source': "But take courage; several members of our society have been in secret, at first, and it has lasted but a short time.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did his curse is not his own!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'life'}
{'question': 'What did some of these people know for examination to be so far off?', 'source': 'Some of these people knew their turn for examination to be so far off, that they lay down on the ground to sleep or smoke, while others talked together, or loitered about.', 'answer': 'their turn'}
{'question': "What did an ominous crowd gather to see him, ``Down with the emigrant!''", 'source': "An ominous crowd gathered to see him dismount of the posting-yard, and many voices called out loudly, ``Down with the emigrant!''", 'answer': 'dismount of the posting-yard, and many voices called out loudly'}
{'question': 'What had ascended forty steps?', 'source': 'When they had ascended forty steps (the prisoner of half an hour already counted them), the gaoler opened a low black door, and they passed into a solitary cell.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Is all here so unprecedented so sudden and unfair?', 'source': 'All here is so unprecedented, so changed, so sudden and unfair, that I am absolutely lost.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did an excited orator know now?', 'source': 'That he had fallen among far greater dangers than those which had developed themselves when he left England, he of course knew now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do he admit to himself that he might not have made?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': 'this journey'}
{'question': "Is without's wife Evremonde?", 'source': "Where is your wife, Evremonde?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who came into a large vaulted chamber?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'When had he sat in his saddle?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': 'some half-hour'}
{'question': 'What did his curse life is not!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'his own'}
{'question': 'Who then rode forward again when all the town was asleep?', 'source': 'They rested on some straw in a loft until the middle of the night, and then rode forward again when all the town was asleep.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did my wife come to to reclaim her father?', 'source': '``My wife came to your house to reclaim her father?', 'answer': 'to your house'}
{'question': 'What had he sat in some half-hour?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': 'in his saddle'}
{'question': "What did he start with it on o'clock in the morning?", 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': 'on the wet, wet roads at three'}
{'question': 'What did he say it with?', 'source': 'He said it with a hard smile, and went on writing.', 'answer': 'with a hard smile'}
{'question': 'What do I not understand?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': 'the meaning of the term'}
{'question': 'Who has heard them say so?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who will do nothing for you?', 'source': "I will do nothing for you.''", 'answer': 'Citizen Defarge'}
{'question': 'Were the escort so wretchedly clothed?', 'source': 'The escort were so wretchedly clothed, that they twisted straw round their bare legs, and thatched their ragged shoulders to keep the wet off.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the unknown future?', 'source': 'Troubled as the future was, it was the unknown future, and in its obscurity there was ignorant hope.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Who would nothing but the production of the afflicted Gabelle's letter from his prison of the Abbaye have got on so far?", 'source': "Nothing but the production of the afflicted Gabelle's letter from his prison of the Abbaye would have got him on so far.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did some of these people know their turn for examination to be off?', 'source': 'Some of these people knew their turn for examination to be so far off, that they lay down on the ground to sleep or smoke, while others talked together, or loitered about.', 'answer': 'so far'}
{'question': 'What then rode forward again when all the town was asleep?', 'source': 'They rested on some straw in a loft until the middle of the night, and then rode forward again when all the town was asleep.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What is his life forfeit to?', 'source': 'His life is forfeit to the people.', 'answer': 'to the people'}
{'question': 'Does the good patriot say?', 'source': "``It is as the good patriot says,'' observed the timid functionary.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the gaoler gone?', 'source': "When the gaoler was gone, he thought in the same wandering way, ``Now am I left, as if I were dead.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they set forth with driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'with the sharp rain'}
{'question': 'What were not so dark as they would appear?', 'source': 'And yet his misgivings were not so dark as, imagined by the light of this later time, they would appear.', 'answer': 'his misgivings'}
{'question': 'What struck him motionless?', 'source': 'It struck him motionless.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did they set forth with the sharp rain driving in: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'in their faces'}
{'question': 'Who had sanded it?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did Charles Darnay request the speaker to take notice that he was a free traveller and French citizen?', 'source': 'Naturally struck by the disagreeable word, Charles Darnay requested the speaker to take notice that he was a free traveller and French citizen, in charge of an escort which the disturbed state of the country had imposed upon him, and which he had paid for.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had they ascended?', 'source': 'When they had ascended forty steps (the prisoner of half an hour already counted them), the gaoler opened a low black door, and they passed into a solitary cell.', 'answer': 'forty steps'}
{'question': 'When did he start with it on the wet, wet roads at three?', 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': "o'clock in the morning"}
{'question': 'What did he take?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': 'note of these things'}
{'question': 'Had an officer read over to himself what he had written?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they come into?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': 'into a large vaulted chamber'}
{'question': 'What did he turn from it with?', 'source': "Stopping then, to look down at the mattress, he turned from it with a sick feeling, and thought, ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death.''", 'answer': 'with a sick feeling'}
{'question': 'What said:?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': 'an escort stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle'}
{'question': 'Is a always as the good patriot?', 'source': "``It is always as the good patriot says,'' observed the functionary.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What had he handed to Defarge ``In secret''?", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did Charles Darnay cross the room to a grated door where the gaoler awaited him?', 'source': 'There was a murmur of commiseration as Charles Darnay crossed the room to a grated door where the gaoler awaited him, and many voices-- among which, the soft and compassionate voices of women were conspicuous-- gave him good wishes and encouragement.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Citizen Defarge sink into this silence there was Darnay thought?', 'source': 'The deeper he sank into this silence, the fainter hope there was-- or so Darnay thought-- of his softening in any slight degree.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Charles Darnay say, ``I have no choice''?", 'source': "``I have no choice,'' said Charles Darnay.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where will he be judged?', 'source': "He will be judged at Paris.''", 'answer': 'at Paris'}
{'question': "Who has some free communication with the world outside, ``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly''?", 'source': "``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly, shall I have some free communication with the world outside?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do he admit to that he might not have made this journey?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': "Did the officer write until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded the stolid reply, and handed it to Defarge ``In secret?''", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is he?', 'source': '``He is a traitor since the decree.', 'answer': 'a traitor since the decree'}
{'question': 'Who am I?', 'source': 'I am the sworn servant of both, against you.', 'answer': 'the sworn servant'}
{'question': "Was the ``sharp female newly-born, and called La Guillotine,'' hardly known to him, or to the generality of people, by name?", 'source': "The ``sharp female newly-born, and called La Guillotine,'' was hardly known to him, or to the generality of people, by name.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is my duty to?', 'source': 'My duty is to my country and the People.', 'answer': 'to my country and the People'}
{'question': "Did an ominous crowd gather to see him dismount of the posting-yard, and many voices called out loudly, ``Down with the emigrant!''", 'source': "An ominous crowd gathered to see him dismount of the posting-yard, and many voices called out loudly, ``Down with the emigrant!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who walked on in silence?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did the set forth with the sharp rain driving in: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'in their faces'}
{'question': "Did the few words that an excited orator caught from this man's lips leave Paris?", 'source': "The few words that he caught from this man's lips, first made it known to Charles Darnay that the king was in prison, and that the foreign ambassadors had one and all left Paris.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are you in?', 'source': "``You are a cursed emigrant,'' cried a farrier, making at him in a furious manner through the press, hammer in hand; ``and you are a cursed aristocrat!''", 'answer': 'a cursed emigrant hammer in hand'}
{'question': 'Are you a cursed emigrant hammer in hand?', 'source': "``You are a cursed emigrant,'' cried a farrier, making at him in a furious manner through the press, hammer in hand; ``and you are a cursed aristocrat!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did an excited orator arrive at the prison of La Force with this on his mind?', 'source': 'With this on his mind, which was enough to carry into a dreary prison courtyard, he arrived at the prison of La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had an officer finished?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they walk on in?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': 'in silence'}
{'question': 'What do I demand no more than?', 'source': 'I demand no more than the opportunity to do so without delay.', 'answer': 'than the opportunity to do so without delay'}
{'question': 'Who am I not?', 'source': "I am not a traitor.''", 'answer': 'a traitor'}
{'question': 'Who did it strike motionless?', 'source': 'It struck him motionless.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did his way fare towards Paris from England in the autumn of the year?', 'source': 'The traveller fared slowly on his way, who fared towards Paris from England in the autumn of the year one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is your wife?', 'source': "Where is your wife, Evremonde?''", 'answer': 'Evremonde'}
{'question': 'What did as soon as he could make his voice hear?', 'source': "Checking the postmaster, who was for turning his horse's head to the yard (the drunken patriot sat composedly in his saddle looking on, with the line round his wrist), Darnay said, as soon as he could make his voice heard:", 'answer': 'checking the postmaster'}
{'question': 'Who has heard of me?', 'source': "Possibly you have heard of me.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': 'in this state'}
{'question': 'Who will Citizen Defarge do nothing for?', 'source': "I will do nothing for you.''", 'answer': 'for you'}
{'question': 'When was it?', 'source': 'Troubled as the future was, it was the unknown future, and in its obscurity there was ignorant hope.', 'answer': 'the unknown future'}
{'question': "Would nothing but the production of the afflicted Gabelle's letter from his prison of the Abbaye have got him on so far?", 'source': "Nothing but the production of the afflicted Gabelle's letter from his prison of the Abbaye would have got him on so far.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did a few shake their fingers at as an aristocrat; otherwise was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': 'at him'}
{'question': 'What do the words so much regret!', 'source': 'We so much regret it!', 'answer': '``Ah, what a pity!'}
{'question': 'Who is it always as?', 'source': "``It is always as the good patriot says,'' observed the functionary.", 'answer': 'as the good patriot'}
{'question': 'Could a man be?', 'source': 'And he was, therefore, as little surprised as a man could be, to find himself awakened at the small inn to which he had been remitted until morning, in the middle of the night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the few words that he caught from this man's lips leave Paris?", 'source': "The few words that he caught from this man's lips, first made it known to Charles Darnay that the king was in prison, and that the foreign ambassadors had one and all left Paris.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was four and a half five paces?', 'source': "``Five paces by four and a half, five paces by four and a half, five paces by four and a half.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his mind enough to carry into a dreary prison courtyard?', 'source': 'With this on his mind, which was enough to carry into a dreary prison courtyard, he arrived at the prison of La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What do I have outside, ``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly''?", 'source': "``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly, shall I have some free communication with the world outside?''", 'answer': 'some free communication with the world'}
{'question': 'What had he sanded?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who have I heard say so?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': "Did the same personage in authority cast his eyes over Gabelle's letter?", 'source': "Casting his eyes over Gabelle's letter, the same personage in authority showed some disorder and surprise, and looked at Darnay with a close attention.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who can say what it is?', 'source': "You can say what it is.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did Defarge glance darkly at him for answer?', 'source': 'Defarge glanced darkly at him for answer, and walked on in a steady and set silence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are not my orders?', 'source': '``Such are not my orders.', 'answer': 'such'}
{'question': 'What have I heard say so?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Whose hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight did it close under forever?', 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': "under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight"}
{'question': 'Do the words so much regret ``Ah, what a pity! !', 'source': 'We so much regret it!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do without doubt?', 'source': '``Without doubt.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is not a traitor?', 'source': "I am not a traitor.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did an officer of a coarse, dark aspect, preside over these?', 'source': 'Some registers were lying open on a desk, and an officer of a coarse, dark aspect, presided over these.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the long unreal ride some progress of disease that had brought him to these gloomy shades!', 'source': 'Surely, the long unreal ride some progress of disease that had brought him to these gloomy shades!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did a few shake at him as an aristocrat; otherwise was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': 'their fingers'}
{'question': 'Who have you heard of?', 'source': "Possibly you have heard of me.''", 'answer': 'of me'}
{'question': 'Were an officer here?', 'source': "``We have new laws, Evremonde, and new offences, since you were here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his difficulty at the guard-house in this small place been such?', 'source': 'His difficulty at the guard-house in this small place had been such, that he felt his journey to have come to a crisis.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had the traveller's difficulty at the guard-house in this small place been such?", 'source': 'His difficulty at the guard-house in this small place had been such, that he felt his journey to have come to a crisis.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sink into this silence there was Darnay thought?', 'source': 'The deeper he sank into this silence, the fainter hope there was-- or so Darnay thought-- of his softening in any slight degree.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does he raise?', 'source': "Then he added, raising his voice, ``I grieve to inform the society-- in secret.''", 'answer': 'his voice'}
{'question': 'What did he sink into this silence?', 'source': 'The deeper he sank into this silence, the fainter hope there was-- or so Darnay thought-- of his softening in any slight degree.', 'answer': 'there was Darnay thought'}
{'question': "Did he say to Darnay's conductor?", 'source': "``Citizen Defarge,'' said he to Darnay's conductor, as he took a slip of paper to write on.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did national muskets and sabres ride one on either side of him?', 'source': 'The escort were two mounted patriots in red caps and tri-coloured cockades, armed with national muskets and sabres, who rode one on either side of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the new-comer recoil from this company in the instinctive association of prisoners with shameful crime and disgrace?', 'source': 'In the instinctive association of prisoners with shameful crime and disgrace, the new-comer recoiled from this company.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it close under forever?', 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': "under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight"}
{'question': 'Did they rest on some straw in a loft until the middle of the night?', 'source': 'They rested on some straw in a loft until the middle of the night, and then rode forward again when all the town was asleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do he see to?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': 'how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets'}
{'question': 'Did their mouths sit down on the bed?', 'source': 'Awakened by a timid local functionary and three armed patriots in rough red caps and with pipes in their mouths, who sat down on the bed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is consigned?', 'source': "You are consigned, Evremonde, to the prison of La Force.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What will he be judged at?', 'source': "He will be judged at Paris.''", 'answer': 'at Paris'}
{'question': "Was the postmaster for turning his horse's head to the yard?", 'source': "Checking the postmaster, who was for turning his horse's head to the yard (the drunken patriot sat composedly in his saddle looking on, with the line round his wrist), Darnay said, as soon as he could make his voice heard:", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the crowning unreality of his long unreal ride, ?', 'source': 'But the crowning unreality of his long unreal ride, was, their all at once rising to receive him, with every refinement of manner known to the time, and with all the engaging graces and courtesies of life.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the farrier strike a blow upon them with his hammer, and the crowd groaned?', 'source': 'The farrier struck a blow upon them with his hammer, and the crowd groaned; but, no more was done.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who so much regret it!', 'source': 'We so much regret it!', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What do he dread of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child?', 'source': 'Of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child, he foreshadowed the likelihood, or the certainty; but, beyond this, he dreaded nothing distinctly.', 'answer': 'nothing distinctly'}
{'question': 'Does the gentleman follow the chief gaoler with his eyes?', 'source': "``But I hope,'' said the gentleman, following the chief gaoler with his eyes, who moved across the room, ``that you are not in secret?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the drunken patriot produce the papers of this prisoner?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the future?', 'source': 'Troubled as the future was, it was the unknown future, and in its obscurity there was ignorant hope.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it be an impertinence elsewhere?', 'source': "It would be an impertinence elsewhere, but it is not so here, to ask your name and condition?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did one add ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion?", 'source': "Three turnkeys who entered responsive to a bell she rang, echoed the sentiment, and one added, ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What resumed it as his safest place?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': 'he stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle'}
{'question': 'Who rang?', 'source': "Three turnkeys who entered responsive to a bell she rang, echoed the sentiment, and one added, ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did the drunken patriot have the papers of this prisoner in his cap?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his eyes move across the room?', 'source': "``But I hope,'' said the gentleman, following the chief gaoler with his eyes, who moved across the room, ``that you are not in secret?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Charles Darnay feel it hopeless to entreat him further?', 'source': 'Charles Darnay felt it hopeless to entreat him further, and his pride was touched besides.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his new charge accompany him by corridor and staircase locking behind them?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the frightful deeds that were to be soon done, probably unimagined at that time in the brains of the doers?', 'source': 'The frightful deeds that were to be soon done, were probably unimagined at that time in the brains of the doers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the sentiment add ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion?", 'source': "Three turnkeys who entered responsive to a bell she rang, echoed the sentiment, and one added, ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he arrive at the prison of La Force with this on his mind?', 'source': 'With this on his mind, which was enough to carry into a dreary prison courtyard, he arrived at the prison of La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he heard absolutely nothing on the road?', 'source': 'On the road (except at Beauvais) he had heard absolutely nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he think ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death?''", 'source': "Stopping then, to look down at the mattress, he turned from it with a sick feeling, and thought, ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Defarge look straight before him?', 'source': 'Defarge spoke, always looking straight before him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did some of these people know their turn for examination to be so far off?', 'source': 'Some of these people knew their turn for examination to be so far off, that they lay down on the ground to sleep or smoke, while others talked together, or loitered about.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they traverse without change?', 'source': 'In this state they traversed without change, except of horses and pace, all the mire-deep leagues that lay between them and the capital.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the timid functionary observe, ``It is as the good patriot says''?", 'source': "``It is as the good patriot says,'' observed the timid functionary.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he a traitor since the decree?', 'source': '``He is a traitor since the decree.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do an excited orator admit to himself?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': 'that he might not have made this journey'}
{'question': 'Were a very few French leagues of his journey accomplished?', 'source': 'A very few French leagues of his journey were accomplished, when Charles Darnay began to perceive that for him along these country roads there was no hope of return until he should have been declared a good citizen at Paris.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn at the grated door?', 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do Charles Darnay have some free communication with the world outside, ``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly''?", 'source': "``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly, shall I have some free communication with the world outside?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the same personage take note of these things?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will he be judged at Paris?', 'source': "He will be judged at Paris.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will I do nothing for?', 'source': "I will do nothing for you.''", 'answer': 'for you'}
{'question': 'Did the traveller fare slowly on his way one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two?', 'source': 'The traveller fared slowly on his way, who fared towards Paris from England in the autumn of the year one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he deliver to the escort?', 'source': 'Then he delivered to the escort, drunk and sober, a receipt for the escorted, and requested him to dismount.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do we so much regret!', 'source': 'We so much regret it!', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was the chief at length taking up his keys?', 'source': "said the chief, at length taking up his keys, ``come with me, emigrant.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the escort and the universal watchfulness completely isolated him?', 'source': 'The escort and the universal watchfulness had completely isolated him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the drunken patriot produce them?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been days upon his journey in France alone?', 'source': 'He had been days upon his journey in France alone, when he went to bed tired out, in a little town on the high road, still a long way from Paris.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I demand no more than the opportunity to do so without delay?', 'source': 'I demand no more than the opportunity to do so without delay.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were strangely clouded these refinements by the prison manners and gloom?', 'source': 'So strangely clouded were these refinements by the prison manners and gloom, so spectral did they become in the inappropriate squalor and misery through which they were seen, that Charles Darnay seemed to stand in a company of the dead.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle resume it as his safest place?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the two patriots lead his tired horse?', 'source': 'He did so, and the two patriots, leading his tired horse, turned and rode away without entering the city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go into the guard-room?', 'source': 'He left escort and escorted without saying a word, however, and went into the guard-room; meanwhile, they sat upon their horses outside the gate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the functionary observe, ``It is always as the good patriot says''?", 'source': "``It is always as the good patriot says,'' observed the functionary.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Defarge motion with the paper to the prisoner?', 'source': 'Defarge motioned with the paper to the prisoner that he must accompany him.', 'answer': 'that he must accompany him'}
{'question': 'Did he leave escort?', 'source': 'He left escort and escorted without saying a word, however, and went into the guard-room; meanwhile, they sat upon their horses outside the gate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is all the same?', 'source': 'It is all the same.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was the gaoler left with his wife?', 'source': 'exclaimed the gaoler, left with his wife.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they come into a large vaulted chamber?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a few passers turn their heads?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I the sworn servant?', 'source': 'I am the sworn servant of both, against you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not understand the meaning of the term?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he accompany his conductor into a guard-room?', 'source': 'He accompanied his conductor into a guard-room, smelling of common wine and tobacco, where certain soldiers and patriots, asleep and awake, drunk and sober, and in various neutral states between sleeping and waking, drunkenness and sobriety, were standing and lying about.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make haste to say:?', 'source': 'He, therefore, made haste to say:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Or are Friends you deceived?', 'source': '``Friends, you deceive yourselves, or you are deceived.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they sit upon their horses outside the gate?', 'source': 'He left escort and escorted without saying a word, however, and went into the guard-room; meanwhile, they sat upon their horses outside the gate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his pride touched besides?', 'source': 'Charles Darnay felt it hopeless to entreat him further, and his pride was touched besides.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could I dispense with the escort?', 'source': "``Citizen, I desire nothing more than to get to Paris, though I could dispense with the escort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can you say?', 'source': "You can say what it is.''", 'answer': 'what it is'}
{'question': 'What could he not conceal from himself?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': 'that the aspect of affairs was very alarming'}
{'question': 'Did his new charge accompany him by corridor and staircase clanging?', 'source': 'Through the dismal prison twilight, his new charge accompanied him by corridor and staircase, many doors clanging and locking behind them, until they came into a large, low, vaulted chamber, crowded with prisoners of both sexes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the gaoler's wife merely reply, ``One must have patience, my dear!''", 'source': "The gaoler's wife, being provided with no answer to the question, merely replied, ``One must have patience, my dear!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the universal watchfulness so encompass him?', 'source': 'The universal watchfulness so encompassed him, that if he had been taken in a net, or were being forwarded to his destination in a cage, he could not have felt his freedom more completely gone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they travel in the night?', 'source': 'They traveled in the night, halting an hour or two after daybreak, and lying by until the twilight fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is France of my own will?', 'source': "Do you not see me here, in France, of my own will?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do an excited orator admit to himself that he might not have made this journey?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they ascended forty steps?', 'source': 'When they had ascended forty steps (the prisoner of half an hour already counted them), the gaoler opened a low black door, and they passed into a solitary cell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has it lasted but a short time?', 'source': "But take courage; several members of our society have been in secret, at first, and it has lasted but a short time.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pay a heavy price for his escort?', 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner count its measurement?', 'source': 'The prisoner walked to and fro in his cell, counting its measurement, and the roar of the city arose like muffled drums with a wild swell of voices added to them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you a cursed aristocrat?', 'source': "``You are a cursed emigrant,'' cried a farrier, making at him in a furious manner through the press, hammer in hand; ``and you are a cursed aristocrat!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take note of these things?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he admit to himself that he might not have made this journey?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the crowd roar approval at this?', 'source': 'At this the crowd roared approval.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the drunken patriot have them in his cap?', 'source': 'The drunken patriot had them in his cap, and produced them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did my wife come to your house to reclaim her father?', 'source': '``My wife came to your house to reclaim her father?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my name Defarge?', 'source': '``My name is Defarge, and I keep a wine-shop in the Quarter Saint Antoine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say it with a hard smile?', 'source': 'He said it with a hard smile, and went on writing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who stopped then?', 'source': "Stopping then, to look down at the mattress, he turned from it with a sick feeling, and thought, ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was it the unknown future?', 'source': 'Troubled as the future was, it was the unknown future, and in its obscurity there was ignorant hope.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did it close under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever?", 'source': "He turned at the grated door, to render the thanks of his heart; it closed under the gaoler's hand; and the apparitions vanished from his sight forever.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I heard?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': 'them say so'}
{'question': 'Did he request him to dismount?', 'source': 'Then he delivered to the escort, drunk and sober, a receipt for the escorted, and requested him to dismount.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle say:?', 'source': 'He stopped in the act of swinging himself out of his saddle, and, resuming it as his safest place, said:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Indeed who is lost here?', 'source': '``Indeed I am lost here.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who would appear?', 'source': 'And yet his misgivings were not so dark as, imagined by the light of this later time, they would appear.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "He must on to his journey's end?", 'source': "Whatever might befall now, he must on to his journey's end.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will I do for you?', 'source': "I will do nothing for you.''", 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': "Did he start with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning?", 'source': "Here he paid a heavy price for his escort, and hence he started with it on the wet, wet roads at three o'clock in the morning.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it strike cold and damp?', 'source': 'It struck cold and damp, but was not dark.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would appear?', 'source': 'And yet his misgivings were not so dark as, imagined by the light of this later time, they would appear.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Is my duty to my country and the People?', 'source': 'My duty is to my country and the People.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn from it with a sick feeling?', 'source': "Stopping then, to look down at the mattress, he turned from it with a sick feeling, and thought, ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go on writing?', 'source': 'He said it with a hard smile, and went on writing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they come to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he of course know now?', 'source': 'That he had fallen among far greater dangers than those which had developed themselves when he left England, he of course knew now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your wife Evremonde?', 'source': "Where is your wife, Evremonde?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they then ride forward again when all the town was asleep?', 'source': 'They rested on some straw in a loft until the middle of the night, and then rode forward again when all the town was asleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is not so here?', 'source': "It would be an impertinence elsewhere, but it is not so here, to ask your name and condition?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'May you buy your food, and nothing more at present?', 'source': "At present, you may buy your food, and nothing more.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you be visited?', 'source': 'You will be visited, and can ask then.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he as little surprised as a man could be?', 'source': 'And he was, therefore, as little surprised as a man could be, to find himself awakened at the small inn to which he had been remitted until morning, in the middle of the night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his curse!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'life is not his own'}
{'question': 'Is his life forfeit to the people?', 'source': 'His life is forfeit to the people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they walk on in silence?', 'source': 'As they walked on in silence, he could not but see how used the people were to the spectacle of prisoners passing along the streets.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his curse life is not his own!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he sat in his saddle some half-hour?', 'source': 'When he had sat in his saddle some half-hour, taking note of these things, Darnay found himself confronted by the same man in authority, who directed the guard to open the barrier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming?', 'source': 'But when they came to the town of Beauvais-- which they did at eventide, when the streets were filled with people-- he could not conceal from himself that the aspect of affairs was very alarming.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the smith curse!', 'source': "His cursed life is not his own!''", 'answer': 'life is not his own'}
{'question': 'Did the very children scarcely notice him?', 'source': 'The very children scarcely noticed him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I not a traitor?', 'source': "I am not a traitor.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is that what he meant when he said your life was not your own?', 'source': "That is what he meant when he said your life was not your own.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did as soon as he could make his voice hear checking the postmaster?', 'source': "Checking the postmaster, who was for turning his horse's head to the yard (the drunken patriot sat composedly in his saddle looking on, with the line round his wrist), Darnay said, as soon as he could make his voice heard:", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you consigned?', 'source': "You are consigned, Evremonde, to the prison of La Force.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it always as the good patriot?', 'source': "``It is always as the good patriot says,'' observed the functionary.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had he handed it to Defarge ``In secret''?", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you ask then?', 'source': 'You will be visited, and can ask then.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he read over to himself what he had written?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his misgivings not so dark as they would appear?', 'source': 'And yet his misgivings were not so dark as, imagined by the light of this later time, they would appear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do he admit to himself?', 'source': 'He could not but admit to himself that he might not have made this journey, if he could have foreseen the events of a few days.', 'answer': 'that he might not have made this journey'}
{'question': 'Was it not dark?', 'source': 'It struck cold and damp, but was not dark.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the officer write until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge ``In secret?''", 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had he read over to?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'to himself what he had written'}
{'question': "Do I have some free communication with the world outside, ``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly''?", 'source': "``In this prison that I am going to so unjustly, shall I have some free communication with the world outside?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had an officer read over to?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': 'to himself what he had written'}
{'question': 'Are such not my orders?', 'source': '``Such are not my orders.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he do so?', 'source': 'He did so, and the two patriots, leading his tired horse, turned and rode away without entering the city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it strike him motionless?', 'source': 'It struck him motionless.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she ring?', 'source': "Three turnkeys who entered responsive to a bell she rang, echoed the sentiment, and one added, ``For the love of Liberty;'' which sounded in that place like an inappropriate conclusion.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I heard them say so?', 'source': "``I do not understand the meaning of the term, but I have heard them say so.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he sanded it?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads in this state?', 'source': 'In this state they set forth with the sharp rain driving in their faces: clattering at a heavy dragoon trot over the uneven town pavement, and out upon the mire-deep roads.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it all the same?', 'source': 'It is all the same.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he raise his voice?', 'source': "Then he added, raising his voice, ``I grieve to inform the society-- in secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stop then?', 'source': "Stopping then, to look down at the mattress, he turned from it with a sick feeling, and thought, ``And here in these crawling creatures is the first condition of the body after death.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I do nothing for you?', 'source': "I will do nothing for you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he dread nothing distinctly of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child?', 'source': 'Of unjust treatment in detention and hardship, and in cruel separation from his wife and child, he foreshadowed the likelihood, or the certainty; but, beyond this, he dreaded nothing distinctly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have you heard of me?', 'source': "Possibly you have heard of me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Indeed am I lost here?', 'source': '``Indeed I am lost here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you say what it is?', 'source': "You can say what it is.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you see?', 'source': '``You will see.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would they appear?', 'source': 'And yet his misgivings were not so dark as, imagined by the light of this later time, they would appear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he finished?', 'source': "The officer wrote until he had finished, read over to himself what he had written, sanded it, and handed it to Defarge, with the words ``In secret.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a few shake their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work?', 'source': 'A few passers turned their heads, and a few shook their fingers at him as an aristocrat; otherwise, that a man in good clothes should be going to prison, was no more remarkable than that a labourer in working clothes should be going to work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it not so here?', 'source': "It would be an impertinence elsewhere, but it is not so here, to ask your name and condition?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you here?', 'source': "``We have new laws, Evremonde, and new offences, since you were here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do we so much regret it!', 'source': 'We so much regret it!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is that?', 'source': "That is what he meant when he said your life was not your own.''", 'answer': 'what he meant when he said your life was not your own'}
{'question': 'Who do I tell that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "What said, ``You scarcely seem to like your hand''?", 'source': "``You scarcely seem to like your hand,'' said Sydney, with the greatest composure.", 'answer': 'Sydney'}
{'question': 'Was and come into the dark room here?', 'source': "Come into the dark room here, and let us have one final word alone.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked?', 'source': 'It was a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked, making guns for the Army of the Republic.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'When is in short this?', 'source': "``In short,'' said Sydney, ``this is a desperate time, when desperate games are played for desperate stakes.", 'answer': 'a desperate time'}
{'question': 'Do the speaker who struck in, remember faces well?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am Solomon busy?', 'source': 'I am busy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the spy pale?', 'source': 'The spy, who was pale, turned paler, and asked him how he dared--', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who explored the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is your hand?', 'source': 'Look over your hand, Mr. Barsad, and see what you have.', 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': 'Was consternation the old gentleman?', 'source': 'Struck with consternation, the old gentleman exclaimed, ``What do you tell me!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knew you were here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'Solomon'}
{'question': 'Do Solomon ask the favor?', 'source': 'Might I ask the favor?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is?', 'source': 'There it is.', 'answer': 'dejected head'}
{'question': 'Who knows of most people who are here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he draw near?', 'source': 'He drew the bottle near, poured out another glassful of brandy, and drank it off.', 'answer': 'the bottle'}
{'question': "Did a light break clearly on the speaker who struck in,'s mind?", 'source': 'cried Carton, striking his open hand on the table, as a light broke clearly on his mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where do I propose that we first conduct your sister safely?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'to the corner of her own street'}
{'question': "Though it's not important in the same mechanical way though what does-- it's not important-- No,'s not important?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "What 'd I catch hold of?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': 'of your throat'}
{'question': 'What moved?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': 'her fingers'}
{'question': 'Did a man rise to depart?', 'source': 'As their wine was measuring out, a man parted from another man in a corner, and rose to depart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is your arm?', 'source': 'Let me take your arm, Miss Pross.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "Who 'll yes I go with?", 'source': "Yes, I 'll go with you.''", 'answer': 'with you'}
{'question': "Who do I _ know 're John?", 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the speaker who struck in, echo his word?', 'source': 'repeated Carton, musing, and not appearing to notice him at all, though he echoed his word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did I leave him safe and free!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': 'within these two hours'}
{'question': 'Was the old gentleman Barsad?', 'source': 'repeated the old gentleman, ``Barsad?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Solomon expect me to be surprised?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the speaker who struck in, stand at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself?", 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the speaker who struck in, know the face?', 'source': "Yet I know the face.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did the spy say do not know him?', 'source': "You do not know him,'' said the spy, quickly.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he have behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat?', 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': 'his hands'}
{'question': 'What did I arrive at?', 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': "at Mr. Lorry 's"}
{'question': 'Who does your escort know?', 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': "What 'll you have enough with giving your attention to that gentleman?", 'source': "``Never you trouble your head about this man,'' retorted the contentious Mr. Cruncher; ``you 'll have trouble enough with giving your attention to that gentleman.", 'answer': 'trouble'}
{'question': 'Who did the spy say you do not know?', 'source': "You do not know him,'' said the spy, quickly.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who did Better for him that his beard had never grown shave close?', 'source': 'Better for him that his beard had never grown, for the National Razor shaved him close.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who were her tears?', 'source': "Miss Pross, shaking her loving and dejected head at her by no means affectionate brother, said through her tears, ``Mr. Cruncher.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Was consternation at a loss?', 'source': 'While he was at a loss, Carton said, resuming his former air of contemplating cards:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Barsad see losing cards in it that Sydney Carton knew nothing of?', 'source': 'Mr. Barsad saw losing cards in it that Sydney Carton knew nothing of.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What made the most of it?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': 'his practiced eye'}
{'question': "What 'll Mr. Lorry see?", 'source': "I 'll see what I hold, -- Mr. Lorry, you know what a brute I am; I wish you 'd give me a little brandy.''", 'answer': 'what I hold'}
{'question': 'Who was the two as well between?', 'source': '``So far, we have spoken before these two, because it was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me.', 'answer': 'that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': "Who said ``Now, there you are hasty'' ``there you really give me an advantage over you''?", 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': 'Barsad'}
{'question': 'What did they have for anything in their surprise?', 'source': 'But, they had no ears for anything in their surprise.', 'answer': 'no ears'}
{'question': "What did the spy say, ``You need''?", 'source': "``You need have good cards, sir,'' said the spy.", 'answer': 'have good cards'}
{'question': 'Who is my hand?', 'source': "Have you followed my hand, Mr. Barsad?''", 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': 'What did they have no ears for?', 'source': 'But, they had no ears for anything in their surprise.', 'answer': 'for anything in their surprise'}
{'question': 'What does Mr. Cruncher know?', 'source': "Me and two more knows it.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was that somebody assassinated by somebody vindicating a difference of opinion was the likeliest occurrence?', 'source': 'That somebody was assassinated by somebody vindicating a difference of opinion was the likeliest occurrence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they leave her at?', 'source': "They left her at the corner of the street, and Carton led the way to Mr. Lorry's, which was within a few minutes ' walk.", 'answer': 'at the corner of the street'}
{'question': 'Did the spy irresolutely ask?', 'source': 'the spy irresolutely asked.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is your name?', 'source': "As to whether your name is John Solomon, or Solomon John?''", 'answer': 'John Solomon, or Solomon John'}
{'question': 'Who sat near you?', 'source': 'I walked into the wine-shop here, close after you, and sat near you.', 'answer': 'the speaker who struck in,'}
{'question': 'Who is your hand carefully?', 'source': '``Look over your hand carefully, Mr. Barsad.', 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': 'Where did I walk?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': 'in your direction'}
{'question': 'What did his unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevent my following?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'his remains'}
{'question': "Though it's not important in the same mechanical way though what--'s not important-- No, it's not important?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did his unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevent following his remains?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'my'}
{'question': 'Who proposes that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did Solomon know were here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "What 'll I swear it was?", 'source': "But I 'll swear it was a name of two syllables.''", 'answer': 'a name of two syllables'}
{'question': 'Did another voice strike in?', 'source': "``Barsad,'' said another voice, striking in.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``though it's not important''?", 'source': "``Is, I assure you,'' said the spy; ``though it's not important.''", 'answer': 'the spy'}
{'question': 'Was Carton coolly?', 'source': "``I told you you had a remarkable face, Mr. Barsad,'' observed Carton, coolly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who helped to lay him in his coffin?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who told me you had a proposal; what is this?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Barsad see losing cards in this that Sydney Carton knew nothing of?', 'source': 'Mr. Barsad saw losing cards in it that Sydney Carton knew nothing of.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they show with which he saw a stranger?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': 'the surprise'}
{'question': 'What was that your respect for my sister?', 'source': "``I should have hoped, gentlemen both,'' said the spy, always striving to hook Mr. Lorry into the discussion, ``that your respect for my sister--''", 'answer': 'the discussion'}
{'question': "What 'd I choke you for?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': 'for half a guinea'}
{'question': 'What did he explore through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'the depths of her reticule'}
{'question': 'Did the speaker who struck in, have to do with?', 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who drank it off?', 'source': 'He drew the bottle near, poured out another glassful of brandy, and drank it off.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Am just Solomon getting on!', 'source': "Just as I am getting on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did you bury paving-stones and earth in?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': 'in that there coffin'}
{'question': 'Am the speaker who struck in, sure not?', 'source': 'I am sure not.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he explore the depths of her reticule through her tears with?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'with great difficulty paid for her wine'}
{'question': 'What do I play?', 'source': '``I play my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee.', 'answer': 'my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee'}
{'question': "What did he stand at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey?", 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': 'Who walked in your direction?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who goes on duty soon?', 'source': 'I go on duty soon, and cannot overstay my time.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did he see them admitted by?', 'source': 'He left the messengers at the gate, and saw them admitted by the porter.', 'answer': 'by the porter'}
{'question': 'Who did the speaker who struck in, have his hands behind under the skirts of his riding-coat?', 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': 'behind him'}
{'question': 'What was that friend and fellow-Sheep?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': 'consternation'}
{'question': 'Was the time sir?', 'source': "``At another time, sir,'' he returned, evasively, ``the present time is ill-conwenient for explainin '.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When could his hair not have been more violently?', 'source': 'His hair could not have been more violently on end, if it had been that moment dressed by the Cow with the crumpled horn in the house that Jack built.', 'answer': 'on end'}
{'question': 'What do and let us have alone?', 'source': "Come into the dark room here, and let us have one final word alone.''", 'answer': 'one final word'}
{'question': 'What did he turn as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': 'his head'}
{'question': 'What prevented my following his remains?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'his unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment'}
{'question': 'What was it to?', 'source': 'It was a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked, making guns for the Army of the Republic.', 'answer': 'a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked'}
{'question': 'What should I make?', 'source': 'In short, I should make that choice.', 'answer': 'that choice'}
{'question': 'What was well?', 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': 'all'}
{'question': 'Do Solomon say!', 'source': '``I say!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who does this's escort know?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': 'What did he drink?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': 'another glassful'}
{'question': 'Who did I sit near?', 'source': 'I walked into the wine-shop here, close after you, and sat near you.', 'answer': 'near you'}
{'question': 'Are all secret men men soon terrified?', 'source': 'Besides that all secret men are men soon terrified, here were surely cards enough of one black suit, to justify the holder in growing rather livid as he turned them over.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he explore the depths of her reticule through with great difficulty paid for her wine?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'through her tears'}
{'question': 'Who has a face to be remembered?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "What does that's not to be beaten?", 'source': "That's a card not to be beaten.", 'answer': 'a card'}
{'question': 'Where did he trace it?', 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': 'to its source'}
{'question': 'Had Sydney Carton been lost in amazement at this turn of the business with Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton, who, with Mr. Lorry, had been lost in amazement at this turn of the business, here requested Mr. Cruncher to moderate and explain himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the speaker who struck in, think not?', 'source': '``I think not.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who talks of desperation?', 'source': 'You talk of desperation.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Would very circumstance be alarming?', 'source': "``But that very circumstance would be alarming, when we remember how identified he is with his son-in-law.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who think not?', 'source': '``I think not.', 'answer': 'the speaker who struck in,'}
{'question': 'Who was you?', 'source': 'You was a spy-- witness at the Bailey.', 'answer': 'a spy-- witness at the Bailey'}
{'question': 'What broke clearly on his mind?', 'source': 'cried Carton, striking his open hand on the table, as a light broke clearly on his mind.', 'answer': 'a light'}
{'question': 'What did his practiced eye make?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': 'the most of it'}
{'question': 'Did the spy ask?', 'source': 'the spy asked.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I walk into here?', 'source': 'I walked into the wine-shop here, close after you, and sat near you.', 'answer': 'into the wine-shop'}
{'question': 'Who do Solomon expect to be surprised?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who may I denounce if I think proper?', 'source': 'I may denounce you if I think proper, and I can swear my way through stone walls, and so can others.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who passes to worse news?', 'source': 'I pass to worse news.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do an official know you?', 'source': 'I know you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was that friend and fellow-Sheep?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he supply?', 'source': "As he took a chair himself, he supplied the link that Mr. Lorry wanted, by saying to him with a frown, ``Witness at that trial.''", 'answer': 'the link that Mr. Lorry wanted'}
{'question': 'What did he explore the depths of through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'of her reticule'}
{'question': 'Who said you do not know him?', 'source': "You do not know him,'' said the spy, quickly.", 'answer': 'the spy'}
{'question': 'What did his practiced eye see?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who are you?', 'source': "You are a turnkey at the Conciergerie?''", 'answer': 'a turnkey at the Conciergerie'}
{'question': 'Who do I propose that we first conduct safely to the corner of her own street?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'your sister'}
{'question': 'What may not be so?', 'source': 'But it may not be so.', 'answer': 'as'}
{'question': 'Was the spy quickly?', 'source': "You do not know him,'' said the spy, quickly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did everybody only see a man and a woman standing staring at each other; the man with all the outward aspect of a Frenchman and a thorough Republican; the woman, evidently English?', 'source': 'Everybody looked to see somebody fall, but only saw a man and a woman standing staring at each other; the man with all the outward aspect of a Frenchman and a thorough Republican; the woman, evidently English.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'The speaker who struck in, will not?', 'source': "I will not.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you have?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': 'a face to be remembered'}
{'question': 'What did the spy ask the speaker who struck in, --?', 'source': 'The spy, who was pale, turned paler, and asked him how he dared--', 'answer': 'how he dared'}
{'question': "What 'll the speaker who struck in, hear?", 'source': "``I 'll hear what you have got to say.", 'answer': 'what you have got to say'}
{'question': 'What were your admirers the nature of?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': 'of your calling'}
{'question': 'Who knows it?', 'source': "Me and two more knows it.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Who is it!', 'source': "growled Mr. Cruncher, ``it's you I have got a old grudge again, is it, with your shameful impositions upon tradesmen!", 'answer': 'growled Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Who did I help to lay in his coffin?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': "What 'd I catch?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': 'hold of your throat'}
{'question': 'What did he always remember with?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': 'with fear and trembling'}
{'question': 'What was put before him?', 'source': 'It was put before him, and he drank off a glassful-- drank off another glassful-- pushed the bottle thoughtfully away.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who was he?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': 'that friend and fellow-Sheep'}
{'question': 'Had an official not previously uttered a word?', 'source': 'He had not previously uttered a word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What's not important in the same mechanical way?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What was it than he suspected?', 'source': 'It was a poorer hand than he suspected.', 'answer': 'a poorer hand'}
{'question': "What 'll I have took off?", 'source': "I 'll have my head took off, if he was ever in it.''", 'answer': 'my head'}
{'question': 'Who is this gentleman?', 'source': "I admit that _ I _ am a spy, and that it is considered a discreditable station-- though it must be filled by somebody; but this gentleman is no spy, and why should he so demean himself as to make himself one?''", 'answer': 'no spy'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross thread her way along the narrow streets?', 'source': 'Happily unconscious of the new calamity at home, Miss Pross threaded her way along the narrow streets and crossed the river by the bridge of the Pont-Neuf, reckoning in her mind the number of indispensable purchases she had to make.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a very good card a sham?', 'source': "Though how this man knows it was a sham, is a wonder of wonders to me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who traced it to its source?', 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Who 'll run them over?", 'source': "``I 'll run them over.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'When can I not overstay?', 'source': 'I go on duty soon, and cannot overstay my time.', 'answer': 'my time'}
{'question': 'Who was at a loss?', 'source': 'While he was at a loss, Carton said, resuming his former air of contemplating cards:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Who do I _ know you 're?", 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': 'John'}
{'question': 'Who was it put before?', 'source': 'It was put before him, and he drank off a glassful-- drank off another glassful-- pushed the bottle thoughtfully away.', 'answer': 'before him'}
{'question': 'Who echoed his word?', 'source': 'repeated Carton, musing, and not appearing to notice him at all, though he echoed his word.', 'answer': 'the speaker who struck in,'}
{'question': 'Was the spy firmly?', 'source': "``I tell you once for all, there is no such thing as an escape possible,'' said the spy, firmly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had since seen her?', 'source': 'He had since seen her, in the Section of Saint Antoine, over and over again produce her knitted registers, and denounce people whose lives the guillotine then surely swallowed up.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did he have to face Miss Pross in going?', 'source': 'In going, he had to face Miss Pross.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did good cards have that man before Disguised at the Old Bailey?', 'source': "We had that man before us at the Old Bailey.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'to the corner of her own street'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross reckon in her mind the number of indispensable purchases?', 'source': 'Happily unconscious of the new calamity at home, Miss Pross threaded her way along the narrow streets and crossed the river by the bridge of the Pont-Neuf, reckoning in her mind the number of indispensable purchases she had to make.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he at?', 'source': 'While he was at a loss, Carton said, resuming his former air of contemplating cards:', 'answer': 'at a loss'}
{'question': "Who said, ``Now, the speaker who struck in, told you so'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing''?", 'source': "``Now, I told you so,'' said the spy, casting a reproachful look at his sister; ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing.''", 'answer': 'the spy'}
{'question': "Did the speaker who struck in, have no difficulty in deducing from the wine-shop's unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers?", 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who may take it in your hand?', 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What do I wish for your sake?', 'source': "I wish for your sake Mr. Barsad was not a Sheep of the Prisons.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Barsad was not a Sheep of the Prisons'}
{'question': "'d Mr. Cruncher catch hold of that's throat?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``Now, I told you so'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing''?", 'source': "``Now, I told you so,'' said the spy, casting a reproachful look at his sister; ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing.''", 'answer': 'the spy'}
{'question': 'Was this a poorer hand than Mr. Lorry suspected?', 'source': 'It was a poorer hand than he suspected.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he supply the link that Mr. Lorry wanted?', 'source': "As he took a chair himself, he supplied the link that Mr. Lorry wanted, by saying to him with a frown, ``Witness at that trial.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Solomon never see you again?', 'source': '``Far rather would I never see you again, dear Solomon, though I have ever loved you truly, and ever shall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who will I invite to Mr. Lorry's with us?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': "Who will I invite him to Mr. Lorry's with?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'with us'}
{'question': 'Who means that he war not never in it?', 'source': "``I mean,'' said Mr. Cruncher, ``that he war not never in it.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I pass to?', 'source': 'I pass to worse news.', 'answer': 'to worse news'}
{'question': 'Is the stake I have resolved to play for a friend in the Conciergerie?', 'source': 'Now, the stake I have resolved to play for, in case of the worst, is a friend in the Conciergerie.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll Mr. Cruncher have trouble enough with giving the greatest wonder's attention to that gentleman?", 'source': "``Never you trouble your head about this man,'' retorted the contentious Mr. Cruncher; ``you 'll have trouble enough with giving your attention to that gentleman.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is that!', 'source': "growled Mr. Cruncher, ``it's you I have got a old grudge again, is it, with your shameful impositions upon tradesmen!", 'answer': 'growled Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'Who is about to return to him!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who shall I be rendered?', 'source': 'I shall be rendered Suspected, by my own sister.', 'answer': 'Suspected'}
{'question': 'What do you talk of?', 'source': 'You talk of desperation.', 'answer': 'of desperation'}
{'question': 'Who is your sister?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did he drink off?', 'source': 'He drew the bottle near, poured out another glassful of brandy, and drank it off.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did I help to lay him in?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': 'in his coffin'}
{'question': 'Who expects me to be surprised?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the Sheep of the prisons turn from him to Sydney Carton?', 'source': 'The Sheep of the prisons turned from him to Sydney Carton, and said, with more decision, ``It has come to a point.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What does it's?", 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': 'no forgery'}
{'question': 'Who am I about to return to!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Who asks the favor?', 'source': 'Might I ask the favor?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he say?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': 'not a word, however, and Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'What do you want to be?', 'source': 'You want to be the death of me.', 'answer': 'the death of me'}
{'question': "What does it's not important in?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': 'in the same mechanical way'}
{'question': 'Did the aspect of things rather take her fancy at the National Palace, once the Tuileries?', 'source': 'After peeping into several wine-shops, she stopped at the sign of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, not far from the National Palace, once (and twice) the Tuileries, where the aspect of things rather took her fancy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is an official?', 'source': "I am an official.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I go soon on?', 'source': 'I go on duty soon, and cannot overstay my time.', 'answer': 'on duty soon'}
{'question': 'Did John Barsad, or Solomon Pross, walk at his side?', 'source': 'John Barsad, or Solomon Pross, walked at his side.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the spy ask him--?', 'source': 'The spy, who was pale, turned paler, and asked him how he dared--', 'answer': 'how he dared'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross say through her tears?', 'source': "Miss Pross, shaking her loving and dejected head at her by no means affectionate brother, said through her tears, ``Mr. Cruncher.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knows the face?', 'source': "Yet I know the face.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Cruncher walk at her side?', 'source': 'Mr. Cruncher, with the basket, walked at her side.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both look in unspeakable astonishment at Jerry?', 'source': 'The spy looked round at the two gentlemen; they both looked in unspeakable astonishment at Jerry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will I invite him to with us?', 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': "to Mr. Lorry 's"}
{'question': 'What do I know?', 'source': "Yet I know the face.''", 'answer': 'the face'}
{'question': 'Who cannot call to mind what your name was?', 'source': "``Well, I do not know all I mean, for I cannot call to mind what your name was, over the water.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What were your admirers?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': 'the nature of your calling'}
{'question': 'Who had he since seen?', 'source': 'He had since seen her, in the Section of Saint Antoine, over and over again produce her knitted registers, and denounce people whose lives the guillotine then surely swallowed up.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Who am I?', 'source': "I am an official.''", 'answer': 'an official'}
{'question': 'What do I ask?', 'source': 'Might I ask the favor?', 'answer': 'the favor'}
{'question': 'When was his surprise?', 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': 'yesterday'}
{'question': 'What did I walk in?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': 'in your direction'}
{'question': 'Who did I know were here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with?', 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': 'the speaker who struck in,'}
{'question': "What 'll I hear?", 'source': "``I 'll hear what you have got to say.", 'answer': 'what you have got to say'}
{'question': "Who 'll I run over?", 'source': "``I 'll run them over.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who did I attend in his last illness?', 'source': 'I attended him in his last illness.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who attended him in his last illness?', 'source': 'I attended him in his last illness.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did Barsad lean back in his chair?', 'source': "Barsad leaned back in his chair, and stammered, ``What do you mean?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who seeded it?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he see that the spy was?', 'source': 'He saw that the spy was fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him.', 'answer': 'fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him'}
{'question': 'What saw it?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': 'his practiced eye'}
{'question': 'What did he trace to its source?', 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "What 'll I run over?", 'source': "``I 'll run them over.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Do I wish for your sake Mr. Barsad was not a Sheep of the Prisons?', 'source': "I wish for your sake Mr. Barsad was not a Sheep of the Prisons.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Pray leave struck with consternation, the old gentleman within these two hours!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the discussion that Mr. Lorry's respect for consternation's sister?", 'source': "``I should have hoped, gentlemen both,'' said the spy, always striving to hook Mr. Lorry into the discussion, ``that your respect for my sister--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is dejected head?', 'source': 'There it is.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she stop at the sign of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity?', 'source': 'After peeping into several wine-shops, she stopped at the sign of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, not far from the National Palace, once (and twice) the Tuileries, where the aspect of things rather took her fancy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What may you take in your hand?', 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the friend and fellow-Sheep speak of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was you a spy-- witness at the Bailey?', 'source': 'You was a spy-- witness at the Bailey.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is this not?', 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': 'a good city'}
{'question': 'Did a woman standing staring at each other; the man with all the outward aspect of a Frenchman and a thorough Republican; the woman, evidently English always remember with fear and trembling?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Who did Barsad say ``Now, there you are hasty'' ``there really give me an advantage over you''?", 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who do Solomon never see again?', 'source': '``Far rather would I never see you again, dear Solomon, though I have ever loved you truly, and ever shall.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he echo?', 'source': 'repeated Carton, musing, and not appearing to notice him at all, though he echoed his word.', 'answer': 'his word'}
{'question': 'Who do you expect to be surprised?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What did he seed?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What do I mean that he war not never in?', 'source': "``I mean,'' said Mr. Cruncher, ``that he war not never in it.", 'answer': 'in it'}
{'question': 'What did he trace it to?', 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': 'to its source'}
{'question': 'Who do the speaker who struck in, wish than?', 'source': 'I wish you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad.', 'answer': 'you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross shake her loving and dejected head at her by no means affectionate brother?', 'source': "Miss Pross, shaking her loving and dejected head at her by no means affectionate brother, said through her tears, ``Mr. Cruncher.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do an official know?', 'source': 'I know you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What was a take in?', 'source': 'It was a take in.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What had he not previously uttered?', 'source': 'He had not previously uttered a word.', 'answer': 'a word'}
{'question': 'Was Barsad with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side?', 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your name John Solomon, or Solomon John?', 'source': "As to whether your name is John Solomon, or Solomon John?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is growled Mr. Cruncher it!', 'source': "growled Mr. Cruncher, ``it's you I have got a old grudge again, is it, with your shameful impositions upon tradesmen!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me?', 'source': '``So far, we have spoken before these two, because it was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Did he discover it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head?", 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I know?', 'source': 'I know you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Did Carton say ``I play my Ace, Mr. Barsad''?", 'source': "``I play my Ace, Mr. Barsad,'' said Carton, taking the answer on himself, and looking at his watch, ``without any scruple, in a very few minutes.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What may you take it in?', 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': 'in your hand'}
{'question': 'Who knew it?', 'source': '``I knew it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What is it of?', 'source': 'Now, it is of no use asking too much of me.', 'answer': 'of no use asking too much of me'}
{'question': 'Did confused, but sensible that something might depend on his presence of mind he command himself?', 'source': 'Confused, but sensible that something might depend on his presence of mind, he commanded himself, and was silently attentive.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'That you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin do Mr. Cruncher tell you?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross bethink herself of the wine they wanted?', 'source': 'Having purchased a few small articles of grocery, and a measure of oil for the lamp, Miss Pross bethought herself of the wine they wanted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross clap her hands?', 'source': 'No sooner did he face her, than Miss Pross uttered a scream, and clapped her hands.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you a turnkey at the Conciergerie?', 'source': "You are a turnkey at the Conciergerie?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should Mr. Cruncher make that choice?', 'source': 'In short, I should make that choice.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the official turn towards him with sudden distrust?', 'source': 'The official turned towards him with sudden distrust.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross only shake her head?', 'source': 'Miss Pross only shook her head and wept in silence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Might the speaker who struck in, not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for good Miss Pross!'s mutual satisfaction for my great respect for Sydney's sister?", 'source': 'But for my great respect for your sister, I might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I play my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee?', 'source': '``I play my Ace, Denunciation of Mr. Barsad to the nearest Section Committee.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I _ know?', 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': "you 're John"}
{'question': 'Had the estrangement between them come of any culpability of hers?', 'source': 'As if the estrangement between them had come of any culpability of hers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are we here?', 'source': 'We are all desperate here.', 'answer': 'all desperate'}
{'question': "Did Carton's negligent recklessness of manner come powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill?", 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did you tell me had a proposal; what is it?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who remembers faces well?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did you tell you had a proposal; what is it?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What was I?', 'source': '``I lighted on you, Mr. Barsad, coming out of the prison of the Conciergerie while I was contemplating the walls, an hour or more ago.', 'answer': 'contemplating the walls'}
{'question': 'What do an official _ know?', 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': "you 're John"}
{'question': 'Was he buried in London?', 'source': 'He was buried in London, at the church of Saint Pancras-in-the-Fields.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knows you?', 'source': 'I know you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did the speaker who struck in, have in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with?', 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Cruncher bury paving-stones and earth in that there coffin?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall I be rendered Suspected?', 'source': 'I shall be rendered Suspected, by my own sister.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What 'll I swear?", 'source': "But I 'll swear it was a name of two syllables.''", 'answer': 'it was a name of two syllables'}
{'question': 'Is growled Mr. Cruncher that!', 'source': "growled Mr. Cruncher, ``it's you I have got a old grudge again, is it, with your shameful impositions upon tradesmen!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Though it's not important in the same mechanical way though does-- it's not important-- No, it's not important?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the Good Republican Brutus attended by her cavalier?', 'source': 'Sounding Mr. Cruncher, and finding him of her opinion, Miss Pross resorted to the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, attended by her cavalier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What 'll I see?", 'source': "I 'll see what I hold, -- Mr. Lorry, you know what a brute I am; I wish you 'd give me a little brandy.''", 'answer': 'what I hold'}
{'question': "What did Carton observe, ``I told you''?", 'source': "``I told you you had a remarkable face, Mr. Barsad,'' observed Carton, coolly.", 'answer': 'you had a remarkable face'}
{'question': "Did I arrive at Mr. Lorry's?", 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': "Though how this man knows it was a sham, is a wonder of wonders to me.''", 'answer': 'a sham'}
{'question': 'Is your hand Mr. Barsad?', 'source': 'Look over your hand, Mr. Barsad, and see what you have.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What 'll I have?", 'source': "I 'll have my head took off, if he was ever in it.''", 'answer': 'my head took off'}
{'question': 'What did Solomon know?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'you were here'}
{'question': 'Is your arm Miss Pross?', 'source': 'Let me take your arm, Miss Pross.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will not?', 'source': "I will not.''", 'answer': 'the speaker who struck in,'}
{'question': "Did he return ``At another time''?", 'source': "``At another time, sir,'' he returned, evasively, ``the present time is ill-conwenient for explainin '.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What must be recorded?', 'source': 'For, it must be recorded, that not only was Miss Pross lost in amazement and agitation, but, Mr. Cruncher-- though it seemed on his own separate and individual account-- was in a state of the greatest wonder.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who never sees you again?', 'source': '``Far rather would I never see you again, dear Solomon, though I have ever loved you truly, and ever shall.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Were the whole company on their feet in a moment?', 'source': 'In a moment, the whole company were on their feet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Miss Pross finding him of her opinion?', 'source': 'Sounding Mr. Cruncher, and finding him of her opinion, Miss Pross resorted to the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, attended by her cavalier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton say I see one thing?', 'source': "I see one thing,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Sydney Carton watch it as it dropped?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton filled another glass with brandy, poured it slowly out upon the hearth, and watched it as it dropped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have an association with the name-- and with the face?', 'source': "I have an association with the name-- and with the face.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I attend him in?', 'source': 'I attended him in his last illness.', 'answer': 'in his last illness'}
{'question': 'What will I play?', 'source': 'Let the Doctor play the winning game; I will play the losing one.', 'answer': 'the losing one'}
{'question': 'May I denounce you if I can swear my way through stone walls?', 'source': 'I may denounce you if I think proper, and I can swear my way through stone walls, and so can others.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does your escort know Mr. Barsad?', 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were her tears Mr. Cruncher?', 'source': "Miss Pross, shaking her loving and dejected head at her by no means affectionate brother, said through her tears, ``Mr. Cruncher.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction for my great respect for your sister?', 'source': 'But for my great respect for your sister, I might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Is my hand Mr. Barsad?', 'source': "Have you followed my hand, Mr. Barsad?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he leave the messengers at the gate?', 'source': 'He left the messengers at the gate, and saw them admitted by the porter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does me and two more know?', 'source': "Me and two more knows it.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Am I shaken by Doctor Manette's not having had the power to prevent this arrest I own to you?", 'source': "I own to you, I am shaken, Mr. Lorry, by Doctor Manette's not having had the power to prevent this arrest.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he explore the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did we have that man before us at the Old Bailey?', 'source': "We had that man before us at the Old Bailey.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Will I invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I wish you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad?', 'source': 'I wish you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I know of?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'of most people who are here'}
{'question': 'Who is she?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': 'your sister'}
{'question': 'What did you tell me you had?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'a proposal; what is it'}
{'question': 'Did I think like a foreigner?', 'source': "Yet like a foreigner, I thought?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say not a word, however, and Miss Pross?', 'source': 'He said not a word, however, and Miss Pross, exploring the depths of her reticule through her tears with great difficulty paid for her wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May as not be so?', 'source': 'But it may not be so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I wish than?', 'source': 'I wish you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad.', 'answer': 'you had a better employed brother than Mr. Barsad'}
{'question': "What does that's?", 'source': "That's a very good card.", 'answer': 'a very good card'}
{'question': 'Is your hand carefully Mr. Barsad?', 'source': '``Look over your hand carefully, Mr. Barsad.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do Mr. Cruncher mean in?', 'source': "``I mean,'' said Mr. Cruncher, ``that he war not never in it.", 'answer': 'that he war not never in a chair'}
{'question': 'Did he draw the bottle near?', 'source': 'He drew the bottle near, poured out another glassful of brandy, and drank it off.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Cruncher tell me?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'you had a proposal; what is this'}
{'question': 'Who must know?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "What did Barsad say ``there you really give me an advantage over you''?", 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': 'Now, there you are hasty'}
{'question': "'ll you have trouble enough with giving your attention to that gentleman?", 'source': "``Never you trouble your head about this man,'' retorted the contentious Mr. Cruncher; ``you 'll have trouble enough with giving your attention to that gentleman.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the speaker who struck in, made curious by seeing you in that connection?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he drink another glassful?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who was too much occupied then with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately to heed what she observed?", 'source': "She was too much occupied then with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately to heed what she observed.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did he see that the spy was fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him?', 'source': 'He saw that the spy was fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Am Mr. Lorry shaken by Doctor Manette's not having had the power to prevent this arrest I own to you?", 'source': "I own to you, I am shaken, Mr. Lorry, by Doctor Manette's not having had the power to prevent this arrest.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'In short is this a desperate time?', 'source': "``In short,'' said Sydney, ``this is a desperate time, when desperate games are played for desperate stakes.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I never see again?', 'source': '``Far rather would I never see you again, dear Solomon, though I have ever loved you truly, and ever shall.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Did Carton observe, ``I told you you had a remarkable face''?", 'source': "``I told you you had a remarkable face, Mr. Barsad,'' observed Carton, coolly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the French language cause them all to relapse into their former places and pursuits?', 'source': 'As she did so, Solomon turned to the followers of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, and offered a few words of explanation in the French language, which caused them all to relapse into their former places and pursuits.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was it as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between?', 'source': '``So far, we have spoken before these two, because it was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me.', 'answer': 'between you and me'}
{'question': 'Did he have his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat?', 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I have better trust my life to the chances of a refusal than the chances of consent?', 'source': 'Ask me to do anything in my office, putting my head in great extra danger, and I had better trust my life to the chances of a refusal than the chances of consent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does this's escort know Mr. Barsad?", 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the spy say, ``You need have good cards''?", 'source': "``You need have good cards, sir,'' said the spy.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he always remember with fear and trembling?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is sure not?', 'source': 'I am sure not.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do you have a face to be remembered?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevent my following his remains?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'That you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin do I tell you?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who throws up?', 'source': '``I throw up.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do I know of most people who are here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was confused, but sensible that something might depend on his presence of mind he silently attentive?', 'source': 'Confused, but sensible that something might depend on his presence of mind, he commanded himself, and was silently attentive.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they show the surprise with which he saw a stranger?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was own father to yourself, you called at that time in the name of the Father of Lies?', 'source': "What, in the name of the Father of Lies, own father to yourself, was you called at that time?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I made curious by having a reason?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is busy?', 'source': 'I am busy.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was all well?', 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the spy say, ``I tell you once for all, there is no such thing as an escape possible''?", 'source': "``I tell you once for all, there is no such thing as an escape possible,'' said the spy, firmly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked?', 'source': 'It was a raw evening, and the misty river, blurred to the eye with blazing lights and to the ear with harsh noises, showed where the barges were stationed in which the smiths worked, making guns for the Army of the Republic.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I swear it was a name of two syllables?", 'source': "But I 'll swear it was a name of two syllables.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the spy ask him how he dared--?', 'source': 'The spy, who was pale, turned paler, and asked him how he dared--', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that friend and fellow-Sheep consternation?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did you bury paving-stones and earth in that there coffin?', 'source': "``I tell you,'' said Jerry, ``that you buried paving-stones and earth in that there coffin.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Sydney say, ``You scarcely seem to like your hand''?", 'source': "``You scarcely seem to like your hand,'' said Sydney, with the greatest composure.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he stand at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself?", 'source': "He had his hands behind him under the skirts of his riding-coat, and he stood at Mr. Cruncher's elbow as negligently as he might have stood at the Old Bailey itself.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'d I choke you for half a guinea?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I walk into the wine-shop here?', 'source': 'I walked into the wine-shop here, close after you, and sat near you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who stands to, ?', 'source': 'What I stand to, is, that he knows well wot that there Cly was never in that there coffin.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did Better for him that his beard had never grown shave him close?', 'source': 'Better for him that his beard had never grown, for the National Razor shaved him close.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who just is getting on!', 'source': "Just as I am getting on!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was that friend and fellow-Sheep he?', 'source': "That friend and fellow-Sheep, who spoke of himself as pasturing in the country prisons; who was he?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should I make that choice?', 'source': 'In short, I should make that choice.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they leave her at the corner of the street?', 'source': "They left her at the corner of the street, and Carton led the way to Mr. Lorry's, which was within a few minutes ' walk.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was she too much occupied then with to heed what she observed?', 'source': "She was too much occupied then with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately to heed what she observed.", 'answer': "with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately"}
{'question': 'Did it have a quieter look than any other place of the same description they had passed, and was not so red as the rest?', 'source': 'It had a quieter look than any other place of the same description they had passed, and, though red with patriotic caps, was not so red as the rest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's a card not to be beaten?", 'source': "That's a card not to be beaten.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do and let us have one final word alone?', 'source': "Come into the dark room here, and let us have one final word alone.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I contemplating the walls?', 'source': '``I lighted on you, Mr. Barsad, coming out of the prison of the Conciergerie while I was contemplating the walls, an hour or more ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I play the losing one?', 'source': 'Let the Doctor play the winning game; I will play the losing one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his practiced eye make the most of it?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who says!', 'source': '``I say!', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "What did Barsad say ``Now, there you are hasty'' ?", 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': 'there you really give me an advantage over you'}
{'question': 'Do I go on duty soon?', 'source': 'I go on duty soon, and cannot overstay my time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's not important in the same mechanical way?", 'source': "``Though it's not important,'' repeated Carton, in the same mechanical way-- ``though it's not important-- No, it's not important.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could his hair not have been more violently on end?', 'source': 'His hair could not have been more violently on end, if it had been that moment dressed by the Cow with the crumpled horn in the house that Jack built.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a light break clearly on his mind?', 'source': 'cried Carton, striking his open hand on the table, as a light broke clearly on his mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross cast up her tear-fraught eyes, ``that had the makings in him of one of the best and greatest of men in his native country, an official among foreigners, and such foreigners''?", 'source': "``My English brother Solomon,'' mourned Miss Pross, casting up her tear-fraught eyes, ``that had the makings in him of one of the best and greatest of men in his native country, an official among foreigners, and such foreigners!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Cruncher tell me you had a proposal; what is this?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a poorer hand than he suspected?', 'source': 'It was a poorer hand than he suspected.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's no forgery?", 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What entered?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "'ll I hear what you have got to say?", 'source': "``I 'll hear what you have got to say.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they have no ears for anything in their surprise?', 'source': 'But, they had no ears for anything in their surprise.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I know?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': 'you were here'}
{'question': "Did the spy say, ``though it's not important''?", 'source': "``Is, I assure you,'' said the spy; ``though it's not important.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I leave him safe and free within these two hours!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'d I catch hold of your throat?", 'source': "I 'd catch hold of your throat and choke you for half a guinea.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll yes I go with you?", 'source': "Yes, I 'll go with you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he see?', 'source': 'He saw that the spy was fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him.', 'answer': 'that the spy was fearful of his drinking himself into a fit state for the immediate denunciation of him'}
{'question': 'Who thinks not?', 'source': '``I think not.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do I pass to worse news?', 'source': 'I pass to worse news.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he see them admitted by the porter?', 'source': 'He left the messengers at the gate, and saw them admitted by the porter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can I not call to mind?', 'source': "``Well, I do not know all I mean, for I cannot call to mind what your name was, over the water.''", 'answer': 'what your name was'}
{'question': 'Where do I propose?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street'}
{'question': 'What dropped?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton filled another glass with brandy, poured it slowly out upon the hearth, and watched it as it dropped.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'May I denounce you if I think proper?', 'source': 'I may denounce you if I think proper, and I can swear my way through stone walls, and so can others.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you talk of desperation?', 'source': 'You talk of desperation.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might I not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction for?', 'source': 'But for my great respect for your sister, I might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction.', 'answer': 'for my great respect for your sister'}
{'question': 'Is this gentleman no spy?', 'source': "I admit that _ I _ am a spy, and that it is considered a discreditable station-- though it must be filled by somebody; but this gentleman is no spy, and why should he so demean himself as to make himself one?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I an official?', 'source': "I am an official.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I help to lay him in his coffin?', 'source': "His unpopularity with the blackguard multitude at the moment prevented my following his remains, but I helped to lay him in his coffin.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Barsad say ``Now, there you are hasty'' ``there you really give me an advantage over you''?", 'source': "``Now, there you are hasty, sir,'' said Barsad, with a smile that gave his aquiline nose an extra inclination to one side; ``there you really give me an advantage over you.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she call you Solomon?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you want to be the death of me?', 'source': 'You want to be the death of me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he at a loss?', 'source': 'While he was at a loss, Carton said, resuming his former air of contemplating cards:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's an excellent card?", 'source': "That's an excellent card.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did you tell me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it of no use asking too much of me?', 'source': 'Now, it is of no use asking too much of me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did so?', 'source': 'As she did so, Solomon turned to the followers of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, and offered a few words of explanation in the French language, which caused them all to relapse into their former places and pursuits.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was I made curious by seeing you in that connection?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a sham?', 'source': "Though how this man knows it was a sham, is a wonder of wonders to me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had I done at random?', 'source': "And gradually, what I had done at random, seemed to shape itself into a purpose, Mr. Barsad.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his practiced eye see it?', 'source': 'His practiced eye saw it, and made the most of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I have my head took off?", 'source': "I 'll have my head took off, if he was ever in it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with?', 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pour out?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must it be recorded?', 'source': 'For, it must be recorded, that not only was Miss Pross lost in amazement and agitation, but, Mr. Cruncher-- though it seemed on his own separate and individual account-- was in a state of the greatest wonder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I sit near you?', 'source': 'I walked into the wine-shop here, close after you, and sat near you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were your admirers the nature of your calling?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I _?', 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': "know you 're John"}
{'question': 'Did the spy say you do not know him?', 'source': "You do not know him,'' said the spy, quickly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do an official _?', 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': "know you 're John"}
{'question': 'Do I ask the favor?', 'source': 'Might I ask the favor?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do I _ know you 're John?", 'source': "And _ I _ know you 're John, you know.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I see what I hold?", 'source': "I 'll see what I hold, -- Mr. Lorry, you know what a brute I am; I wish you 'd give me a little brandy.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know the face?', 'source': "Yet I know the face.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the discussion that your respect for my sister?', 'source': "``I should have hoped, gentlemen both,'' said the spy, always striving to hook Mr. Lorry into the discussion, ``that your respect for my sister--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was their wine measuring out?', 'source': 'As their wine was measuring out, a man parted from another man in a corner, and rose to depart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I remember faces well?', 'source': 'You have a face to be remembered, and I remember faces well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both look?', 'source': 'They both looked to the right and to the left into most of the shops they passed, had a wary eye for all gregarious assemblages of people, and turned out of their road to avoid any very excited group of talkers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this not a good city?', 'source': "This is not a good city, at this time, for you to be out in, unprotected; and as your escort knows Mr. Barsad, I will invite him to Mr. Lorry's with us.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he trace it to its source?', 'source': "Tracing it to its source, he discovered it to be caused by a sudden extraordinary rising and stiffening of all the risen and stiff hair on Mr. Cruncher's head.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May you take it in your hand?', 'source': "You may take it in your hand; it's no forgery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a take in?', 'source': 'It was a take in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I walk in your direction?', 'source': 'Made curious by seeing you in that connection, and having a reason, to which you are no stranger, for associating you with the misfortunes of a friend now very unfortunate, I walked in your direction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her fingers move?', 'source': 'He always remembered with fear and trembling, that that terrible woman had knitted when he talked with her, and had looked ominously at him as her fingers moved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I attend him in his last illness?', 'source': 'I attended him in his last illness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I mean that he war not never in it?', 'source': "``I mean,'' said Mr. Cruncher, ``that he war not never in it.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's a very good card?", 'source': "That's a very good card.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he drink it off?', 'source': 'He drew the bottle near, poured out another glassful of brandy, and drank it off.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I have no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it put before him?', 'source': 'It was put before him, and he drank off a glassful-- drank off another glassful-- pushed the bottle thoughtfully away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we all desperate here?', 'source': 'We are all desperate here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he not previously uttered a word?', 'source': 'He had not previously uttered a word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not overstay my time?', 'source': 'I go on duty soon, and cannot overstay my time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I throw up?', 'source': '``I throw up.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his surprise yesterday?', 'source': "I arrived at Mr. Lorry's, to his surprise, yesterday evening; we agreed that I would not present myself elsewhere until all was well, or unless I could be useful; I present myself here, to beg a little talk with your brother.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does this man know?', 'source': "Though how this man knows it was a sham, is a wonder of wonders to me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I busy?', 'source': 'I am busy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must she know?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I sure not?', 'source': 'I am sure not.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I propose to?', 'source': '``I propose that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street.', 'answer': 'that we first conduct your sister safely to the corner of her own street'}
{'question': "'ll I run them over?", 'source': "``I 'll run them over.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I know you were here?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he since seen her?', 'source': 'He had since seen her, in the Section of Saint Antoine, over and over again produce her knitted registers, and denounce people whose lives the guillotine then surely swallowed up.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I about to return to him!', 'source': "I left him safe and free within these two hours, and am about to return to him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he echo his word?', 'source': 'repeated Carton, musing, and not appearing to notice him at all, though he echoed his word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take a chair himself?', 'source': "As he took a chair himself, he supplied the link that Mr. Lorry wanted, by saying to him with a frown, ``Witness at that trial.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have to do with?', 'source': "Carton's negligent recklessness of manner came powerfully in aid of his quickness and skill, in such a business as he had in his secret mind, and with such a man as he had to do with.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might I not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction for my great respect for your sister?', 'source': 'But for my great respect for your sister, I might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What shaved him close?', 'source': 'Better for him that his beard had never grown, for the National Razor shaved him close.', 'answer': 'Better for him that his beard had never grown'}
{'question': 'Did he seed it?', 'source': 'Seeing it, he poured out and drank another glassful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I stand to?', 'source': 'What I stand to, is, that he knows well wot that there Cly was never in that there coffin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might I not have led up so pleasantly to for my great respect for your sister?', 'source': 'But for my great respect for your sister, I might not have led up so pleasantly to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction.', 'answer': 'to a little proposal that I wish to make for our mutual satisfaction'}
{'question': 'Did he say?', 'source': 'It being all spent, he said, rising:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am just I getting on!', 'source': "Just as I am getting on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I know it?', 'source': '``I knew it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is she your sister?', 'source': 'She calls you Solomon, and she must know, being your sister.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the spy say, ``Now, the speaker who struck in, told you so'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing''?", 'source': "``Now, I told you so,'' said the spy, casting a reproachful look at his sister; ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me?', 'source': '``So far, we have spoken before these two, because it was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the spy say, ``Now, I told you so'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing'', ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing''?", 'source': "``Now, I told you so,'' said the spy, casting a reproachful look at his sister; ``if any trouble comes of this, it's your doing.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not call to mind what your name was?', 'source': "``Well, I do not know all I mean, for I cannot call to mind what your name was, over the water.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he rise?', 'source': 'It being all spent, he said, rising:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you expect me to be surprised?', 'source': "``If you expect me to be surprised,'' said her brother Solomon, ``I am not surprised; I knew you were here; I know of most people who are here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think not?', 'source': '``I think not.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she do so?', 'source': 'As she did so, Solomon turned to the followers of the Good Republican Brutus of Antiquity, and offered a few words of explanation in the French language, which caused them all to relapse into their former places and pursuits.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I have?', 'source': 'I had no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers, the nature of your calling.', 'answer': 'no difficulty in deducing from your unreserved conversation, and the rumor openly going about among your admirers'}
{'question': 'Did he suspect?', 'source': 'It was a poorer hand than he suspected.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know you?', 'source': 'I know you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they enter?', 'source': 'He turned his head as they entered, and showed the surprise with which he saw a stranger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I say!', 'source': '``I say!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it drop?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton filled another glass with brandy, poured it slowly out upon the hearth, and watched it as it dropped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May it not be so?', 'source': 'But it may not be so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does me and two more know it?', 'source': "Me and two more knows it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was she too much occupied then with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately to heed what she observed?", 'source': "She was too much occupied then with fears for the brother who so little deserved her affection, and with Sydney's friendly reassurances, adequately to heed what she observed.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'I will not?', 'source': "I will not.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I never see you again?', 'source': '``Far rather would I never see you again, dear Solomon, though I have ever loved you truly, and ever shall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it?', 'source': 'There it is.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I mean in?', 'source': "``I mean,'' said Mr. Cruncher, ``that he war not never in it.", 'answer': 'that he war not never in it'}
{'question': 'What did you tell me?', 'source': 'You told me you had a proposal; what is it?', 'answer': 'you had a proposal; what is it'}
{'question': 'Who was it as well between?', 'source': '``So far, we have spoken before these two, because it was as well that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me.', 'answer': 'that the merits of the cards should not rest solely between you and me'}
{'question': 'What do I ai not a going to be blest out of?', 'source': '``I ai not a going to be blest out of house and home.', 'answer': 'of house and home'}
{'question': 'What kept him in a dark place?', 'source': 'They kept him in a dark place, like a cheese, until he had the full Tellson flavor and blue-mould upon him.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who hid him somewhere till he was old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did your deeds get into?', 'source': 'Your deeds got into extemporised strong-rooms made of kitchens and sculleries, and fretted all the fat out of their parchments into the banking-house air.', 'answer': 'into extemporised strong-rooms made of kitchens and sculleries'}
{'question': 'What was proud of its darkness proud of?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': 'of its incommodiousness'}
{'question': 'What did your bank-notes have?', 'source': 'Your bank-notes had a musty odour, as if they were fast decomposing into rags again.', 'answer': 'a musty odour'}
{'question': 'What hid him somewhere till he was old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who was his express image?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': "a young man's son: the grisly urchin of twelve"}
{'question': 'What were they even boastful of?', 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': 'of its eminence in those particulars'}
{'question': 'What did and present as as he could overlay his natural self with?', 'source': "Towards nine o'clock he smoothed his ruffled aspect, and, presenting as respectable and business-like an exterior as he could overlay his natural self with, issued forth to the occupation of the day.", 'answer': 'as respectable and business-like an exterior'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Cruncher throw off other sarcastic sparks from the whirling grindstone of his indignation?', 'source': 'and throwing off other sarcastic sparks from the whirling grindstone of his indignation, Mr. Cruncher betook himself to his boot-cleaning and his general preparation for business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is my son?', 'source': "You 've got a dutiful mother, you have, my son.", 'answer': 'the dutiful mother'}
{'question': 'Was the word given?', 'source': "The head of one of the regular indoor messengers attached to Tellson's establishment was put through the door, and the word was given:", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he resent Mrs. Cruncher's saying grace with particular animosity?", 'source': "He resented Mrs. Cruncher's saying grace with particular animosity.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was praying for you?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do they hide somewhere till he was old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'When was he never absent?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': 'during business hours'}
{'question': "Who's did?", 'source': "In the meantime, his son, whose head was garnished with tenderer spikes, and whose young eyes stood close by one another, as his father's did, kept the required watch upon his mother.", 'answer': 'his father'}
{'question': "What did his wife explain that she had merely ``asked?''", 'source': "His wife explained that she had merely ``asked a blessing.''", 'answer': 'a blessing'}
{'question': 'Was a boot a very muddy boot?', 'source': "It was a very muddy boot, and may introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy, that, whereas he often came home after banking hours with clean boots, he often got up next morning to find the same boots covered with clay.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are what worth no more than that?', 'source': "They are worth no more than that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Cruncher betook himself to?', 'source': 'and throwing off other sarcastic sparks from the whirling grindstone of his indignation, Mr. Cruncher betook himself to his boot-cleaning and his general preparation for business.', 'answer': 'to his boot-cleaning and his general preparation for business'}
{'question': "Who 'res a nice woman!", 'source': "You 're a nice woman!", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What were its smallness proud of?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': 'of its darkness'}
{'question': 'What are they worth?', 'source': "They are worth no more than that.''", 'answer': 'no more than that'}
{'question': 'What was his mother strongly deprecated?', 'source': 'Master Cruncher (who was in his shirt) took this very ill, and, turning to his mother, strongly deprecated any praying away of his personal board.', 'answer': 'any praying away of his personal board'}
{'question': 'Who was not praying against you?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was I praying for?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': 'for you'}
{'question': 'Who was he represented by?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': 'by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve'}
{'question': 'Who is my boy?', 'source': "You 've got a religious mother, you have, my boy: going and flopping herself down, and praying that the bread-and-butter may be snatched out of the mouth of her only child.''", 'answer': 'the religious mother'}
{'question': 'What was proud of its darkness?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': 'proud of its incommodiousness'}
{'question': 'What could it scarcely be called?', 'source': "It could scarcely be called a trade, in spite of his favorite description of himself as ``a honest tradesman.''", 'answer': 'a trade'}
{'question': "Who do you 're!", 'source': "You 're a nice woman!", 'answer': 'a nice woman'}
{'question': 'Who are worth no more than that?', 'source': "They are worth no more than that.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Is flop mother?', 'source': 'He greatly disturbed that poor woman at intervals, by darting out of his sleeping closet, where he made his toilet, with a suppressed cry of ``You are going to flop, mother.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they keep him in?', 'source': 'They kept him in a dark place, like a cheese, until he had the full Tellson flavor and blue-mould upon him.', 'answer': 'in a dark place'}
{'question': 'Who was I not praying against?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': 'against you'}
{'question': "May it introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy?", 'source': "It was a very muddy boot, and may introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy, that, whereas he often came home after banking hours with clean boots, he often got up next morning to find the same boots covered with clay.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he rise above?', 'source': 'At first, he slept heavily, but, by degrees, began to roll and surge in bed, until he rose above the surface, with his spiky hair looking as if it must tear the sheets to ribbons.', 'answer': 'above the surface'}
{'question': 'Who rose above the surface?', 'source': 'At first, he slept heavily, but, by degrees, began to roll and surge in bed, until he rose above the surface, with his spiky hair looking as if it must tear the sheets to ribbons.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What were they even?', 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': 'boastful of its eminence in those particulars'}
{'question': "Would any one of these partners have disinherited his son on the question of rebuilding Tellson's?", 'source': "Any one of these partners would have disinherited his son on the question of rebuilding Tellson's.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'As if he had been up all night at a party which had taken anything but a convivial turn what did Jerry Cruncher worry rather than ate it?', 'source': 'Exceedingly red-eyed and grim, as if he had been up all night at a party which had taken anything but a convivial turn, Jerry Cruncher worried his breakfast rather than ate it, growling over it like any four-footed inmate of a menagerie.', 'answer': 'his breakfast'}
{'question': 'If you were who will not be took the liberty with?', 'source': 'And if you were, I will not be took the liberty with.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do I tell?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he have?', 'source': 'They kept him in a dark place, like a cheese, until he had the full Tellson flavor and blue-mould upon him.', 'answer': 'the full Tellson flavor'}
{'question': 'What did he make?', 'source': 'He greatly disturbed that poor woman at intervals, by darting out of his sleeping closet, where he made his toilet, with a suppressed cry of ``You are going to flop, mother.', 'answer': 'his toilet'}
{'question': 'What do he not get here!', 'source': "He do not get no iron rust here!''", 'answer': 'no iron rust'}
{'question': 'Was a young man old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were its smallness?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': 'proud of its darkness'}
{'question': "Did particles of which fly up the House's nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut your money came out of, or went into wooden drawers?", 'source': 'Your money came out of, or went into, wormy old wooden drawers, particles of which flew up your nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he throw a boot at the woman as a third?', 'source': 'After hailing the morn with this second salutation, he threw a boot at the woman as a third.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did they take a young man into Tellson's London house?", 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was this?', 'source': 'This was no passive belief, but an active weapon which they flashed at more convenient places of business.', 'answer': 'no passive belief'}
{'question': 'Who tells you?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Was Mr. Cruncher's temper not at all improved when he came to his breakfast?", 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's temper was not at all improved when he came to his breakfast.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': 'an old-fashioned place'}
{'question': 'Who cannot afford it?', 'source': 'I cannot afford it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did your deeds get into extemporised strong-rooms made of kitchens and sculleries?', 'source': 'Your deeds got into extemporised strong-rooms made of kitchens and sculleries, and fretted all the fat out of their parchments into the banking-house air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was your plate stowed away among the neighbouring cesspools?', 'source': 'Your plate was stowed away among the neighbouring cesspools, and evil communications corrupted its good polish in a day or two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he received the added appellation of Jerry on the youthful occasion of his renouncing by proxy the works of darkness church of Hounsditch?', 'source': 'His surname was Cruncher, and on the youthful occasion of his renouncing by proxy the works of darkness, in the easterly parish church of Hounsditch, he had received the added appellation of Jerry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did God speed enter on his reversionary interest in the straw his father had been chewing, and cogitated?', 'source': 'Having thus given his parent God speed, young Jerry seated himself on the stool, entered on his reversionary interest in the straw his father had been chewing, and cogitated.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his surname Cruncher?', 'source': 'His surname was Cruncher, and on the youthful occasion of his renouncing by proxy the works of darkness, in the easterly parish church of Hounsditch, he had received the added appellation of Jerry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Cruncher betook himself to his boot-cleaning and his general preparation for business?', 'source': 'and throwing off other sarcastic sparks from the whirling grindstone of his indignation, Mr. Cruncher betook himself to his boot-cleaning and his general preparation for business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were Tellson even boastful of Tellson's Bank by Temple Bar's eminence in those particulars?", 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the House much on with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable in this respect?', 'source': 'In this respect the House was much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable.', 'answer': 'on a par'}
{'question': 'Who exclaimed?', 'source': 'At which juncture, he exclaimed, in a voice of dire exasperation:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What was much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable in this respect?', 'source': 'In this respect the House was much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable.', 'answer': 'the House'}
{'question': 'Did your deeds fret all the fat out of their parchments into the banking-house air?', 'source': 'Your deeds got into extemporised strong-rooms made of kitchens and sculleries, and fretted all the fat out of their parchments into the banking-house air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can I not afford?', 'source': 'I cannot afford it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did time and tide have drifted this person to the post?', 'source': 'The house had always tolerated some person in that capacity, and time and tide had drifted this person to the post.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a woman of orderly and industrious appearance rise from her knees in a corner?', 'source': 'A woman of orderly and industrious appearance rose from her knees in a corner, with sufficient haste and trepidation to show that she was the person referred to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you were what will I not be took with?', 'source': 'And if you were, I will not be took the liberty with.', 'answer': 'the liberty'}
{'question': 'Did his son keep the required watch upon his mother in the meantime?', 'source': "In the meantime, his son, whose head was garnished with tenderer spikes, and whose young eyes stood close by one another, as his father's did, kept the required watch upon his mother.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were they fired by?', 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': 'by an express conviction that it would be less respectable'}
{'question': 'What did particles of which fly up your nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut came out of, or went into wooden drawers?', 'source': 'Your money came out of, or went into, wormy old wooden drawers, particles of which flew up your nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut.', 'answer': 'your money'}
{'question': 'Did your bank-notes have a musty odour?', 'source': 'Your bank-notes had a musty odour, as if they were fast decomposing into rags again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Young Jerry give me a call?', 'source': 'Young Jerry, dress yourself, my boy, and while I clean my boots keep a eye upon your mother now and then, and if you see any signs of more flopping, give me a call.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who 'res religious?", 'source': "You 're religious, too.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did evil communications corrupt its good polish in a day or two?', 'source': 'Your plate was stowed away among the neighbouring cesspools, and evil communications corrupted its good polish in a day or two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will not have my wittles blest off my table?', 'source': 'I will not have my wittles blest off my table.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Does your mother's a nice woman going a praying agin your father's prosperity?", 'source': "your mother's a nice woman, young Jerry, going a praying agin your father's prosperity.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do you 've got a dutiful mother?", 'source': "You 've got a dutiful mother, you have, my son.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did and present as respectable and business-like an exterior as he could overlay his natural self with?', 'source': "Towards nine o'clock he smoothed his ruffled aspect, and, presenting as respectable and business-like an exterior as he could overlay his natural self with, issued forth to the occupation of the day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the house always tolerated some person in that capacity?', 'source': 'The house had always tolerated some person in that capacity, and time and tide had drifted this person to the post.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I ai not a going to be blest out of house and home?', 'source': '``I ai not a going to be blest out of house and home.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who slept heavily?', 'source': 'At first, he slept heavily, but, by degrees, began to roll and surge in bed, until he rose above the surface, with his spiky hair looking as if it must tear the sheets to ribbons.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Presenting as respectable and business-like an exterior as he could overlay his natural self with did and issue forth to the occupation of the day?', 'source': "Towards nine o'clock he smoothed his ruffled aspect, and, presenting as respectable and business-like an exterior as he could overlay his natural self with, issued forth to the occupation of the day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were very decently kept?', 'source': 'But they were very decently kept.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who will I not have blest off my table?', 'source': 'I will not have my wittles blest off my table.', 'answer': 'my wittles'}
{'question': 'Was this no passive belief?', 'source': 'This was no passive belief, but an active weapon which they flashed at more convenient places of business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his son: the grisly urchin of twelve his express image?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will I not have my wittles blest off?', 'source': 'I will not have my wittles blest off my table.', 'answer': 'my table'}
{'question': 'Was his mother strongly deprecated any praying away of his personal board?', 'source': 'Master Cruncher (who was in his shirt) took this very ill, and, turning to his mother, strongly deprecated any praying away of his personal board.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who or no will not be prayed agin?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do they hide him somewhere till he was old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they fired by an express conviction that it would be less respectable?', 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have the full Tellson flavor?', 'source': 'They kept him in a dark place, like a cheese, until he had the full Tellson flavor and blue-mould upon him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did (Mr. Cruncher himself always speak of the year of our Lord as Anna Dominoes? )', 'source': '(Mr. Cruncher himself always spoke of the year of our Lord as Anna Dominoes: apparently under the impression that the Christian era dated from the invention of a popular game, by a lady who had bestowed her name upon it. )', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he never absent during business hours?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it an old-fashioned place?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they even boastful of its eminence in those particulars?', 'source': 'They were even boastful of its eminence in those particulars, and were fired by an express conviction that, if it were less objectionable, it would be less respectable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the dutiful mother my son?', 'source': "You 've got a dutiful mother, you have, my son.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve?', 'source': 'He was never absent during business hours, unless upon an errand, and then he was represented by his son: a grisly urchin of twelve, who was his express image.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he not get no iron rust here!', 'source': "He do not get no iron rust here!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could it scarcely be called a trade?', 'source': "It could scarcely be called a trade, in spite of his favorite description of himself as ``a honest tradesman.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are they worth no more than that?', 'source': "They are worth no more than that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do you 're a nice woman!", 'source': "You 're a nice woman!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they keep him in a dark place?', 'source': 'They kept him in a dark place, like a cheese, until he had the full Tellson flavor and blue-mould upon him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did his wife explain that she had merely ``asked a blessing?''", 'source': "His wife explained that she had merely ``asked a blessing.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it come to pass?', 'source': "Thus it had come to pass, that Tellson's was the triumphant perfection of inconvenience.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did his wife explain?''", 'source': "His wife explained that she had merely ``asked a blessing.''", 'answer': 'that she had merely ``asked a blessing'}
{'question': 'Was proud of its darkness proud of its ugliness?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was proud of its darkness proud of its incommodiousness?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will or no I not be?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': 'prayed agin'}
{'question': "Do I 'm not a going to be made unlucky by _ your _ sneaking?", 'source': "I 'm not a going to be made unlucky by _ your _ sneaking.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it very small very ugly, very incommodious?', 'source': 'It was very small, very dark, very ugly, very incommodious.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were not?', 'source': '``You were not.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'As if he had been up all night at a party which had taken anything but a convivial turn did Jerry Cruncher worry his breakfast rather than ate it?', 'source': 'Exceedingly red-eyed and grim, as if he had been up all night at a party which had taken anything but a convivial turn, Jerry Cruncher worried his breakfast rather than ate it, growling over it like any four-footed inmate of a menagerie.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he rise above the surface?', 'source': 'At first, he slept heavily, but, by degrees, began to roll and surge in bed, until he rose above the surface, with his spiky hair looking as if it must tear the sheets to ribbons.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a very muddy boot?', 'source': "It was a very muddy boot, and may introduce the odd circumstance connected with Mr. Cruncher's domestic economy, that, whereas he often came home after banking hours with clean boots, he often got up next morning to find the same boots covered with clay.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is his fingers al-ways rusty!', 'source': "His fingers is al-ways rusty!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the religious mother my boy?', 'source': "You 've got a religious mother, you have, my boy: going and flopping herself down, and praying that the bread-and-butter may be snatched out of the mouth of her only child.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the House much on a par with in this respect?', 'source': 'In this respect the House was much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable.', 'answer': 'with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable'}
{'question': 'Will I not have my wittles blest off my table?', 'source': 'I will not have my wittles blest off my table.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will or no I not be prayed agin?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do you 're religious?", 'source': "You 're religious, too.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he exclaim?', 'source': 'At which juncture, he exclaimed, in a voice of dire exasperation:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I praying for you?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were its smallness proud of its darkness?', 'source': 'It was an old-fashioned place, moreover, in the moral attribute that the partners in the House were proud of its smallness, proud of its darkness, proud of its ugliness, proud of its incommodiousness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make his toilet?', 'source': 'He greatly disturbed that poor woman at intervals, by darting out of his sleeping closet, where he made his toilet, with a suppressed cry of ``You are going to flop, mother.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I not praying against you?', 'source': "``I was not praying against you; I was praying for you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sleep heavily?', 'source': 'At first, he slept heavily, but, by degrees, began to roll and surge in bed, until he rose above the surface, with his spiky hair looking as if it must tear the sheets to ribbons.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I tell you?', 'source': 'Whether or no, I will not be prayed agin, I tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they very decently kept?', 'source': 'But they were very decently kept.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did particles of which fly up your nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut your money came out of, or went into wooden drawers?', 'source': 'Your money came out of, or went into, wormy old wooden drawers, particles of which flew up your nose and down your throat when they were opened and shut.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not afford it?', 'source': 'I cannot afford it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you were will I not be took the liberty with?', 'source': 'And if you were, I will not be took the liberty with.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the House much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable in this respect?', 'source': 'In this respect the House was much on a par with the Country; which did very often disinherit its sons for suggesting improvements in laws and customs that had long been highly objectionable, but were only the more respectable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he old?', 'source': "When they took a young man into Tellson's London house, they hid him somewhere till he was old.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you not?', 'source': '``You were not.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did two gaolers go out?', 'source': 'Two gaolers, who had been standing there, went out, and the prisoner was brought in, and put to the bar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When is the ocean to give up its dead?', 'source': 'Haunted in a most ghastly manner that abominable place would have been, if the glass could ever have rendered back its reflections, as the ocean is one day to give up its dead.', 'answer': 'one day'}
{'question': 'Had two gaolers been standing there?', 'source': 'Two gaolers, who had been standing there, went out, and the prisoner was brought in, and put to the bar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do some of us have?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': 'damp ways'}
{'question': 'Did the ancient clerk turn his surprised spectacles upon him?', 'source': "``It is the law,'' remarked the ancient clerk, turning his surprised spectacles upon him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will an emotion of the mind express itself through any covering of the body?', 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Jerry, and who had been sucking the rust off his fingers in his absorption, stretch his neck to hear?', 'source': 'Jerry, the messenger, who had made his own observations, in his own manner, and who had been sucking the rust off his fingers in his absorption, stretched his neck to hear who they were.', 'answer': 'who they were'}
{'question': 'Was the prisoner brought in?', 'source': 'Two gaolers, who had been standing there, went out, and the prisoner was brought in, and put to the bar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the door-keeper ask?', 'source': 'he asked, as the result of that conference.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is one day to give up its dead?', 'source': 'Haunted in a most ghastly manner that abominable place would have been, if the glass could ever have rendered back its reflections, as the ocean is one day to give up its dead.', 'answer': 'the ocean'}
{'question': 'Did Jerry add?', 'source': 'Jerry added, by way of proviso.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you know?', 'source': "And you know Mr. Lorry.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What is?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': 'then'}
{'question': 'What was his condition?', 'source': 'His condition was that of a young gentleman.', 'answer': 'that of a young gentleman'}
{'question': "Who did the object of all this's cheek show?", 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': 'the soul to be stronger than the'}
{'question': 'What do some of this have?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': 'damp ways'}
{'question': 'Is so powerful use?', 'source': 'So powerful is use, and so desirable to be good use in the beginning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the whisper of the man?', 'source': 'he asked, in a whisper, of the man he found himself next to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Am the door-keeper going to tell you?', 'source': '``I am going to tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': "the object of all this's hair"}
{'question': 'What had her forehead been?', 'source': 'Her forehead had been strikingly expressive of an engrossing terror and compassion that saw nothing but the peril of the accused.', 'answer': 'strikingly expressive of an engrossing terror'}
{'question': 'Did the wicked and the wretched see the glass?', 'source': 'Be that as it may, a change in his position making him conscious of a bar of light across his face, he looked up; and when he saw the glass his face flushed, and his right hand pushed the herbs away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the door-keeper want you?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is the ocean one day to give up the glass's dead?", 'source': 'Haunted in a most ghastly manner that abominable place would have been, if the glass could ever have rendered back its reflections, as the ocean is one day to give up its dead.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had drawn close to him?', 'source': 'She had drawn close to him, in her dread of the scene, and in her pity for the prisoner.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Is the court sir?', 'source': "``Am I to wait in the court, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did he come?', 'source': 'As the ancient clerk deliberately folded and superscribed the note, Mr. Cruncher, after surveying him in silence until he came to the blotting-paper stage, remarked:', 'answer': 'to the blotting-paper stage'}
{'question': "What's wery hard to spile him?", 'source': "It's hard enough to kill him, but it's wery hard to spile him, sir.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the whisper go about?', 'source': "This had been so very noticeable, so very powerfully and naturally shown, that starers who had had no pity for him were touched by her; and the whisper went about, ``Who are they?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is to tell him you are there?', 'source': "This is to tell him you are there.''", 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'Who had one of her hands drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': 'his daughter'}
{'question': "Did the old clerk say, ``we all have this's various ways of gaining a livelihood''?", 'source': "``Well, well,'' said the old clerk; ``we all have our various ways of gaining a livelihood.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Lorry stood up to look for him?', 'source': 'After some gruff coughing and rubbing of his chin and signing with his hand, Jerry attracted the notice of Mr. Lorry, who had stood up to look for him, and who quietly nodded and sat down again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his daughter have drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': 'one of her hands'}
{'question': 'Who gives you that advice?', 'source': "I give you that advice.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who had she drawn close to?', 'source': 'She had drawn close to him, in her dread of the scene, and in her pity for the prisoner.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What was the object of all this plainly dressed in?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'in black, or very dark gray'}
{'question': 'Who did he find himself next to asked?', 'source': 'he asked, in a whisper, of the man he found himself next to.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did he find next to he asked?', 'source': 'he asked, in a whisper, of the man he found himself next to.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What she had in?', 'source': 'She had drawn close to him, in her dread of the scene, and in her pity for the prisoner.', 'answer': 'in her pity for the prisoner'}
{'question': 'Who sat by him?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What was his hair gathered in at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'in a ribbon'}
{'question': 'Who wants you?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': 'the door-keeper'}
{'question': 'Who give you that advice?', 'source': "I give you that advice.''", 'answer': 'the ancient clerk deliberately folded and superscribed the note'}
{'question': 'What did they pay to see?', 'source': 'For, people then paid to see the play at the Old Bailey, just as they paid to see the play in Bedlam-- only the former entertainment was much the dearer.', 'answer': 'the play in Bedlam-- only the former entertainment'}
{'question': 'Who am the door-keeper going to tell?', 'source': '``I am going to tell you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who did his cheek show?', 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': 'the soul to be stronger than the'}
{'question': 'Was the interest?', 'source': 'Whatever gloss the various spectators put upon the interest, according to their several arts and powers of self-deceit, the interest was, at the root of it, Ogreish.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who am I going to tell?', 'source': '``I am going to tell you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What is my good friend?', 'source': 'Take care of your chest and voice, my good friend, and leave the law to take care of itself.', 'answer': 'your chest and voice'}
{'question': 'Who is going to tell you?', 'source': '``I am going to tell you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "What's hard enough to kill him?", 'source': "It's hard enough to kill him, but it's wery hard to spile him, sir.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did his daughter have one of drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': 'of her hands'}
{'question': 'Did he see the door-keeper making his way to Mr. Lorry?', 'source': "Mr. Cruncher's attention was here diverted to the door-keeper, whom he saw making his way to Mr. Lorry, with the note in his hand.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had her forehead been strikingly expressive of an engrossing terror?', 'source': 'Her forehead had been strikingly expressive of an engrossing terror and compassion that saw nothing but the peril of the accused.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is your chest and voice?', 'source': 'Take care of your chest and voice, my good friend, and leave the law to take care of itself.', 'answer': 'my good friend'}
{'question': 'Who did she sit by?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': 'by him'}
{'question': 'What did he see?', 'source': 'Be that as it may, a change in his position making him conscious of a bar of light across his face, he looked up; and when he saw the glass his face flushed, and his right hand pushed the herbs away.', 'answer': 'the glass'}
{'question': 'Who did he stand with his hands resting on the slab of wood before?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': 'before him'}
{'question': 'Who does the door-keeper want?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who stood quiet?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Did Jerry say ``It's the damp, sir''?", 'source': "``It's the damp, sir, what settles on my chest and voice,'' said Jerry.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the object of all this bow to the Judge?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was otherwise quite self-possessed?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who does he want?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "May some passing thought of the infamy and disgrace for which it had been reserved, have struck the prisoner's mind?", 'source': "Some passing thought of the infamy and disgrace for which it had been reserved, may have struck the prisoner's mind.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Jerry say ``that advice's the damp, sir''?", 'source': "``It's the damp, sir, what settles on my chest and voice,'' said Jerry.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What does that's?", 'source': "``That's all.", 'answer': 'all'}
{'question': 'What was he plainly dressed in?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'in black, or very dark gray'}
{'question': 'What was his hair gathered in a ribbon at?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament'}
{'question': 'Did Jerry, and who had been sucking the rust off his fingers in his absorption, stretch his neck to hear who they were?', 'source': 'Jerry, the messenger, who had made his own observations, in his own manner, and who had been sucking the rust off his fingers in his absorption, stretched his neck to hear who they were.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had crowds of the wicked and the wretched been reflected in it?', 'source': "Crowds of the wicked and the wretched had been reflected in it, and had passed from its surface and this earth's together.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he stand with resting on the slab of wood before him?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': 'with his hands'}
{'question': 'Did he bow to the Judge?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did everybody present stare at him?', 'source': 'Everybody present, except the one wigged gentleman who looked at the ceiling, stared at him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all the human breath in the place, roll at him?', 'source': 'All the human breath in the place, rolled at him, like a sea, or a wind, or a fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was quiet and attentive?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Is then?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What was the object of all this's hair gathered in a ribbon at?", 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament'}
{'question': 'Was his condition that of a young gentleman?', 'source': 'His condition was that of a young gentleman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the object of all this stand quiet?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had Jerry made his own observations?', 'source': 'Jerry, the messenger, who had made his own observations, in his own manner, and who had been sucking the rust off his fingers in his absorption, stretched his neck to hear who they were.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he watch the opening proceedings with a grave interest?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Blaring, was the object of all this a young man of about five-and-twenty, well-grown and well-looking?', 'source': 'The object of all this staring and blaring, was a young man of about five-and-twenty, well-grown and well-looking, with a sunburnt cheek and a dark eye.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know Mr. Lorry?', 'source': "And you know Mr. Lorry.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they pay to see the play in Bedlam-- only the former entertainment?', 'source': 'For, people then paid to see the play at the Old Bailey, just as they paid to see the play in Bedlam-- only the former entertainment was much the dearer.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Staring, was the object of all this a young man of about five-and-twenty, well-grown and well-looking?', 'source': 'The object of all this staring and blaring, was a young man of about five-and-twenty, well-grown and well-looking, with a sunburnt cheek and a dark eye.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the object of all this's condition that of a young gentleman?", 'source': 'His condition was that of a young gentleman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do I think, ``It's hard in the law to spile a man''?", 'source': "``It's hard in the law to spile a man, I think.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will an emotion of the mind express through any covering of the body?', 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': "Did the old clerk say, ``we all have our various ways of gaining a livelihood''?", 'source': "``Well, well,'' said the old clerk; ``we all have our various ways of gaining a livelihood.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he wish to have a messenger at hand?', 'source': 'He wishes to have a messenger at hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What was the object of all this's hair gathered in at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament?", 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': 'in a ribbon'}
{'question': "Had crowds of the wicked and the wretched passed from its surface and this earth's together?", 'source': "Crowds of the wicked and the wretched had been reflected in it, and had passed from its surface and this earth's together.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had crowds of the wicked and the wretched passed from there's surface and this earth's together?", 'source': "Crowds of the wicked and the wretched had been reflected in it, and had passed from its surface and this earth's together.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the root of it Ogreish?', 'source': 'Whatever gloss the various spectators put upon the interest, according to their several arts and powers of self-deceit, the interest was, at the root of it, Ogreish.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the object of all this's hair long and dark?", 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What happened?', 'source': 'It happened, that the action turned his face to that side of the court which was on his left.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Do some of us have damp ways?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do some of us have dry ways?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did so the paleness which his situation engendered come through the brown upon his cheek sun?', 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did so the paleness which the object of all this's situation engendered come through the brown upon his cheek sun?", 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the object of all this otherwise quite self-possessed?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his hair gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the object of all this's cheek show the soul to be stronger than the?", 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do some of this have damp ways?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand quiet?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he come to the blotting-paper stage?', 'source': 'As the ancient clerk deliberately folded and superscribed the note, Mr. Cruncher, after surveying him in silence until he came to the blotting-paper stage, remarked:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his cheek show the soul to be stronger than the?', 'source': 'As an emotion of the mind will express itself through any covering of the body, so the paleness which his situation engendered came through the brown upon his cheek, showing the soul to be stronger than the sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the crowd about him have:?', 'source': 'The crowd about him had pressed and passed the inquiry on to the nearest attendant, and from him it had been more slowly pressed and passed back; at last it got to Jerry:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the object of all this plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do some of this have dry ways?', 'source': 'Some of us have damp ways, and some of us have dry ways.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'She had in her pity for the prisoner?', 'source': 'She had drawn close to him, in her dread of the scene, and in her pity for the prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this to tell sir you are there?', 'source': "This is to tell him you are there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will then let you in?', 'source': "He will then let you in.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did he stand with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he otherwise quite self-possessed?', 'source': 'He was otherwise quite self-possessed, bowed to the Judge, and stood quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the ocean one day to give up its dead?', 'source': 'Haunted in a most ghastly manner that abominable place would have been, if the glass could ever have rendered back its reflections, as the ocean is one day to give up its dead.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he find himself next to he asked?', 'source': 'he asked, in a whisper, of the man he found himself next to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will he then let in?', 'source': "He will then let you in.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Does it's wery hard to spile him?", 'source': "It's hard enough to kill him, but it's wery hard to spile him, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the ancient clerk deliberately folded and superscribed the note give you that advice?', 'source': "I give you that advice.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his hair long and dark?', 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were those always left wide open?', 'source': 'Therefore, all the Old Bailey doors were well guarded-- except, indeed, the social doors by which the criminals got there, and those were always left wide open.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it have more than once happened?', 'source': "It had more than once happened, that the Judge in the black cap pronounced his own doom as certainly as the prisoner's, and even died before him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his daughter have one of her hands drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's the sentence?", 'source': "That's the sentence.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he quiet and attentive?', 'source': 'He was quiet and attentive; watched the opening proceedings with a grave interest; and stood with his hands resting on the slab of wood before him, so composedly, that they had not displaced a leaf of the herbs with which it was strewn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he see the glass?', 'source': 'Be that as it may, a change in his position making him conscious of a bar of light across his face, he looked up; and when he saw the glass his face flushed, and his right hand pushed the herbs away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she drawn close to him?', 'source': 'She had drawn close to him, in her dread of the scene, and in her pity for the prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he ask?', 'source': 'he asked, as the result of that conference.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your chest and voice my good friend?', 'source': 'Take care of your chest and voice, my good friend, and leave the law to take care of itself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had this been so very noticeable, so very powerfully and naturally shown?', 'source': "This had been so very noticeable, so very powerfully and naturally shown, that starers who had had no pity for him were touched by her; and the whisper went about, ``Who are they?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this to tell him you are there?', 'source': "This is to tell him you are there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's all?", 'source': "``That's all.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's hard enough to kill him?", 'source': "It's hard enough to kill him, but it's wery hard to spile him, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it happen?', 'source': 'It happened, that the action turned his face to that side of the court which was on his left.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does he's found Guilty?", 'source': "``If he's found Guilty, you mean to say?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I going to tell you?', 'source': '``I am going to tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she sit by him?', 'source': 'His daughter had one of her hands drawn through his arm, as she sat by him, and the other pressed upon it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the object of all this's hair gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament?", 'source': 'He was plainly dressed in black, or very dark gray, and his hair, which was long and dark, was gathered in a ribbon at the back of his neck; more to be out of his way than for ornament.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he want you?', 'source': "Then what you have to do, is, to remain there until he wants you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I give you that advice?', 'source': "I give you that advice.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will he then let you in?', 'source': "He will then let you in.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Pride submission?', 'source': 'Pride, contempt, defiance, stubbornness, submission, lamentation, succeeded one another; so did varieties of sunken cheek, cadaverous color, emaciated hands and figures.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose work was it so like?', 'source': "It was so like Smith's work, so much more like the top of a strongly spiked wall than a head of hair, that the best of players at leap-frog might have declined him, as the most dangerous man in the world to go over.", 'answer': "like Smith's work"}
{'question': 'Was the crown raggedly bald?', 'source': 'Except on the crown, which was raggedly bald, he had stiff, black hair, standing jaggedly all over it, and growing down hill almost to his broad, blunt nose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked out at the rising sun?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Would the ghostly face rise?', 'source': 'Out of the midst of them, the ghostly face would rise, and he would accost it again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Pride contempt?', 'source': 'Pride, contempt, defiance, stubbornness, submission, lamentation, succeeded one another; so did varieties of sunken cheek, cadaverous color, emaciated hands and figures.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did the shadows of the night reveal?', 'source': 'To whom, likewise, the shadows of the night revealed themselves, in the forms their dozing eyes and wandering thoughts suggested.', 'answer': 'themselves'}
{'question': 'Do the rattle of the harness not understand?', 'source': "I do not understand.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What hope in time to read it all?', 'source': 'No more can I turn the leaves of this dear book that I loved, and vainly hope in time to read it all.', 'answer': 'vainly'}
{'question': 'What did his natural and not to be alienated inheritance have exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in?', 'source': 'As to this, his natural and not to be alienated inheritance, the messenger on horseback had exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in London.', 'answer': 'in London'}
{'question': 'What did the shadows of the night reveal?', 'source': 'To whom, likewise, the shadows of the night revealed themselves, in the forms their dozing eyes and wandering thoughts suggested.', 'answer': 'themselves'}
{'question': 'What did he move this muffler with?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': 'with his left hand'}
{'question': 'Who lowered the window?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What glanced into it?', 'source': 'No more can I look into the depths of this unfathomable water, wherein, as momentary lights glanced into it, I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged.', 'answer': 'momentary lights'}
{'question': 'Was the sky clear?', 'source': 'Though the earth was cold and wet, the sky was clear, and the sun rose bright, placid, and beautiful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would the passenger then lower the window?', 'source': 'The passenger would then start to himself, and lower the window, to get the reality of mist and rain on his cheek.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he look out at?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': 'at the rising sun'}
{'question': 'What did he move with his left hand?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': 'this muffler'}
{'question': 'Was every head prematurely white?', 'source': 'But the face was in the main one face, and every head was prematurely white.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it given in?', 'source': "Sometimes, it was given in a tender rain of tears, and then it was, ``Take me to her.''", 'answer': 'in a tender rain of tears'}
{'question': 'Who had a sinister expression?', 'source': "They had a sinister expression, under an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon, and over a great muffler for the chin and throat, which descended nearly to the wearer's knees.", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What do I have had submerged?', 'source': 'No more can I look into the depths of this unfathomable water, wherein, as momentary lights glanced into it, I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged.', 'answer': 'glimpses of buried treasure and other things'}
{'question': 'What would it not suit _ your _ line of!', 'source': 'Jerry, you honest tradesman, it would not suit _ your _ line of business!', 'answer': 'of business'}
{'question': 'Who was his natural and not to be alienated inheritance?', 'source': 'As to this, his natural and not to be alienated inheritance, the messenger on horseback had exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in London.', 'answer': 'the messenger on horseback'}
{'question': 'What did he lower?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': 'the window'}
{'question': 'Would the passenger then start to himself?', 'source': 'The passenger would then start to himself, and lower the window, to get the reality of mist and rain on his cheek.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon pour his liquor in with his right?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they have?', 'source': "They had a sinister expression, under an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon, and over a great muffler for the chin and throat, which descended nearly to the wearer's knees.", 'answer': 'a sinister expression'}
{'question': 'Was the broken reply?', 'source': "Sometimes, it was given in a tender rain of tears, and then it was, ``Take me to her.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he have?', 'source': 'Except on the crown, which was raggedly bald, he had stiff, black hair, standing jaggedly all over it, and growing down hill almost to his broad, blunt nose.', 'answer': 'stiff, black hair'}
{'question': 'What was it so like?', 'source': "It was so like Smith's work, so much more like the top of a strongly spiked wall than a head of hair, that the best of players at leap-frog might have declined him, as the most dangerous man in the world to go over.", 'answer': "like Smith's work"}
{'question': 'Was the earth cold and wet?', 'source': 'Though the earth was cold and wet, the sky was clear, and the sun rose bright, placid, and beautiful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would accost it again?', 'source': 'Out of the midst of them, the ghostly face would rise, and he would accost it again.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What were his eyes opened on?', 'source': 'Yet even when his eyes were opened on the mist and rain, on the moving patch of light from the lamps, and the hedge at the roadside retreating by jerks, the night shadows outside the coach would fall into the train of the night shadows within.', 'answer': 'on the mist and rain'}
{'question': 'What he would suddenly fan away to?', 'source': 'Got out at last, with earth hanging about his face and hair, he would suddenly fan away to dust.', 'answer': 'to dust'}
{'question': 'What did he stop for?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': 'for drink'}
{'question': 'What had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone?', 'source': 'The words were still in his hearing as just spoken-- distinctly in his hearing as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone.', 'answer': 'ever spoken words'}
{'question': 'What did his message perplex his mind to several times?', 'source': 'His message perplexed his mind to that degree that he was fain, several times, to take off his hat to scratch his head.', 'answer': 'to that degree that he was fain,'}
{'question': 'What would it not suit _!', 'source': 'Jerry, you honest tradesman, it would not suit _ your _ line of business!', 'answer': 'your _ line of business'}
{'question': 'What was he on?', 'source': 'He was on his way to dig some one out of a grave.', 'answer': 'on his way to dig some one out of a grave'}
{'question': 'Shall who shows her to you?', 'source': '``Shall I show her to you?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What would he accost again?', 'source': 'Out of the midst of them, the ghostly face would rise, and he would accost it again.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did a wonderful fact to reflect upon constitute to be that profound secret and mystery to every other?', 'source': 'A wonderful fact to reflect upon, that every human creature is constituted to be that profound secret and mystery to every other.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sometimes who does not know her?', 'source': 'Sometimes it was staring and bewildered, and then it was, ``I do not know her.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What would kill me if I saw her too soon?', 'source': "It would kill me if I saw her too soon.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who would the passenger then start to?', 'source': 'The passenger would then start to himself, and lower the window, to get the reality of mist and rain on his cheek.', 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': 'Was it appointed that the water should be locked in an eternal frost?', 'source': 'It was appointed that the water should be locked in an eternal frost, when the light was playing on its surface, and I stood in ignorance on the shore.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he pour in with his right?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': 'his liquor'}
{'question': 'Who would it kill if I saw her too soon?', 'source': "It would kill me if I saw her too soon.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon move this muffler with his left hand?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a hundred times the dozing passenger inquire of this spectre:?', 'source': 'A hundred times the dozing passenger inquired of this spectre:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall who do I show her to?', 'source': '``Shall I show her to you?', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Shall who do I show to you?', 'source': '``Shall I show her to you?', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What was it appointed in?', 'source': 'It was appointed that the water should be locked in an eternal frost, when the light was playing on its surface, and I stood in ignorance on the shore.', 'answer': 'that the water should be locked in an eternal frost'}
{'question': 'What do I have?', 'source': 'No more can I look into the depths of this unfathomable water, wherein, as momentary lights glanced into it, I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged.', 'answer': 'had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged'}
{'question': 'Would the passenger in his fancy dig after such imaginary discourse?', 'source': 'After such imaginary discourse, the passenger in his fancy would dig, and dig, dig-- now with a spade, now with a great key, now with his hands-- to dig this wretched creature out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When was it appointed?', 'source': 'It was appointed that the book should shut with a spring, for ever and for ever, when I had read but a page.', 'answer': 'that the book should shut with a spring'}
{'question': "Did an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon's message perplex his mind to that degree that he was fain, several times?", 'source': 'His message perplexed his mind to that degree that he was fain, several times, to take off his hat to scratch his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sometimes who do I not know?', 'source': 'Sometimes it was staring and bewildered, and then it was, ``I do not know her.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Did his message perplex his mind to that degree that he was fain, several times?', 'source': 'His message perplexed his mind to that degree that he was fain, several times, to take off his hat to scratch his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were the words still in as just spoken as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone?', 'source': 'The words were still in his hearing as just spoken-- distinctly in his hearing as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone.', 'answer': 'in his hearing'}
{'question': 'Do I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged?', 'source': 'No more can I look into the depths of this unfathomable water, wherein, as momentary lights glanced into it, I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is something of the awfulness, even of Death a wonderful fact to reflect upon, that every human creature is, referable to this?', 'source': 'Something of the awfulness, even of Death itself, is referable to this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were still in his hearing as just spoken as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone?', 'source': 'The words were still in his hearing as just spoken-- distinctly in his hearing as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone.', 'answer': 'the words'}
{'question': 'Did I stand in ignorance on the shore?', 'source': 'It was appointed that the water should be locked in an eternal frost, when the light was playing on its surface, and I stood in ignorance on the shore.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What seemed to be numerous?', 'source': 'They seemed to be numerous, for she shied at every shadow on the road.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was it given in a tender rain of tears?', 'source': "Sometimes, it was given in a tender rain of tears, and then it was, ``Take me to her.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it appointed that the book should shut with a spring?', 'source': 'It was appointed that the book should shut with a spring, for ever and for ever, when I had read but a page.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the answers to this question various and contradictory?', 'source': 'The answers to this question were various and contradictory.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the plough upon it where it had been left last night when the horses were unyoked; beyond a quiet coppice-wood?', 'source': 'There was a ridge of ploughed land, with a plough upon it where it had been left last night when the horses were unyoked; beyond, a quiet coppice-wood, in which many leaves of burning red and golden yellow still remained upon the trees.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look out at the rising sun?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she shy at every shadow on the road?', 'source': 'They seemed to be numerous, for she shied at every shadow on the road.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did momentary lights glance into it?', 'source': 'No more can I look into the depths of this unfathomable water, wherein, as momentary lights glanced into it, I have had glimpses of buried treasure and other things submerged.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does not understand?', 'source': "I do not understand.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did they have a sinister expression?', 'source': "They had a sinister expression, under an old cocked-hat like a three-cornered spittoon, and over a great muffler for the chin and throat, which descended nearly to the wearer's knees.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who rode?', 'source': 'said the messenger, harping on one theme as he rode.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was his natural and not to be alienated inheritance the messenger on horseback?', 'source': 'As to this, his natural and not to be alienated inheritance, the messenger on horseback had exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in London.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is something of the awfulness, even of Death itself, referable to this?', 'source': 'Something of the awfulness, even of Death itself, is referable to this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do vainly hope in time to read it all?', 'source': 'No more can I turn the leaves of this dear book that I loved, and vainly hope in time to read it all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have stiff, black hair?', 'source': 'Except on the crown, which was raggedly bald, he had stiff, black hair, standing jaggedly all over it, and growing down hill almost to his broad, blunt nose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lower the window?', 'source': 'He lowered the window, and looked out at the rising sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was it so like Smith's work?", 'source': "It was so like Smith's work, so much more like the top of a strongly spiked wall than a head of hair, that the best of players at leap-frog might have declined him, as the most dangerous man in the world to go over.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his eyes opened on the mist and rain?', 'source': 'Yet even when his eyes were opened on the mist and rain, on the moving patch of light from the lamps, and the hedge at the roadside retreating by jerks, the night shadows outside the coach would fall into the train of the night shadows within.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he on his way to dig some one out of a grave?', 'source': 'He was on his way to dig some one out of a grave.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he move this muffler with his left hand?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'He would suddenly fan away to dust?', 'source': 'Got out at last, with earth hanging about his face and hair, he would suddenly fan away to dust.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it not suit _ your _ line of business!', 'source': 'Jerry, you honest tradesman, it would not suit _ your _ line of business!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stop for drink?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it kill me if I saw her too soon?', 'source': "It would kill me if I saw her too soon.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they seem to be numerous?', 'source': 'They seemed to be numerous, for she shied at every shadow on the road.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his natural and not to be alienated inheritance have exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in London?', 'source': 'As to this, his natural and not to be alienated inheritance, the messenger on horseback had exactly the same possessions as the King, the first Minister of State, or the richest merchant in London.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pour his liquor in with his right?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he muffle again?', 'source': 'When he stopped for drink, he moved this muffler with his left hand, only while he poured his liquor in with his right; as soon as that was done, he muffled again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had ever spoken words been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone?', 'source': 'The words were still in his hearing as just spoken-- distinctly in his hearing as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall do I show her to you?', 'source': '``Shall I show her to you?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he accost it again?', 'source': 'Out of the midst of them, the ghostly face would rise, and he would accost it again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not understand?', 'source': "I do not understand.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sometimes do I not know her?', 'source': 'Sometimes it was staring and bewildered, and then it was, ``I do not know her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it?', 'source': "Sometimes, it was given in a tender rain of tears, and then it was, ``Take me to her.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he ride?', 'source': 'said the messenger, harping on one theme as he rode.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the words still in his hearing as just spoken as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone?', 'source': 'The words were still in his hearing as just spoken-- distinctly in his hearing as ever spoken words had been in his life-- when the weary passenger started to the consciousness of daylight, and found that the shadows of the night were gone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is better for the poor little plaything to die so?', 'source': 'It is better for the poor little plaything to die so, than to live.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Who said, ``I devote you''?", 'source': "``I devote you,'' said this person, stopping at the last door on his way, and turning in the direction of the sanctuary, ``to the Devil!''", 'answer': 'this person'}
{'question': 'Who is my Gaspard?', 'source': '``Be a brave man, my Gaspard!', 'answer': 'the brave man'}
{'question': 'What had they been silent after?', 'source': 'Neither did the people say anything; after the first cry, they had been silent, and they remained so.', 'answer': 'after the first cry'}
{'question': 'What was he arrested by?', 'source': 'He was arrested by the quick arrival of another man, for whom the rest made way.', 'answer': 'by the quick arrival of another man'}
{'question': 'Was a sumptuous man the Farmer-General?', 'source': 'A sumptuous man was the Farmer-General.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was not one not for?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': "for the woman who stood knitting's dignity to notice it"}
{'question': 'Who was a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed?', 'source': 'He was a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed, haughty in manner, and with a face like a fine mask.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What is it better for to die so?', 'source': 'It is better for the poor little plaything to die so, than to live.', 'answer': 'for the poor little plaything'}
{'question': 'Who had stood in a little space apart?', 'source': 'Not many people had talked with him at the reception; he had stood in a little space apart, and Monseigneur might have been warmer in his manner.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who was their condition?', 'source': 'So cowed was their condition, and so long and hard their experience of what such a man could do to them, within the law and beyond it, that not a voice, or a hand, or even an eye was raised.', 'answer': 'cowed'}
{'question': 'Was Monseigneur seen no more?', 'source': 'There, Monseigneur turned, and came back again, and so in due course of time got himself shut up in his sanctuary by the chocolate sprites, and was seen no more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who got into his carriage?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': 'its owner'}
{'question': "Did the only little change that the face ever's owner drive away?", 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was not one not for the woman who stood knitting's dignity to notice it?", 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he have allied himself perforce with?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': 'with a Farmer-General'}
{'question': 'Monseigneur was about to take his chocolate?', 'source': 'Monseigneur was about to take his chocolate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If they had been mere what do rats come out of?', 'source': 'Monsieur the Marquis ran his eyes over them all, as if they had been mere rats come out of their holes.', 'answer': 'of their holes'}
{'question': 'What would they be contracted by?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': 'by something like a faint pulsation'}
{'question': 'If they had been mere what come out of their holes?', 'source': 'Monsieur the Marquis ran his eyes over them all, as if they had been mere rats come out of their holes.', 'answer': 'rats'}
{'question': 'What were the common wretches left to get out of their difficulties as they could in?', 'source': 'But, few cared enough for that to think of it a second time, and, in this matter, as in all others, the common wretches were left to get out of their difficulties as they could.', 'answer': 'in all others'}
{'question': 'What was his snuff-box slowly passed among?', 'source': 'There was soon but one person left of all the crowd, and he, with his hat under his arm and his snuff-box in his hand, slowly passed among the mirrors on his way out.', 'answer': 'among the mirrors'}
{'question': 'What did he shake the snuff from as if he had shaken the dust from his feet?', 'source': 'With that, he shook the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet, and quietly walked downstairs.', 'answer': 'from his fingers'}
{'question': 'If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage if that brigand were sufficiently near it what should he be crushed under?', 'source': "If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage, and if that brigand were sufficiently near it, he should be crushed under the wheels.''", 'answer': 'under the wheels'}
{'question': 'Did a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in about sixty clearly defined; one set expression on it?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage if that brigand were sufficiently near it who should be crushed under the wheels?', 'source': "If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage, and if that brigand were sufficiently near it, he should be crushed under the wheels.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the only little change that the face ever appear?', 'source': 'It appeared, under the circumstances, rather agreeable to him to see the common people dispersed before his horses, and often barely escaping from being run down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was his inner room his sanctuary of?', 'source': 'Monseigneur was in his inner room, his sanctuary of sanctuaries, the Holiest of Holiests to the crowd of worshippers in the suite of rooms without.', 'answer': 'of sanctuaries'}
{'question': "Who threw him another gold coin, ``and spend it as you will''?", 'source': "``Pick up that, philosopher and vendor of wine,'' said the Marquis, throwing him another gold coin, ``and spend it as you will.", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'Did monseigneur having taken his chocolate, cause the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be issued forth?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did monseigneur having taken his chocolate, cause the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did few care enough for that to think of a second time?', 'source': 'But, few cared enough for that to think of it a second time, and, in this matter, as in all others, the common wretches were left to get out of their difficulties as they could.', 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'Were the lips of the master?', 'source': 'His man drove as if he were charging an enemy, and the furious recklessness of the man brought no check into the face, or to the lips, of the master.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What set expression on it?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': 'a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in about sixty clearly defined; one'}
{'question': 'Was Monsieur calmly?', 'source': 'said Monsieur, calmly looking out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were often known to leave their wounded behind, and why not? ?', 'source': 'But for the latter inconvenience, the carriage probably would not have stopped; carriages were often known to drive on, and leave their wounded behind, and why not?', 'answer': 'carriages'}
{'question': 'Who persisted in changing color sometimes?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did his contemptuous eyes pass over?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'over her'}
{'question': 'What is one or the other of you for ever in?', 'source': 'One or the other of you is for ever in the way.', 'answer': 'in the way'}
{'question': 'Who drove away?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': "the only little change that the face ever's owner"}
{'question': 'Were carriages often known to leave there behind, and why not? ?', 'source': 'But for the latter inconvenience, the carriage probably would not have stopped; carriages were often known to drive on, and leave their wounded behind, and why not?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who quietly walked downstairs?', 'source': 'With that, he shook the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet, and quietly walked downstairs.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What had he stood in apart?', 'source': 'Not many people had talked with him at the reception; he had stood in a little space apart, and Monseigneur might have been warmer in his manner.', 'answer': 'in a little space'}
{'question': 'Where did he lean back again?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'in his seat'}
{'question': "What did he give ``Go on''?", 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'the word'}
{'question': 'What did a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': 'on it'}
{'question': 'Did Monsieur Paris preside in this dainty dress at the gallows and the wheel?', 'source': 'At the gallows and the wheel-- the axe was a rarity-- Monsieur Paris, as it was the episcopal mode among his brother Professors of the provinces, Monsieur Orleans, and the rest, to call him, presided in this dainty dress.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What must he have died of?', 'source': 'Deep would have been the blot upon his escutcheon if his chocolate had been ignobly waited on by only three men; he must have died of two.', 'answer': 'of two'}
{'question': 'Was the nose beautifully formed otherwise?', 'source': 'The nose, beautifully formed otherwise, was very slightly pinched at the top of each nostril.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he a man of, handsomely dressed?', 'source': 'He was a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed, haughty in manner, and with a face like a fine mask.', 'answer': 'of about sixty'}
{'question': 'What was it at?', 'source': 'The fountain was a little removed; for the street opened, where it was, into a space some ten or twelve yards square.', 'answer': 'at the street opened'}
{'question': 'What did its owner get into?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': 'into his carriage'}
{'question': "Did the Marquis throw him another gold coin, ``and spend that as you will''?", 'source': "``Pick up that, philosopher and vendor of wine,'' said the Marquis, throwing him another gold coin, ``and spend it as you will.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did they remain looking on?', 'source': 'The rats had crept out of their holes to look on, and they remained looking on for hours; soldiers and police often passing between them and the spectacle, and making a barrier behind which they slunk, and through which they peeped.', 'answer': 'for hours; soldiers and police passing between them and the spectacle'}
{'question': 'Were carriages often known to drive on, and why not? ?', 'source': 'But for the latter inconvenience, the carriage probably would not have stopped; carriages were often known to drive on, and leave their wounded behind, and why not?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is only the pronoun not much?', 'source': "The text of his order (altered from the original by only a pronoun, which is not much) ran: ``The earth and the fulness thereof are mine, saith Monseigneur.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is extraordinary to me that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What passed over her?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'his contemptuous eyes'}
{'question': 'Who leaned back in his seat again?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'the woman who stood knitting'}
{'question': 'Who is it extraordinary to that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': 'to me'}
{'question': 'Was the comfort?', 'source': 'But, the comfort was, that all the company at the grand hotel of Monseigneur were perfectly dressed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did all the heads crane forward at?', 'source': 'He threw out a gold coin for the valet to pick up, and all the heads craned forward that all the eyes might look down at it as it fell.', 'answer': 'that all the eyes might look down at a gold coin for the valet as it fell'}
{'question': 'What did a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in about sixty clearly defined; one set expression on?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': 'on it'}
{'question': 'What did he quietly walk?', 'source': 'With that, he shook the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet, and quietly walked downstairs.', 'answer': 'downstairs'}
{'question': 'What showed?', 'source': 'In those two compressions, or dints, the only little change that the face ever showed, resided.', 'answer': 'the only little change that the face ever'}
{'question': 'Were all the heads as silent?', 'source': 'They were as silent, however, as the men.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set on it?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': 'expression'}
{'question': 'Who did Monseigneur have allied with?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': 'himself perforce with a Farmer-General'}
{'question': 'Who took out his purse?', 'source': 'He took out his purse.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is it extraordinary to me that you people cannot take care of?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': 'of yourselves and your children'}
{'question': 'Did neither remain so?', 'source': 'Neither did the people say anything; after the first cry, they had been silent, and they remained so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the Farmer-General at least the greatest reality among the personages who attended at the hotel of Monseigneur that day as?', 'source': 'As one who pretended to do nothing but plunder and forage where he could, the Farmer-General-- howsoever his matrimonial relations conduced to social morality-- was at least the greatest reality among the personages who attended at the hotel of Monseigneur that day.', 'answer': 'as one who pretended to do nothing but plunder and forage where he could'}
{'question': 'What appeared?', 'source': 'It appeared, under the circumstances, rather agreeable to him to see the common people dispersed before his horses, and often barely escaping from being run down.', 'answer': 'the only little change that the face ever'}
{'question': 'What was his inner room?', 'source': 'Monseigneur was in his inner room, his sanctuary of sanctuaries, the Holiest of Holiests to the crowd of worshippers in the suite of rooms without.', 'answer': 'his sanctuary of sanctuaries'}
{'question': 'Who was you?', 'source': "``You are a philosopher, you there,'' said the Marquis, smiling.", 'answer': 'the philosopher'}
{'question': 'What is it extraordinary to me that you people cannot take?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': 'care of yourselves and your children'}
{'question': 'Who was the philosopher?', 'source': "``You are a philosopher, you there,'' said the Marquis, smiling.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Was exquisite gentlemen of the finest breeding at that remarkable time?', 'source': 'Exquisite gentlemen of the finest breeding, which was at that remarkable time-- and has been since-- to be known by its fruits of indifference to every natural subject of human interest, were in the most exemplary state of exhaustion, at the hotel of Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was not for his dignity to notice it?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Did the text of his order run: ``The earth and the fulness thereof are mine, saith Monseigneur?''", 'source': "The text of his order (altered from the original by only a pronoun, which is not much) ran: ``The earth and the fulness thereof are mine, saith Monseigneur.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he lean back in again?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'in his seat'}
{'question': 'Are the horses there; they right?', 'source': "The horses there; are they right?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If I knew at if that brigand were sufficiently near it what should he be crushed under the wheels?', 'source': "If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage, and if that brigand were sufficiently near it, he should be crushed under the wheels.''", 'answer': 'which rascal threw at the carriage'}
{'question': 'Did its owner go downstairs into the courtyard?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he take out?', 'source': 'He took out his purse.', 'answer': 'his purse'}
{'question': 'Was nothing in that way left for Heaven-- which may have been one among other reasons why the worshippers of Monseigneur never troubled it?', 'source': 'As to bowing down in body and spirit, nothing in that way was left for Heaven-- which may have been one among other reasons why the worshippers of Monseigneur never troubled it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he arrested by the quick arrival of another man?', 'source': 'He was arrested by the quick arrival of another man, for whom the rest made way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he throw out a gold coin for the valet to pick up?', 'source': 'He threw out a gold coin for the valet to pick up, and all the heads craned forward that all the eyes might look down at it as it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was nothing in that way left for?', 'source': 'As to bowing down in body and spirit, nothing in that way was left for Heaven-- which may have been one among other reasons why the worshippers of Monseigneur never troubled it.', 'answer': 'for Heaven-- which may have been one among other reasons why the worshippers of Monseigneur never troubled it'}
{'question': 'Would they be contracted by something like a faint pulsation?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the miserable creature fall upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'On seeing him, the miserable creature fell upon his shoulder, sobbing and crying, and pointing to the fountain, where some women were stooping over the motionless bundle, and moving gently about it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did this person say, ``Monseigneur devote you''?", 'source': "``I devote you,'' said this person, stopping at the last door on his way, and turning in the direction of the sanctuary, ``to the Devil!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they been silent after the first cry?', 'source': 'Neither did the people say anything; after the first cry, they had been silent, and they remained so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he have allied with?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': 'himself perforce with a Farmer-General'}
{'question': 'Did one of its wheels come to a sickening little jolt?', 'source': 'At last, swooping at a street corner by a fountain, one of its wheels came to a sickening little jolt, and there was a loud cry from a number of voices, and the horses reared and plunged.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would those two compressions be contracted by something like a faint pulsation?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a tall man in a nightcap down in the mud and wet, howling over it like a wild animal?', 'source': 'A tall man in a nightcap had caught up a bundle from among the feet of the horses, and had laid it on the basement of the fountain, and was down in the mud and wet, howling over it like a wild animal.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would Deep have been the blot upon his escutcheon if his chocolate had been ignobly waited on by only three men?', 'source': 'Deep would have been the blot upon his escutcheon if his chocolate had been ignobly waited on by only three men; he must have died of two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they give a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Marquis clap his hand for an instant on his sword-hilt?', 'source': 'As the tall man suddenly got up from the ground, and came running at the carriage, Monsieur the Marquis clapped his hand for an instant on his sword-hilt.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it do a world of good which never became manifest?', 'source': 'Among these, accordingly, much discoursing with spirits went on-- and it did a world of good which never became manifest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were as silent?', 'source': 'They were as silent, however, as the men.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was it impossible for Monseigneur to hold his high place under the admiring Heavens?', 'source': 'It was impossible for Monseigneur to dispense with one of these attendants on the chocolate and hold his high place under the admiring Heavens.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it impossible for Monseigneur to dispense with one of these attendants on the chocolate?', 'source': 'It was impossible for Monseigneur to dispense with one of these attendants on the chocolate and hold his high place under the admiring Heavens.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would be occasionally dilated?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Did the last comer say ``I know all''?", 'source': "``I know all, I know all,'' said the last comer.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens, cause the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens, cause the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be issued forth?', 'source': 'Monseigneur having eased his four men of their burdens and taken his chocolate, caused the doors of the Holiest of Holiests to be thrown open, and issued forth.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were some women moving gently about it at the fountain?', 'source': 'On seeing him, the miserable creature fell upon his shoulder, sobbing and crying, and pointing to the fountain, where some women were stooping over the motionless bundle, and moving gently about it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did thirty horses stand in his stables?', 'source': 'Thirty horses stood in his stables, twenty-four male domestics sat in his halls, six body-women waited on his wife.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Peasant women bring them up?', 'source': 'Peasant women kept the unfashionable babies close, and brought them up, and charming grandmammas of sixty dressed and supped as at twenty.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the last comer say ?', 'source': "``I know all, I know all,'' said the last comer.", 'answer': 'I know all'}
{'question': 'Did these do a world of good which never became manifest?', 'source': 'Among these, accordingly, much discoursing with spirits went on-- and it did a world of good which never became manifest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had a tall man in a nightcap laid it on the basement of the fountain?', 'source': 'A tall man in a nightcap had caught up a bundle from among the feet of the horses, and had laid it on the basement of the fountain, and was down in the mud and wet, howling over it like a wild animal.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did those two compressions give a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it better for the poor little plaything to die so?', 'source': 'It is better for the poor little plaything to die so, than to live.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it do?', 'source': 'Among these, accordingly, much discoursing with spirits went on-- and it did a world of good which never became manifest.', 'answer': 'a world of good which never became manifest'}
{'question': 'Had not many people talked with him at the reception?', 'source': 'Not many people had talked with him at the reception; he had stood in a little space apart, and Monseigneur might have been warmer in his manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has it died in a moment without pain?', 'source': 'It has died in a moment without pain.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did these do?', 'source': 'Among these, accordingly, much discoursing with spirits went on-- and it did a world of good which never became manifest.', 'answer': 'a world of good which never became manifest'}
{'question': 'Was his snuff-box slowly passed among the mirrors?', 'source': 'There was soon but one person left of all the crowd, and he, with his hat under his arm and his snuff-box in his hand, slowly passed among the mirrors on his way out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are the horses there; right?', 'source': "The horses there; are they right?''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did all the heads crane forward that all the eyes might look down at it as it fell?', 'source': 'He threw out a gold coin for the valet to pick up, and all the heads craned forward that all the eyes might look down at it as it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he stood in a little space apart?', 'source': 'Not many people had talked with him at the reception; he had stood in a little space apart, and Monseigneur might have been warmer in his manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Marquis run his eyes over them all?', 'source': 'Monsieur the Marquis ran his eyes over them all, as if they had been mere rats come out of their holes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the Farmer-General at least the greatest reality among the personages who attended at the hotel of Monseigneur that day as one who pretended to do nothing but plunder and forage where he could?', 'source': 'As one who pretended to do nothing but plunder and forage where he could, the Farmer-General-- howsoever his matrimonial relations conduced to social morality-- was at least the greatest reality among the personages who attended at the hotel of Monseigneur that day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are the horses there; right?', 'source': "The horses there; are they right?''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Were the common wretches left to get out of their difficulties as they could in all others?', 'source': 'But, few cared enough for that to think of it a second time, and, in this matter, as in all others, the common wretches were left to get out of their difficulties as they could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did those two compressions persist in changing color sometimes?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was he?', 'source': 'He was a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed, haughty in manner, and with a face like a fine mask.', 'answer': 'a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed'}
{'question': 'Did they remain looking on for hours; soldiers and police making a barrier behind which they slunk?', 'source': 'The rats had crept out of their holes to look on, and they remained looking on for hours; soldiers and police often passing between them and the spectacle, and making a barrier behind which they slunk, and through which they peeped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he shake the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet?', 'source': 'With that, he shook the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet, and quietly walked downstairs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the crowd of worshippers in the suite of rooms impossible for Monseigneur to dispense with one of these attendants on the chocolate?', 'source': 'It was impossible for Monseigneur to dispense with one of these attendants on the chocolate and hold his high place under the admiring Heavens.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was cowed their condition?', 'source': 'So cowed was their condition, and so long and hard their experience of what such a man could do to them, within the law and beyond it, that not a voice, or a hand, or even an eye was raised.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they persist in changing color sometimes?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it extraordinary to me that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it at the street opened?', 'source': 'The fountain was a little removed; for the street opened, where it was, into a space some ten or twelve yards square.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the brave man my Gaspard?', 'source': '``Be a brave man, my Gaspard!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did Monseigneur have with?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': 'allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General'}
{'question': "Did he give the word ``Go on''?", 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who remained so?', 'source': 'Neither did the people say anything; after the first cry, they had been silent, and they remained so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did his man drive as if he were charging an enemy?', 'source': 'His man drove as if he were charging an enemy, and the furious recklessness of the man brought no check into the face, or to the lips, of the master.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed?', 'source': 'He was a man of about sixty, handsomely dressed, haughty in manner, and with a face like a fine mask.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must he have died of two?', 'source': 'Deep would have been the blot upon his escutcheon if his chocolate had been ignobly waited on by only three men; he must have died of two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his inner room his sanctuary of sanctuaries?', 'source': 'Monseigneur was in his inner room, his sanctuary of sanctuaries, the Holiest of Holiests to the crowd of worshippers in the suite of rooms without.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he quietly walk downstairs?', 'source': 'With that, he shook the snuff from his fingers as if he had shaken the dust from his feet, and quietly walked downstairs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were carriages often known to leave their wounded behind, and why not? ?', 'source': 'But for the latter inconvenience, the carriage probably would not have stopped; carriages were often known to drive on, and leave their wounded behind, and why not?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage if that brigand were sufficiently near it should he be crushed under the wheels?', 'source': "If I knew which rascal threw at the carriage, and if that brigand were sufficiently near it, he should be crushed under the wheels.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did its owner drive away?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If they had been mere do rats come out of their holes?', 'source': 'Monsieur the Marquis ran his eyes over them all, as if they had been mere rats come out of their holes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did this person say, ``I devote you''?", 'source': "``I devote you,'' said this person, stopping at the last door on his way, and turning in the direction of the sanctuary, ``to the Devil!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did its owner get into his carriage?', 'source': 'Its owner went downstairs into the courtyard, got into his carriage, and drove away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they remain looking on for hours; soldiers and police passing between them and the spectacle?', 'source': 'The rats had crept out of their holes to look on, and they remained looking on for hours; soldiers and police often passing between them and the spectacle, and making a barrier behind which they slunk, and through which they peeped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is one or the other of you for ever in the way?', 'source': 'One or the other of you is for ever in the way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the philosopher you?', 'source': "``You are a philosopher, you there,'' said the Marquis, smiling.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Marquis throw him another gold coin, ``and spend it as you will''?", 'source': "``Pick up that, philosopher and vendor of wine,'' said the Marquis, throwing him another gold coin, ``and spend it as you will.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his contemptuous eyes pass over her?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would they be occasionally dilated?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would those two compressions be occasionally dilated?', 'source': 'They persisted in changing color sometimes, and they would be occasionally dilated and contracted by something like a faint pulsation; then, they gave a look of treachery, and cruelty, to the whole countenance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they as silent?', 'source': 'They were as silent, however, as the men.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lean back in his seat again?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it?', 'source': 'A face of a transparent paleness; every feature in it clearly defined; one set expression on it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he have with?', 'source': 'Yet, Monseigneur had slowly found that vulgar embarrassments crept into his affairs, both private and public; and he had, as to both classes of affairs, allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General.', 'answer': 'allied himself perforce with a Farmer-General'}
{'question': 'Was it not for his dignity to notice it?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they remain so?', 'source': 'Neither did the people say anything; after the first cry, they had been silent, and they remained so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it appear?', 'source': 'It appeared, under the circumstances, rather agreeable to him to see the common people dispersed before his horses, and often barely escaping from being run down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it not for?', 'source': "It was not for his dignity to notice it; his contemptuous eyes passed over her, and over all the other rats; and he leaned back in his seat again, and gave the word ``Go on!''", 'answer': 'for his dignity to notice it'}
{'question': 'Did he take out his purse?', 'source': 'He took out his purse.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it fall?', 'source': 'He threw out a gold coin for the valet to pick up, and all the heads craned forward that all the eyes might look down at it as it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it extraordinary to me?', 'source': "``It is extraordinary to me,'' said he, ``that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children.", 'answer': 'that you people cannot take care of yourselves and your children'}
{'question': 'Who held her?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry got his arm securely round the daughter's waist, and held her; for he felt that she was sinking.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': "What did he drop his cleaner hand upon the joker's heart in?", 'source': "In his expostulation he dropped his cleaner hand (perhaps accidentally, perhaps not) upon the joker's heart.", 'answer': 'in his expostulation'}
{'question': 'Who called to him across the way?', 'source': 'There, his eyes happening to catch the tall joker writing up his joke, he called to him across the way:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who was then?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': 'God'}
{'question': "What did he drop upon the joker's heart in his expostulation?", 'source': "In his expostulation he dropped his cleaner hand (perhaps accidentally, perhaps not) upon the joker's heart.", 'answer': 'his cleaner hand'}
{'question': 'Who do Monsieur bring to him you bring to?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Who acknowledged their homage by giving them a quick look?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Were two playing cards two playing dominoes?', 'source': 'Other company were there: two playing cards, two playing dominoes, three standing by the counter lengthening out a short supply of wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a faint voice answer something?', 'source': 'A faint voice answered something.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Monsieur bring to him bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Was Willingly sir?', 'source': "``Willingly, sir,'' said Monsieur Defarge, and quietly stepped with him to the door.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Monsieur bring to you bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Where were that soon?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': 'at the top'}
{'question': 'When did they stop?', 'source': 'At last, the top of the staircase was gained, and they stopped for the third time.', 'answer': 'for the third time'}
{'question': 'What can one of you show?', 'source': 'But, now that I remember, one of you has already been there, and can show the way.', 'answer': 'the way'}
{'question': 'What did he wipe upon with that advice?', 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': "his soiled hand upon the joker's dress"}
{'question': 'Who rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady?', 'source': 'The wine-shop keeper accordingly rolled his eyes about, until they rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady, who were seated in a corner.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who acknowledged their homage by bending her head?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did he sit down just within the door?', 'source': 'He sat her down just within the door, and held her, clinging to him.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Did the wine-shop keeper wear no coat?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Monsieur know not what harm-- if his door was left open?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it open from?', 'source': 'It opened from a stinking little black courtyard, and was the general public entrance to a great pile of houses, inhabited by a great number of people.', 'answer': 'from a stinking little black courtyard'}
{'question': 'Were two playing dominoes three?', 'source': 'Other company were there: two playing cards, two playing dominoes, three standing by the counter lengthening out a short supply of wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is English; that is another thing?', 'source': 'Enough; you are English; that is another thing.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who beckoned them to enter?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the three glide by?', 'source': 'The three glided by, and went silently down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady?', 'source': 'The wine-shop keeper accordingly rolled his eyes about, until they rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady, who were seated in a corner.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did he look in through?', 'source': 'With an admonitory gesture to keep them back, he stooped, and looked in through the crevice in the wall.', 'answer': 'through the crevice in the wall'}
{'question': 'Who has lived so long that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces come to?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': 'Monsieur'}
{'question': 'Who brings to him you bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Was the gunmaker's stock murderous?", 'source': "Nothing was represented in a flourishing condition, save tools and weapons; but, the cutler's knives and axes were sharp and bright, the smith's hammers were heavy, and the gunmaker's stock was murderous.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did she answer ``am afraid of it''?", 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who stopped for the third time?', 'source': 'At last, the top of the staircase was gained, and they stopped for the third time.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did it lie on the stones just outside?', 'source': 'The accident had happened in getting it out of a cart; the cask had tumbled out with a run, the hoops had burst, and it lay on the stones just outside the door of the wine-shop, shattered like a walnut-shell.', 'answer': 'just outside the door of the wine-shop'}
{'question': 'Had all the people within reach suspended their business, or their idleness, to run to the spot?', 'source': 'All the people within reach had suspended their business, or their idleness, to run to the spot and drink the wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the joker rap it with?', 'source': 'The joker rapped it with his own, took a nimble spring upward, and came down in a fantastic dancing attitude, with one of his stained shoes jerked off his foot into his hand, and held out.', 'answer': 'with his own'}
{'question': 'Had all the people within reach suspended their business, or their idleness, to drink the wine?', 'source': 'All the people within reach had suspended their business, or their idleness, to run to the spot and drink the wine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were the smith's hammers heavy?", 'source': "Nothing was represented in a flourishing condition, save tools and weapons; but, the cutler's knives and axes were sharp and bright, the smith's hammers were heavy, and the gunmaker's stock was murderous.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the people from the market do?', 'source': '``The people from the market did it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did these three show themselves to be the three of?', 'source': 'On hearing footsteps close at hand, these three turned, and rose, and showed themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop.', 'answer': 'of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop'}
{'question': 'Who became absorbed in it?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was the staircase short?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the joker hold out?', 'source': 'The joker rapped it with his own, took a nimble spring upward, and came down in a fantastic dancing attitude, with one of his stained shoes jerked off his foot into his hand, and held out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was hurried her into the room?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'his shoulder'}
{'question': 'Who help him!', 'source': "God help him, who should be with him!''", 'answer': 'God'}
{'question': 'Is so much the worse! that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had he become?', 'source': 'He had no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left, but had become a secret, angry, dangerous man.', 'answer': 'a secret dangerous man'}
{'question': 'What did he strike twice or thrice upon?', 'source': 'Soon raising his head again, he struck twice or thrice upon the door-- evidently with no other object than to make a noise there.', 'answer': 'upon the door'}
{'question': 'Is wine wine;?', 'source': "``Call wine, wine; and finish there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What's well?", 'source': "That's well, friend Defarge.", 'answer': 'that'}
{'question': 'What did these three show themselves to be?', 'source': 'On hearing footsteps close at hand, these three turned, and rose, and showed themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop.', 'answer': 'the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop'}
{'question': 'Who did they rest upon?', 'source': 'The wine-shop keeper accordingly rolled his eyes about, until they rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady, who were seated in a corner.', 'answer': 'upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady'}
{'question': 'What had it stained?', 'source': 'It had stained many hands, too, and many faces, and many naked feet, and many wooden shoes.', 'answer': 'many hands'}
{'question': 'What is so much the worse! that such poor cattle always have in?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': 'in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques'}
{'question': 'What did he draw over the arm that shook upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'over his neck'}
{'question': 'What did he look into?', 'source': 'The door slowly opened inward under his hand, and he looked into the room and said something.', 'answer': 'into the room'}
{'question': 'What combined made it almost insupportable?', 'source': 'The uncontrollable and hopeless mass of decomposition so engendered, would have polluted the air, even if poverty and deprivation had not loaded it with their intangible impurities; the two bad sources combined made it almost insupportable.', 'answer': 'the two bad sources'}
{'question': 'What were they at?', 'source': 'Indeed they were at sea, and the ship and crew were in peril of tempest.', 'answer': 'at sea'}
{'question': 'What had her husband kept upon her?', 'source': "``Gentlemen,'' said her husband, who had kept his bright eye observantly upon her, ``good day.", 'answer': 'his bright eye observantly'}
{'question': 'Who had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who were at sea?', 'source': 'Indeed they were at sea, and the ship and crew were in peril of tempest.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "What did she answer ``I am afraid of''?", 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'What was its abiding place in fitted to it?', 'source': 'Its abiding place was in all things fitted to it.', 'answer': 'in all things'}
{'question': 'Did the other find God?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who put it clumsily into the lock?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who do you bring to him you bring to?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Who feigned not to notice the two strangers?', 'source': 'But, he feigned not to notice the two strangers, and fell into discourse with the triumvirate of customers who were drinking at the counter.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who do you bring to him bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'When had it not lasted?', 'source': 'It had not lasted a minute, when he nodded and went out.', 'answer': 'a minute'}
{'question': 'Did a shrill sound of laughter and of amused voices resound in the street while this wine game lasted?', 'source': 'A shrill sound of laughter and of amused voices-- voices of men, women, and children-- resounded in the street while this wine game lasted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge sit in the shop behind the counter as he came in?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge, his wife, sat in the shop behind the counter as he came in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you bring to you bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What did they begin ascending?', 'source': 'Thus, Monsieur Defarge, in a stern voice, to Mr. Lorry, as they began ascending the stairs.', 'answer': 'the stairs'}
{'question': 'Is a very remarkable transformation a little difficult?', 'source': '``It is very high; it is a little difficult.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a little begin ascending the stairs?', 'source': 'Thus, Monsieur Defarge, in a stern voice, to Mr. Lorry, as they began ascending the stairs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is all the relief all the happiness?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who began ascending the stairs?', 'source': 'Thus, Monsieur Defarge, in a stern voice, to Mr. Lorry, as they began ascending the stairs.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who was rendered in a manner desperate?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who paid for their wine?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who was he altogether?', 'source': 'He was a dark man altogether, with good eyes and a good bold breadth between them.', 'answer': 'a dark man'}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge raise her eyebrows by the breadth of another line?', 'source': 'When this interchange of Christian name was effected, Madame Defarge, picking her teeth with her toothpick, coughed another grain of cough, and raised her eyebrows by the breadth of another line.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she take up?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': 'her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit'}
{'question': 'Was the time prevalent everywhere?', 'source': 'It was prevalent everywhere.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did her face express?', 'source': 'But, by this time she trembled under such strong emotion, and her face expressed such deep anxiety, and, above all, such dread and terror, that Mr. Lorry felt it incumbent on him to speak a word or two of reassurance.', 'answer': 'such deep anxiety'}
{'question': 'What had she laid it down to pick her teeth with?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'with a toothpick'}
{'question': 'What were they soon at?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': 'at the top'}
{'question': 'What missed its mark?', 'source': 'It missed its mark, and completely failed, as is often the way with his tribe too.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Monsieur has lived so long that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces come to?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are you English; that is?', 'source': 'Enough; you are English; that is another thing.', 'answer': 'another thing'}
{'question': 'Did the kennel run?', 'source': 'The kennel, to make amends, ran down the middle of the street-- when it ran at all: which was only after heavy rains, and then it ran, by many eccentric fits, into the houses.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the eyes of Monsieur Defarge studying his wife at her knitting when the elderly gentleman advanced from his corner?', 'source': 'The eyes of Monsieur Defarge were studying his wife at her knitting when the elderly gentleman advanced from his corner, and begged the favor of a word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they leave?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'the place'}
{'question': 'Was the other opened?', 'source': 'To exclude the cold, one half of this door was fast closed, and the other was opened but a very little way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What paid for their wine?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Would such a staircase be bad enough now?', 'source': 'Such a staircase, with its accessories, in the older and more crowded parts of Paris, would be bad enough now; but, at that time, it was vile indeed to unaccustomed and unhardened senses.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do _ you _?', 'source': "``What the devil do _ you _ do in that galley there?''", 'answer': 'the devil'}
{'question': 'What is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': 'so much the worse!'}
{'question': 'Who was her knitting before?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'before her'}
{'question': 'What did she acknowledge by giving them a quick look?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': 'their homage'}
{'question': 'Who did he feign not to notice?', 'source': 'But, he feigned not to notice the two strangers, and fell into discourse with the triumvirate of customers who were drinking at the counter.', 'answer': 'the two strangers'}
{'question': 'Was the time to come?', 'source': 'The time was to come, when that wine too would be spilled on the street-stones, and when the stain of it would be red upon many there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are of my name?', 'source': '``I choose them as real men, of my name-- Jacques is my name-- to whom the sight is likely to do good.', 'answer': 'real men'}
{'question': 'Who smacked his lips?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was the garret story reached?', 'source': 'There was yet an upper staircase, of a steeper inclination and of contracted dimensions, to be ascended, before the garret story was reached.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a hot temperament a bitter day?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Madame Defarge a stout woman of about his own age?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge was a stout woman of about his own age, with a watchful eye that seldom seemed to look at anything, a large hand heavily ringed, a steady face, strong features, and great composure of manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he put clumsily into the lock?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who put down his empty drinking vessel?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he pass behind?', 'source': "As he passed behind the counter, he took notice that the elderly gentleman said in a look to the young lady, ``This is our man.''", 'answer': 'behind the counter'}
{'question': 'What did he say?', 'source': 'The door slowly opened inward under his hand, and he looked into the room and said something.', 'answer': 'something'}
{'question': 'What did she become absorbed in?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': 'in it'}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It opened from a stinking little black courtyard, and was the general public entrance to a great pile of houses, inhabited by a great number of people.', 'answer': 'the general public entrance to a great pile of houses'}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge say nothing when her lord came in, but coughed just one grain of cough?', 'source': 'Thus engaged, with her right elbow supported by her left hand, Madame Defarge said nothing when her lord came in, but coughed just one grain of cough.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What should he have been of?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': 'of a hot temperament'}
{'question': 'What did she acknowledge by bending her head?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': 'their homage'}
{'question': 'Who wound about her head again?', 'source': 'The hands of the man who sawed the wood, left red marks on the billets; and the forehead of the woman who nursed her baby, was stained with the stain of the old rag she wound about her head again.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who were soon at the top?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who do say, then do?', 'source': "``Say, then, my Gaspard, what do you do there?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he call to him across?', 'source': 'There, his eyes happening to catch the tall joker writing up his joke, he called to him across the way:', 'answer': 'across the way'}
{'question': 'Who did he beckon to enter?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Was the key across the same intention three or four times?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were men women, and children?', 'source': 'A shrill sound of laughter and of amused voices-- voices of men, women, and children-- resounded in the street while this wine game lasted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who was ``good day''?", 'source': "``Gentlemen,'' said her husband, who had kept his bright eye observantly upon her, ``good day.", 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What did he carry slung over his shoulder?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': 'one'}
{'question': 'What is my Gaspard?', 'source': "``Say, then, my Gaspard, what do you do there?''", 'answer': 'say, then'}
{'question': 'Is the worst over?', 'source': 'The worst will be over in a moment; it is but passing the room-door, and the worst is over.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was lifted her a little, ?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'his shoulder'}
{'question': 'What now said his say?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': 'the last of the three'}
{'question': 'What was his shoulder hurried her into?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'into the room'}
{'question': 'What did he beckon to enter?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What was he rendered in?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'in a manner desperate'}
{'question': 'Who left the place?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What was it gently done?', 'source': 'It was a gentle action, but not at all gently done; a very remarkable transformation had come over him in a few seconds.', 'answer': 'a gentle action'}
{'question': 'What was before her?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'her knitting'}
{'question': 'What did he walk across?', 'source': 'Finally, he walked across the room with a measured tread to where the window was.', 'answer': 'across the room with a measured tread to where the window was'}
{'question': 'How many times was the key across it?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'three or four times'}
{'question': 'What were that soon at?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': 'at the top'}
{'question': 'Who felt that she was sinking?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry got his arm securely round the daughter's waist, and held her; for he felt that she was sinking.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Was the response of Monsieur Defarge ``You are right''?", 'source': "``You are right, Jacques,'' was the response of Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had not lasted a minute?', 'source': 'It had not lasted a minute, when he nodded and went out.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What left the place?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had she laid down to pick her teeth with a toothpick?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was the wine gone?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge still use her toothpick with profound composure?', 'source': 'At this second interchange of the Christian name, Madame Defarge, still using her toothpick with profound composure, coughed another grain of cough, and raised her eyebrows by the breadth of another line.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they pay for?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': 'for their wine'}
{'question': 'What did he sit her down just within?', 'source': 'He sat her down just within the door, and held her, clinging to him.', 'answer': 'just within the door'}
{'question': 'Who did he hold?', 'source': 'He sat her down just within the door, and held her, clinging to him.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What had she laid it down to pick with a toothpick?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': 'her teeth'}
{'question': 'What did he face?', 'source': 'He stopped there, and faced round.', 'answer': 'round'}
{'question': 'What did he draw?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'the key across it'}
{'question': 'What did it miss?', 'source': 'It missed its mark, and completely failed, as is often the way with his tribe too.', 'answer': 'its mark'}
{'question': 'Did the three go silently down?', 'source': 'The three glided by, and went silently down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who means of him?', 'source': '``I mean of him.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who knows not what harm-- if his door was left open?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he look back over?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': 'over his shoulder'}
{'question': 'Was each of these stoppages made at a doleful grating?', 'source': 'Each of these stoppages was made at a doleful grating, by which any languishing good airs that were left uncorrupted, seemed to escape, and all spoilt and sickly vapors seemed to crawl in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who faced round?', 'source': 'He stopped there, and faced round.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he wear?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': 'no coat'}
{'question': 'Were the wine-shops croaked over their scanty measures of thin wine and beer?', 'source': 'The people rudely pictured as drinking in the wine-shops, croaked over their scanty measures of thin wine and beer, and were gloweringly confidential together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the time not come yet?', 'source': 'But, the time was not come yet; and every wind that blew over France shook the rags of the scarecrows in vain, for the birds, fine of song and feather, took no warning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Monsieur Defarge return ``It is so''?", 'source': "``It is so, Jacques,'' Monsieur Defarge returned.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she wind about again?', 'source': 'The hands of the man who sawed the wood, left red marks on the billets; and the forehead of the woman who nursed her baby, was stained with the stain of the old rag she wound about her head again.', 'answer': 'about her head'}
{'question': 'What had this dialogue been held in?', 'source': "This dialogue had been held in so very low a whisper, that not a word of it had reached the young lady's ears.", 'answer': 'in so very low a whisper'}
{'question': 'Who did he have?', 'source': 'He had no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left, but had become a secret, angry, dangerous man.', 'answer': 'no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left'}
{'question': 'Is a very remarkable transformation very high?', 'source': '``It is very high; it is a little difficult.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you?', 'source': "``Say, then, my Gaspard, what do you do there?''", 'answer': 'say, then'}
{'question': 'Were the places where it had been most abundant raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I mean of?', 'source': '``I mean of him.', 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'Did he wipe then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop with that advice?', 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do _ I _ think is well?', 'source': "'' _ I _ think it is well.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he put it clumsily into?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'into the lock'}
{'question': "Did Monsieur Defarge explain, ``I forgot them in the surprise of your visit''?", 'source': "``I forgot them in the surprise of your visit,'' explained Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did his young companion's agitation become greater every instant?", 'source': "Yielding to his own disturbance of mind, and to his young companion's agitation, which became greater every instant, Mr. Jarvis Lorry twice stopped to rest.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it open from a stinking little black courtyard?', 'source': 'It opened from a stinking little black courtyard, and was the general public entrance to a great pile of houses, inhabited by a great number of people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she glance in a casual manner round the wine-shop?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was God?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is Jacques?', 'source': "``How goes it, Jacques?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry hold her?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry got his arm securely round the daughter's waist, and held her; for he felt that she was sinking.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he smack?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': 'his lips'}
{'question': 'Was it spilled at Paris?', 'source': 'The wine was red wine, and had stained the ground of the narrow street in the suburb of Saint Antoine, in Paris, where it was spilled.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it the general public entrance to a great pile of houses?', 'source': 'It opened from a stinking little black courtyard, and was the general public entrance to a great pile of houses, inhabited by a great number of people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is God now?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are you English;?', 'source': 'Enough; you are English; that is another thing.', 'answer': 'that is another thing'}
{'question': 'What was her?', 'source': "``Gentlemen,'' said her husband, who had kept his bright eye observantly upon her, ``good day.", 'answer': "``good day''"}
{'question': "Did he drop his cleaner hand upon the joker's heart in his expostulation?", 'source': "In his expostulation he dropped his cleaner hand (perhaps accidentally, perhaps not) upon the joker's heart.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was prevalent everywhere?', 'source': 'It was prevalent everywhere.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did he walk across the room with a measured tread to where the window was?', 'source': 'Finally, he walked across the room with a measured tread to where the window was.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he raise again?', 'source': 'Soon raising his head again, he struck twice or thrice upon the door-- evidently with no other object than to make a noise there.', 'answer': 'his head'}
{'question': 'Were his brown arms bare to the elbows?', 'source': 'His shirt-sleeves were rolled up, too, and his brown arms were bare to the elbows.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the worst?', 'source': 'The worst will be over in a moment; it is but passing the room-door, and the worst is over.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who shuddered?', 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did he put down?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': 'his empty drinking vessel'}
{'question': 'Was God then?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was such a scanty portion of light admitted through these means?', 'source': 'Such a scanty portion of light was admitted through these means, that it was difficult, on first coming in, to see anything; and long habit alone could have slowly formed in any one, the ability to do any work requiring nicety in such obscurity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the key across it?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'three or four times'}
{'question': 'Who did they find?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge pick her teeth with her toothpick?', 'source': 'When this interchange of Christian name was effected, Madame Defarge, picking her teeth with her toothpick, coughed another grain of cough, and raised her eyebrows by the breadth of another line.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he wipe his soiled hand upon the joker's dress with that advice?", 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was this wine-shop keeper a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Jarvis Lorry and Miss Manette join Monsieur Defarge in the doorway to which he had directed his own company just before?', 'source': 'Mr. Jarvis Lorry and Miss Manette, emerging from the wine-shop thus, joined Monsieur Defarge in the doorway to which he had directed his own company just before.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he fall into discourse with the triumvirate of customers who were drinking at the counter?', 'source': 'But, he feigned not to notice the two strangers, and fell into discourse with the triumvirate of customers who were drinking at the counter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it vile indeed to unaccustomed and unhardened senses at that time?', 'source': 'Such a staircase, with its accessories, in the older and more crowded parts of Paris, would be bad enough now; but, at that time, it was vile indeed to unaccustomed and unhardened senses.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who turned it as heavily as he could?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was the inscription written in every small loaf of his scanty stock of bad bread?', 'source': "Hunger was the inscription on the baker's shelves, written in every small loaf of his scanty stock of bad bread; at the sausage-shop, in every dead-dog preparation that was offered for sale.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look in through the crevice in the wall?', 'source': 'With an admonitory gesture to keep them back, he stooped, and looked in through the crevice in the wall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked?', 'source': 'A joker of an extremely, not to say wolfishly practical character, he looked, under those circumstances.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'When was it?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': 'a bitter day'}
{'question': 'Had her husband kept his bright eye observantly upon her?', 'source': "``Gentlemen,'' said her husband, who had kept his bright eye observantly upon her, ``good day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the staircase vile indeed to unaccustomed and unhardened senses at that time?', 'source': 'Such a staircase, with its accessories, in the older and more crowded parts of Paris, would be bad enough now; but, at that time, it was vile indeed to unaccustomed and unhardened senses.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'all the relief'}
{'question': 'Was Madame Defarge his wife?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge, his wife, sat in the shop behind the counter as he came in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he draw over his neck?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': 'the arm that shook upon his shoulder'}
{'question': 'Was this third interchange of the Christian name completed at the moment when Madame Defarge put her toothpick by, kept her eyebrows up, and slightly rustled in her seat?', 'source': 'This third interchange of the Christian name was completed at the moment when Madame Defarge put her toothpick by, kept her eyebrows up, and slightly rustled in her seat.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these three show themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop?', 'source': 'On hearing footsteps close at hand, these three turned, and rose, and showed themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the pavement with their many little reservoirs of mud and water?', 'source': 'The crippling stones of the pavement, with their many little reservoirs of mud and water, had no footways, but broke off abruptly at the doors.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What see you!', 'source': 'And a beautiful world we live in, when it _ is _ possible, and when many other such things are possible, and not only possible, but done-- done, see you!', 'answer': 'a beautiful world we live in'}
{'question': 'Who is it?', 'source': "``How goes it, Jacques?''", 'answer': 'Jacques'}
{'question': "Did Monsieur Defarge to himself say, ``I do not know you''?", 'source': "said Monsieur Defarge to himself; ``I do not know you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who found me?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did he wipe with that advice?', 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': 'then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop'}
{'question': 'Do God help him!', 'source': "God help him, who should be with him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had a very remarkable transformation come over him in a few seconds?', 'source': 'It was a gentle action, but not at all gently done; a very remarkable transformation had come over him in a few seconds.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Monsieur defarge whispered it closer in his ear?', 'source': 'Monsieur Defarge whispered it closer in his ear, and frowned heavily.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she acknowledge their homage by giving them a quick look?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the door slowly open inward under his hand?', 'source': 'The door slowly opened inward under his hand, and he looked into the room and said something.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Monsieur put her hand to his lips?', 'source': 'In the gloomy tile-paved entry to the gloomy tile-paved staircase, Monsieur Defarge bent down on one knee to the child of his old master, and put her hand to his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What found me?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What _ think it is well?', 'source': "'' _ I _ think it is well.''", 'answer': '_ I'}
{'question': 'Did they rest upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady?', 'source': 'The wine-shop keeper accordingly rolled his eyes about, until they rested upon an elderly gentleman and a young lady, who were seated in a corner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she take up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he turn as heavily as he could?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Had bent over their shoulders all women run out between their fingers?', 'source': 'Some men kneeled down, made scoops of their two hands joined, and sipped, or tried to help women, who bent over their shoulders, to sip, before the wine had all run out between their fingers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you bring to him you bring to him?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who went out?', 'source': 'The gentleman then beckoned to the young lady, and they, too, went out.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who had broken out?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Should he have been of a hot temperament?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they stop for the third time?', 'source': 'At last, the top of the staircase was gained, and they stopped for the third time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it stained many hands?', 'source': 'It had stained many hands, too, and many faces, and many naked feet, and many wooden shoes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the door locked it on the inside?', 'source': 'Defarge drew out the key, closed the door, locked it on the inside, took out the key again, and held it in his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it that such poor cattle always have in?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': 'in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques'}
{'question': 'Had this dialogue been held in so very low a whisper?', 'source': "This dialogue had been held in so very low a whisper, that not a word of it had reached the young lady's ears.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What went out?', 'source': 'The gentleman then beckoned to the young lady, and they, too, went out.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Are you English; that is another thing?', 'source': 'Enough; you are English; that is another thing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he become a secret dangerous man?', 'source': 'He had no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left, but had become a secret, angry, dangerous man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did?', 'source': 'All this he did, methodically, and with as loud and harsh an accompaniment of noise as he could make.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Had the accident happened in getting it out of a cart?', 'source': 'The accident had happened in getting it out of a cart; the cask had tumbled out with a run, the hoops had burst, and it lay on the stones just outside the door of the wine-shop, shattered like a walnut-shell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did she answer ``I am afraid of it''?", 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her face express such deep anxiety?', 'source': 'But, by this time she trembled under such strong emotion, and her face expressed such deep anxiety, and, above all, such dread and terror, that Mr. Lorry felt it incumbent on him to speak a word or two of reassurance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he feel?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry got his arm securely round the daughter's waist, and held her; for he felt that she was sinking.", 'answer': 'that she was sinking'}
{'question': 'Was this interchange of Christian name effected?', 'source': 'When this interchange of Christian name was effected, Madame Defarge, picking her teeth with her toothpick, coughed another grain of cough, and raised her eyebrows by the breadth of another line.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What completely failed?', 'source': 'It missed its mark, and completely failed, as is often the way with his tribe too.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was one half of this door fast closed?', 'source': 'To exclude the cold, one half of this door was fast closed, and the other was opened but a very little way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he strike twice or thrice upon the door?', 'source': 'Soon raising his head again, he struck twice or thrice upon the door-- evidently with no other object than to make a noise there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What he has lived so long that he would be frightened--?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': 'rave-- tear himself to pieces come to'}
{'question': 'Had she laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they at sea?', 'source': 'Indeed they were at sea, and the ship and crew were in peril of tempest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he draw over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they begin ascending the stairs?', 'source': 'Thus, Monsieur Defarge, in a stern voice, to Mr. Lorry, as they began ascending the stairs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the two bad sources combine made it almost insupportable?', 'source': 'The uncontrollable and hopeless mass of decomposition so engendered, would have polluted the air, even if poverty and deprivation had not loaded it with their intangible impurities; the two bad sources combined made it almost insupportable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look into the room?', 'source': 'The door slowly opened inward under his hand, and he looked into the room and said something.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Defarge hold it in his hand?', 'source': 'Defarge drew out the key, closed the door, locked it on the inside, took out the key again, and held it in his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the second of the three address Monsieur Defarge, ``that many of these miserable beasts know the taste of wine, or of anything but black bread and death''?", 'source': "``It is not often,'' said the second of the three, addressing Monsieur Defarge, ``that many of these miserable beasts know the taste of wine, or of anything but black bread and death.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left?', 'source': 'He had no good-humour in his face, nor any openness of aspect left, but had become a secret, angry, dangerous man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it lie on the stones just outside the door of the wine-shop?', 'source': 'The accident had happened in getting it out of a cart; the cask had tumbled out with a run, the hoops had burst, and it lay on the stones just outside the door of the wine-shop, shattered like a walnut-shell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these demonstrations cease?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do a beautiful world we live in see you!', 'source': 'And a beautiful world we live in, when it _ is _ possible, and when many other such things are possible, and not only possible, but done-- done, see you!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can one of you show the way?', 'source': 'But, now that I remember, one of you has already been there, and can show the way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she acknowledge their homage by bending her head?', 'source': 'She acknowledged their homage by bending her head, and giving them a quick look.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he feign not to notice the two strangers?', 'source': 'But, he feigned not to notice the two strangers, and fell into discourse with the triumvirate of customers who were drinking at the counter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were left alone?', 'source': 'There appearing to be no other door on that floor, and the keeper of the wine-shop going straight to this one when they were left alone, Mr. Lorry asked him in a whisper, with a little anger:', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did the joker rap it with his own?', 'source': 'The joker rapped it with his own, took a nimble spring upward, and came down in a fantastic dancing attitude, with one of his stained shoes jerked off his foot into his hand, and held out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were left alone?', 'source': 'There appearing to be no other door on that floor, and the keeper of the wine-shop going straight to this one when they were left alone, Mr. Lorry asked him in a whisper, with a little anger:', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was he a dark man altogether?', 'source': 'He was a dark man altogether, with good eyes and a good bold breadth between them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the last of the three now say his say?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his shirt-sleeves rolled up?', 'source': 'His shirt-sleeves were rolled up, too, and his brown arms were bare to the elbows.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he rendered in a manner desperate?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they leave the place?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say something?', 'source': 'The door slowly opened inward under his hand, and he looked into the room and said something.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who could make?', 'source': 'All this he did, methodically, and with as loud and harsh an accompaniment of noise as he could make.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who went up slowly and softly?', 'source': 'They went up slowly and softly.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he pass behind the counter?', 'source': "As he passed behind the counter, he took notice that the elderly gentleman said in a look to the young lady, ``This is our man.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they soon at the top?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a gentle action gently done?', 'source': 'It was a gentle action, but not at all gently done; a very remarkable transformation had come over him in a few seconds.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What Monsieur has lived so long?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': 'that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces come to'}
{'question': 'Had it not lasted a minute?', 'source': 'It had not lasted a minute, when he nodded and went out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Monsieur bring to him to?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'you bring to him'}
{'question': 'Who came in?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge, his wife, sat in the shop behind the counter as he came in.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who stopped there?', 'source': 'He stopped there, and faced round.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'He has lived so long that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces come to?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was her ``good day''?", 'source': "``Gentlemen,'' said her husband, who had kept his bright eye observantly upon her, ``good day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do say, then do you?', 'source': "``Say, then, my Gaspard, what do you do there?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it prevalent everywhere?', 'source': 'It was prevalent everywhere.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he face round?', 'source': 'He stopped there, and faced round.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these three rise?', 'source': 'On hearing footsteps close at hand, these three turned, and rose, and showed themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he call to him across the way?', 'source': 'There, his eyes happening to catch the tall joker writing up his joke, he called to him across the way:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was its abiding place in all things fitted to it?', 'source': 'Its abiding place was in all things fitted to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these three turn?', 'source': 'On hearing footsteps close at hand, these three turned, and rose, and showed themselves to be the three of one name who had been drinking in the wine-shop.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were that soon at the top?', 'source': 'The staircase was short, and they were soon at the top.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are real men of my name?', 'source': '``I choose them as real men, of my name-- Jacques is my name-- to whom the sight is likely to do good.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is so much the worse! in?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': 'that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques'}
{'question': 'Is say, then my Gaspard?', 'source': "``Say, then, my Gaspard, what do you do there?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did their conference very decide?', 'source': 'Their conference was very short, but very decided.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his shoulder hurried her into the room?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he wear no coat?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit her down just within the door?', 'source': 'He sat her down just within the door, and held her, clinging to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the devil do _ you _?', 'source': "``What the devil do _ you _ do in that galley there?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they go out?', 'source': 'The gentleman then beckoned to the young lady, and they, too, went out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she become absorbed in it?', 'source': 'Then she glanced in a casual manner round the wine-shop, took up her knitting with great apparent calmness and repose of spirit, and became absorbed in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do _ I _ think?', 'source': "'' _ I _ think it is well.''", 'answer': 'it is well'}
{'question': 'Did he draw the key across it?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he beckon them to enter?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was their conference very short?', 'source': 'Their conference was very short, but very decided.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stoop?', 'source': 'With an admonitory gesture to keep them back, he stooped, and looked in through the crevice in the wall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it a little difficult?', 'source': '``It is very high; it is a little difficult.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this wine game last?', 'source': 'A shrill sound of laughter and of amused voices-- voices of men, women, and children-- resounded in the street while this wine game lasted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he put down his empty drinking vessel?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is him all the relief?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they pay for their wine?', 'source': 'They paid for their wine, and left the place.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has one of you already been there?', 'source': 'But, now that I remember, one of you has already been there, and can show the way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her knitting before her?', 'source': 'Her knitting was before her, but she had laid it down to pick her teeth with a toothpick.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it completely fail?', 'source': 'It missed its mark, and completely failed, as is often the way with his tribe too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he carry one slung over his shoulder?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it miss its mark?', 'source': 'It missed its mark, and completely failed, as is often the way with his tribe too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look back over his shoulder?', 'source': 'He looked back over his shoulder, and beckoned them to enter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a bitter day?', 'source': 'This wine-shop keeper was a bull-necked, martial-looking man of thirty, and he should have been of a hot temperament, for, although it was a bitter day, he wore no coat, but carried one slung over his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she shudder?', 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the key across it three or four times?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was?', 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did he look?', 'source': 'A joker of an extremely, not to say wolfishly practical character, he looked, under those circumstances.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he urge?', 'source': 'he urged, with a moisture that was not of business shining on his cheek.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he put it clumsily into the lock?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his shoulder lifted her a little, ?', 'source': 'Rendered in a manner desperate, by her state and by the beckoning of their conductor, he drew over his neck the arm that shook upon his shoulder, lifted her a little, and hurried her into the room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had these demonstrations broken out?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hold her?', 'source': 'He sat her down just within the door, and held her, clinging to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they broken out?', 'source': 'When the wine was gone, and the places where it had been most abundant were raked into a gridiron-pattern by fingers, these demonstrations ceased, as suddenly as they had broken out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she wind about her head again?', 'source': 'The hands of the man who sawed the wood, left red marks on the billets; and the forehead of the woman who nursed her baby, was stained with the stain of the old rag she wound about her head again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he smack his lips?', 'source': 'The last of the three now said his say, as he put down his empty drinking vessel and smacked his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he feel that she was sinking?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry got his arm securely round the daughter's waist, and held her; for he felt that she was sinking.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What he has lived so long?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': 'that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces come to'}
{'question': 'Do _ I _ think it is well?', 'source': "'' _ I _ think it is well.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did she answer ``of''?", 'source': "``I am afraid of it,'' she answered, shuddering.", 'answer': 'I am afraid of it'}
{'question': 'Is it Jacques?', 'source': "``How goes it, Jacques?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he do?', 'source': 'All this he did, methodically, and with as loud and harsh an accompaniment of noise as he could make.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he come in?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge, his wife, sat in the shop behind the counter as he came in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it very high?', 'source': '``It is very high; it is a little difficult.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I mean of him?', 'source': '``I mean of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he raise his head again?', 'source': 'Soon raising his head again, he struck twice or thrice upon the door-- evidently with no other object than to make a noise there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it run?', 'source': 'The kennel, to make amends, ran down the middle of the street-- when it ran at all: which was only after heavy rains, and then it ran, by many eccentric fits, into the houses.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know not what harm-- if his door was left open?', 'source': "Because he has lived so long, locked up, that he would be frightened-- rave-- tear himself to pieces-- die-- come to I know not what harm-- if his door was left open.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stop there?', 'source': 'He stopped there, and faced round.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he and his two companions ascend higher and higher?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's spirits grew heavier and heavier, as he and his two companions ascended higher and higher.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they left alone?', 'source': 'There appearing to be no other door on that floor, and the keeper of the wine-shop going straight to this one when they were left alone, Mr. Lorry asked him in a whisper, with a little anger:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you bring to him to?', 'source': 'Then, all the good you bring to him, all the relief, all the happiness you bring to him, begin.', 'answer': 'you bring to him'}
{'question': 'Did they go up slowly and softly?', 'source': 'They went up slowly and softly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he make?', 'source': 'All this he did, methodically, and with as loud and harsh an accompaniment of noise as he could make.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they find me?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn it as heavily as he could?', 'source': 'With the same intention, he drew the key across it, three or four times, before he put it clumsily into the lock, and turned it as heavily as he could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's well?", 'source': "That's well, friend Defarge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it?', 'source': 'The worst will be over in a moment; it is but passing the room-door, and the worst is over.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that go up slowly and softly?', 'source': 'They went up slowly and softly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he now?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it?', 'source': "With that advice, he wiped his soiled hand upon the joker's dress, such as it was-- quite deliberately, as having dirtied the hand on his account; and then recrossed the road and entered the wine-shop.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he then?', 'source': "As he was, when I first saw him after they found me and demanded to know if I would take him, and, at my peril be discreet-- as he was then, so he is now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it in?', 'source': 'A bitter taste it is that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques.', 'answer': 'that such poor cattle always have in their mouths, and hard lives they live, Jacques'}
{'question': 'Who wish you had never taken that cold in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher'}
{'question': 'What do you stir from till I come back!', 'source': 'Now, Ladybird, never you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'answer': 'from that fire'}
{'question': 'What was upon her?', 'source': 'And yet his wife trembled, and a vague but heavy fear was upon her.', 'answer': 'a vague but heavy fear'}
{'question': 'Who must hold up our heads?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Cruncher see me again?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do the first ``ask no more''?", 'source': "``Citizen Doctor,'' said the first, with his former reluctance, ``ask no more.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the lower voice after a pause?', 'source': 'He looked abstractedly from one to another, and said, in a lower voice, after a pause:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will this citizen be happy to make the Republic demands without?', 'source': 'If the Republic demands sacrifices from you, without doubt you as a good patriot will be happy to make them.', 'answer': 'without doubt'}
{'question': 'Did Charles open the two?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he cross the two intervening?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': 'outer rooms'}
{'question': 'Who always made a bargain for it?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did her mind look for him among?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': 'among the Condemned'}
{'question': 'What did they leave Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': 'by a bright fire'}
{'question': 'Was the latter the basket?', 'source': 'For some months past, Miss Pross and Mr. Cruncher had discharged the office of purveyors; the former carrying the money; the latter, the basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who left Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Do Nice have but one?', 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did the Doctor answer ``I think you may take''?", 'source': "``I think you may take that liberty,'' the Doctor answered, smiling.", 'answer': 'that liberty'}
{'question': 'What did she always make a bargain for?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': 'Are the Republic demands pressed?', 'source': "Evremonde, we are pressed.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What startles you!', 'source': 'The least thing-- nothing-- startles you!', 'answer': 'the least thing'}
{'question': 'Who fared forth on this duty?', 'source': 'Every afternoon at about the time when the public lamps were lighted, they fared forth on this duty, and made and brought home such purchases as were needful.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What left Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Cruncher fear not yet?', 'source': '``I fear not yet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose golden hair did she glance at in the light of the fire?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, cheerfully repressing a sigh as she glanced at her darling's golden hair in the light of the fire, ``then we must have patience and wait: that's all.", 'answer': "at her darling's golden hair"}
{'question': 'Do the public lamps want wine?', 'source': 'We want wine, among the rest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did I see you?', 'source': 'I know you, Evremonde; I saw you before the Tribunal to-day.', 'answer': 'before the Tribunal to-day'}
{'question': 'What did they fare forth on?', 'source': 'Every afternoon at about the time when the public lamps were lighted, they fared forth on this duty, and made and brought home such purchases as were needful.', 'answer': 'on this duty'}
{'question': "What did she glance at her darling's golden hair in?", 'source': "said Miss Pross, cheerfully repressing a sigh as she glanced at her darling's golden hair in the light of the fire, ``then we must have patience and wait: that's all.", 'answer': 'in the light of the fire'}
{'question': 'What did he take the lamp in?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': 'in his hand'}
{'question': 'Is the People supreme?', 'source': 'The People is supreme.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will be happy to make them without doubt?', 'source': 'If the Republic demands sacrifices from you, without doubt you as a good patriot will be happy to make them.', 'answer': 'you as a good patriot'}
{'question': 'Who does the least thing startle!', 'source': 'The least thing-- nothing-- startles you!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who is summoned for to-morrow?', 'source': "You are summoned for to-morrow.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What was it not another of in which he had often come back?', 'source': 'It was not another of the dreams in which he had often come back; he was really here.', 'answer': 'of the dreams'}
{'question': 'Who are you again?', 'source': "You are again the prisoner of the Republic.''", 'answer': 'the prisoner of the Republic'}
{'question': 'Who do Mr. Cruncher see again?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What went out?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': '-- Do not'}
{'question': 'Did the citizen here indicate added:?', 'source': 'The citizen here indicated nodded his head, and added:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she glance at in the light of the fire?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, cheerfully repressing a sigh as she glanced at her darling's golden hair in the light of the fire, ``then we must have patience and wait: that's all.", 'answer': "at her darling's golden hair"}
{'question': 'Did-- Do not go out?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is wine among the rest?', 'source': 'We want wine, among the rest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When are you summoned?', 'source': "You are summoned for to-morrow.''", 'answer': 'for to-morrow'}
{'question': "What does it's?", 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': 'Midnight Murder, and Mischief'}
{'question': 'What was it not in which he had often come back?', 'source': 'It was not another of the dreams in which he had often come back; he was really here.', 'answer': 'another of the dreams'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say ``Mr. Cruncher am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you''?", 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he denounced by the Citizen and Citizeness Defarge?', 'source': 'But he is denounced-- and gravely-- by the Citizen and Citizeness Defarge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What must we hold up?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': 'our heads'}
{'question': 'Was all subdued?', 'source': 'All was subdued and quiet, and Lucie was more at ease than she had been.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he take in his hand?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': 'the lamp'}
{'question': 'Is the first against rule?', 'source': 'Truly it is against rule.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did her father cheer?', 'source': "Her father, cheering her, showed a compassionate superiority to this woman's weakness, which was wonderful to see.", 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What surrounded him?', 'source': 'The four surrounded him, where he stood with his wife and child clinging to him.', 'answer': 'the four'}
{'question': 'All was quiet?', 'source': 'All was subdued and quiet, and Lucie was more at ease than she had been.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did her mind pursue?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': "What did the Doctor answer ``I think''?", 'source': "``I think you may take that liberty,'' the Doctor answered, smiling.", 'answer': 'you may take that liberty'}
{'question': 'Was Lucie more at ease than she had been?', 'source': 'All was subdued and quiet, and Lucie was more at ease than she had been.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Then will the Doctor be answered to-morrow?', 'source': "``Then,'' said he of Saint Antoine, with a strange look, ``you will be answered to-morrow.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who wishes you had never taken that cold in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What had he accomplished the task he had set himself?', 'source': 'He had accomplished the task he had set himself, his promise was redeemed, he had saved Charles.', 'answer': 'he had saved Charles'}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Cruncher stir from that fire till I come back!', 'source': 'Now, Ladybird, never you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is my love?', 'source': "``My love, the staircase is as still as Death.''", 'answer': 'the staircase'}
{'question': 'What did her mind pursue?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Had Miss Pross put it aside in a corner undisturbed?', 'source': 'Miss Pross had lighted the lamp, but had put it aside in a corner, that they might enjoy the fire-light undisturbed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do they drink?', 'source': "``It will be much the same to your knowledge, miss, I should think,'' retorted Jerry, ``whether they drink your health or the Old Un's.''", 'answer': "your health or the Old Un 's"}
{'question': 'What do I wish you had never taken in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'that cold'}
{'question': 'What did she always make for it?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': 'a bargain'}
{'question': 'Who cheered her?', 'source': "Her father, cheering her, showed a compassionate superiority to this woman's weakness, which was wonderful to see.", 'answer': 'her father'}
{'question': 'Who must fight low?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What do we want?', 'source': 'We want wine, among the rest.', 'answer': 'wine'}
{'question': 'What did he say?', 'source': 'As he said the word, a blow was struck upon the door.', 'answer': 'the word'}
{'question': 'What will you as a good patriot be happy to make them without?', 'source': 'If the Republic demands sacrifices from you, without doubt you as a good patriot will be happy to make them.', 'answer': 'without doubt'}
{'question': 'Does Nice toast these Redheads will be drinking?', 'source': "Nice toasts these Redheads will be drinking, wherever we buy it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do they have?', 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': 'but one'}
{'question': 'Who do I know?', 'source': 'I know you, Evremonde; I saw you before the Tribunal to-day.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What is it against?', 'source': 'Truly it is against rule.', 'answer': 'against rule'}
{'question': 'Who do I wish had never taken that cold in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What pursued them?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': 'her mind'}
{'question': 'Who said the word?', 'source': 'As he said the word, a blow was struck upon the door.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they leave by a bright fire?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': 'Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child,'}
{'question': 'Who opened it?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Will this citizen be happy to make the Republic demands without doubt?', 'source': 'If the Republic demands sacrifices from you, without doubt you as a good patriot will be happy to make them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he open?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who have but one?', 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who knows you?', 'source': 'I know you, Evremonde; I saw you before the Tribunal to-day.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do I seek?', 'source': '``I seek him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who want wine?', 'source': 'We want wine, among the rest.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say, ``if you are ready, I am'', ``if you are ready, I am''?", 'source': "``Now, Mr. Cruncher,'' said Miss Pross, whose eyes were red with felicity; ``if you are ready, I am.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say, ``Nice have quite enough of that''?", 'source': "``For gracious sake, do not talk about Liberty; we have quite enough of that,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do we seek?', 'source': 'We seek him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What had he worn off long ago?', 'source': 'He had worn all his rust off long ago, but nothing would file his spiky head down.', 'answer': 'all his rust'}
{'question': "Did her father show a compassionate superiority to this woman's weakness?", 'source': "Her father, cheering her, showed a compassionate superiority to this woman's weakness, which was wonderful to see.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Doctor answer ``Mr. Cruncher think you may take that liberty''?", 'source': "``I think you may take that liberty,'' the Doctor answered, smiling.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say, ``we have quite enough of that''?", 'source': "``For gracious sake, do not talk about Liberty; we have quite enough of that,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Then when will you be answered?', 'source': "``Then,'' said he of Saint Antoine, with a strange look, ``you will be answered to-morrow.", 'answer': 'to-morrow'}
{'question': 'Who seeks him?', 'source': '``I seek him.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I wish you had never taken that cold in?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'in your voice'}
{'question': 'Who sees me again?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did they bring home such purchases as were needful?', 'source': 'Every afternoon at about the time when the public lamps were lighted, they fared forth on this duty, and made and brought home such purchases as were needful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Doctor turn his eyes upon that man?', 'source': 'The Doctor turned his eyes upon that man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who seek him?', 'source': 'We seek him.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Who _es!', 'source': "_ You _, your father's daughter!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Does it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief?", 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a vague but heavy fear upon her?', 'source': 'And yet his wife trembled, and a vague but heavy fear was upon her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the first answer, ``It is against rule''?", 'source': "``It is against rule,'' answered the first; ``but you can ask Him of Saint Antoine here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might his number be?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': 'its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up'}
{'question': 'Who has it now?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Are you again the prisoner of the Republic?', 'source': "You are again the prisoner of the Republic.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you see again?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Would it be dangerous for Charles yet?', 'source': "It would be dangerous for Charles yet.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I see you before the Tribunal to-day?', 'source': 'I know you, Evremonde; I saw you before the Tribunal to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he cross the two intervening outer rooms?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the Doctor answer ?', 'source': "``I think you may take that liberty,'' the Doctor answered, smiling.", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher think you may take that liberty'}
{'question': 'Did the public lamps fare forth on this duty?', 'source': 'Every afternoon at about the time when the public lamps were lighted, they fared forth on this duty, and made and brought home such purchases as were needful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would nothing file his spiky head down?', 'source': 'He had worn all his rust off long ago, but nothing would file his spiky head down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who went out?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who cried?', 'source': 'she cried, all at once.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did my brother Solomon use to say?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he accomplished the task he had set himself he had saved Charles?', 'source': 'He had accomplished the task he had set himself, his promise was redeemed, he had saved Charles.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the least thing startle you!', 'source': 'The least thing-- nothing-- startles you!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you have now?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who was really here?', 'source': 'It was not another of the dreams in which he had often come back; he was really here.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did he look abstractedly from one to another:?', 'source': 'He looked abstractedly from one to another, and said, in a lower voice, after a pause:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say ``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you''?", 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you as a good patriot be happy to make them without doubt?', 'source': 'If the Republic demands sacrifices from you, without doubt you as a good patriot will be happy to make them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they fare forth on this duty?', 'source': 'Every afternoon at about the time when the public lamps were lighted, they fared forth on this duty, and made and brought home such purchases as were needful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is dumb!', 'source': "Now, I am dumb!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'source': 'Now, Ladybird, never you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are pressed?', 'source': "Evremonde, we are pressed.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What do Mr. Cruncher wish in?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'you had never taken that cold in your voice'}
{'question': 'Did her mind look for him among the Condemned?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must we fight low?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who fears not yet?', 'source': '``I fear not yet.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Are you summoned for to-morrow?', 'source': "You are summoned for to-morrow.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might his number its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up be?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his wife tremble?', 'source': 'And yet his wife trembled, and a vague but heavy fear was upon her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Cruncher wish you had never taken that cold in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who goes?', 'source': "May I ask a question, Doctor Manette, before I go?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who comes back?', 'source': 'Now, Ladybird, never you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Did the Doctor answer ``I think you may take that liberty''?", 'source': "``I think you may take that liberty,'' the Doctor answered, smiling.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do they drink your health or the Old Un's?", 'source': "``It will be much the same to your knowledge, miss, I should think,'' retorted Jerry, ``whether they drink your health or the Old Un's.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take the lamp in his hand?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they leave Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the four surround him?', 'source': 'The four surrounded him, where he stood with his wife and child clinging to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my love the staircase?', 'source': "``My love, the staircase is as still as Death.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is in!', 'source': 'What a disordered state you are in!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Must we hold up our heads?', 'source': 'We must hold up our heads and fight low, as my brother Solomon used to say.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do we want wine?', 'source': 'We want wine, among the rest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they go out?', 'source': 'They went out, leaving Lucie, and her husband, her father, and the child, by a bright fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she always make a bargain for it?', 'source': 'She always made a bargain for it, by holding up, as a statement of its just price, one finger less than the merchant held up, whatever his number might be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not another of the dreams in which he had often come back?', 'source': 'It was not another of the dreams in which he had often come back; he was really here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did Miss Pross say ``in''?", 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'Mr. Cruncher am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you'}
{'question': 'Is it against rule?', 'source': 'Truly it is against rule.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say the word?', 'source': 'As he said the word, a blow was struck upon the door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do they have but one?', 'source': "They have but one, and it's Midnight Murder, and Mischief.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say:?', 'source': 'He looked abstractedly from one to another, and said, in a lower voice, after a pause:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did she glance at her darling's golden hair in the light of the fire?", 'source': "said Miss Pross, cheerfully repressing a sigh as she glanced at her darling's golden hair in the light of the fire, ``then we must have patience and wait: that's all.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her mind pursue them?', 'source': 'Her mind pursued them, looking for him among the Condemned; and then she clung closer to his real presence and trembled more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her father cheer her?', 'source': "Her father, cheering her, showed a compassionate superiority to this woman's weakness, which was wonderful to see.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he accomplished the task?', 'source': 'He had accomplished the task he had set himself, his promise was redeemed, he had saved Charles.', 'answer': 'he had set himself he had saved Charles'}
{'question': 'Had he worn all his rust off long ago?', 'source': 'He had worn all his rust off long ago, but nothing would file his spiky head down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I dumb!', 'source': "Now, I am dumb!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you _!', 'source': "_ You _, your father's daughter!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Then will you be answered to-morrow?', 'source': "``Then,'' said he of Saint Antoine, with a strange look, ``you will be answered to-morrow.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he open it?', 'source': 'He took the lamp in his hand, crossed the two intervening outer rooms, and opened it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know you?', 'source': 'I know you, Evremonde; I saw you before the Tribunal to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I come back?', 'source': 'Now, Ladybird, never you stir from that fire till I come back!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she cry?', 'source': 'she cried, all at once.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he really here?', 'source': 'It was not another of the dreams in which he had often come back; he was really here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I seek him?', 'source': '``I seek him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I wish in?', 'source': "``I am glad you have so much of the Englishman in you, though I wish you had never taken that cold in your voice,'' said Miss Pross, approvingly.", 'answer': 'you had never taken that cold in your voice'}
{'question': 'Do we seek him?', 'source': 'We seek him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we pressed?', 'source': "Evremonde, we are pressed.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I fear not yet?', 'source': '``I fear not yet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I go?', 'source': "May I ask a question, Doctor Manette, before I go?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you in!', 'source': 'What a disordered state you are in!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you see me again?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you have it now?', 'source': 'Take care of the dear husband you have recovered, and do not move your pretty head from his shoulder as you have it now, till you see me again!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a man say the last words into his usual manner?', 'source': 'Though he said the last words, with a slip into his usual manner, there was a true feeling and respect both in his tone and in his touch, that Mr. Lorry, who had never seen the better side of him, was wholly unprepared for.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What poured cheerfully out as he passed?', 'source': 'But, the theaters were all well filled, and the people poured cheerfully out as he passed, and went chatting home.', 'answer': 'the people'}
{'question': 'Who was strongly reminded of that expression?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'What was a long, grieving sound sob?', 'source': 'It was a long, grieving sound, like a sigh-- almost like a sob.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the stream carry there on to the sea?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If a man should prowl about the streets a long time who; shall reappear in the morning?', 'source': 'If I should prowl about the streets a long time, do not be uneasy; I shall reappear in the morning.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who does it seem to be?', 'source': 'It seems to be one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way.', 'answer': 'one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way'}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients and how can a honest tradesman rightly have one without t ` other?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he put them in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': 'for them'}
{'question': 'Who did he put in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What looked along them?', 'source': 'And looking along them, with reverently shaded eyes, a bridge of light appeared to span the air between him and the sun, while the river sparkled under it.', 'answer': 'a bridge of light'}
{'question': 'Who did not quite mean what I said?', 'source': "I did not quite mean what I said.''", 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'Was good night citizen?', 'source': "``Good night, citizen,'' said Sydney Carton, pausing in going by; for, the man eyed him inquisitively.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What am I glad of?', 'source': '``I am glad of that.', 'answer': 'of that'}
{'question': 'Was every eye turned to the jury?', 'source': 'Every eye was turned to the jury.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do a man know my vagabond and restless habits?', 'source': 'You know my vagabond and restless habits.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When had he heard of her going to the prison?', 'source': 'He had heard of her going to the prison every day.', 'answer': 'every day'}
{'question': 'Had last night been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he put them in, counted out the money for them?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': 'in the breast of his inner coat'}
{'question': 'Did the chemist say?', 'source': 'Sydney Carton took no heed, and the chemist said:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'President, do Ernest Defarge indignantly protest to you that this is a forgery and a fraud?', 'source': '``President, I indignantly protest to you that this is a forgery and a fraud.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What hailed this rebuke?', 'source': 'Loud acclamations hailed this rebuke.', 'answer': 'loud acclamations'}
{'question': 'Who is free from that misfortune?', 'source': "You are free from that misfortune, however.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he put them in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': 'for them'}
{'question': 'Did last night put certain small packets in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who serves my gun that day?', 'source': 'As I serve my gun that day, I resolve, when the place shall fall, to examine that cell.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry ask him?', 'source': 'When they were alone, Mr. Lorry asked him what he had done?', 'answer': 'what he had done'}
{'question': 'What carried it on to the sea?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'the stream'}
{'question': 'What did he put in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did a man not quite mean what I said?', 'source': "I did not quite mean what I said.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was loosed from his neck?', 'source': 'He carried the child over, and before the timid arm was loosed from his neck asked her for a kiss.', 'answer': 'the timid arm'}
{'question': 'Did a man return the look?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who 'll walk with you to her gate?", 'source': "``I 'll walk with you to her gate.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who mounts to the cell?', 'source': 'I mount to the cell, with a fellow-citizen who is one of the Jury, directed by a gaoler.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he lay the scrap of paper before him?', 'source': 'Giving this citizen, too, good night, as he confronted him at his counter, he laid the scrap of paper before him.', 'answer': 'giving this citizen'}
{'question': "Did it attract Mr. Lorry's eyes to Carton's face?", 'source': "It attracted Mr. Lorry's eyes to Carton's face, which was turned to the fire.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the end sir?', 'source': "``And your duties here have drawn to an end, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who can put my hand out?', 'source': 'I can put my hand out, to do any little helpful work for her that my hand can find to do, without that.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'Was the Republic one of a race?', 'source': 'Suspected and Denounced enemy of the Republic, Aristocrat, one of a family of tyrants, one of a race proscribed, for that they had used their abolished privileges to the infamous oppression of the people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What sparkled under it?', 'source': 'And looking along them, with reverently shaded eyes, a bridge of light appeared to span the air between him and the sun, while the river sparkled under it.', 'answer': 'the river'}
{'question': 'What had he been famous among his earliest competitors as?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': 'as a youth of great promise'}
{'question': 'What was it sob?', 'source': 'It was a long, grieving sound, like a sigh-- almost like a sob.', 'answer': 'a long, grieving sound'}
{'question': 'Who did a man get, would never prosper with?', 'source': 'And wot little a man did get, would never prosper with him, Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'with him'}
{'question': 'What was floated by him?', 'source': 'A trading-boat, with a sail of the softened color of a dead leaf, then glided into his view, floated by him, and died away.', 'answer': 'his view'}
{'question': 'Do a man have my Leave to Pass?', 'source': 'I have my Leave to Pass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I mount to?', 'source': 'I mount to the cell, with a fellow-citizen who is one of the Jury, directed by a gaoler.', 'answer': 'to the cell'}
{'question': 'Who had he followed to the grave?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': 'his father'}
{'question': 'Who sat beside her father?', 'source': 'She was there, sitting beside her father.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What had closed his shop?', 'source': 'A little wood-sawyer, having closed his shop, was smoking his pipe at his shop-door.', 'answer': 'a little wood-sawyer'}
{'question': 'Who was his view floated by?', 'source': 'A trading-boat, with a sail of the softened color of a dead leaf, then glided into his view, floated by him, and died away.', 'answer': 'by him'}
{'question': "Could a man not respect weep's sorrow more?", 'source': 'And I could not respect your sorrow more, if you were my father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself?', 'source': '``If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, you would have no duty but to sacrifice her.', 'answer': 'the Republic'}
{'question': 'Did a man evidently understand there?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who call the World?', 'source': ", and by many associations of the days when what we call the World was not so real with me, and my faults were not confirmed in me.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'If it should go ill with the prisoner, who has ensured access to him?', 'source': "If it should go ill with the prisoner, I have ensured access to him, once.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did A fall?', 'source': 'A fell, uncompromising, murderous business-meaning there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who walked by the stream?', 'source': 'He walked by the stream, far from the houses, and in the light and warmth of the sun fell asleep on the bank.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What shall mount to a hundred soon?', 'source': 'We shall mount to a hundred soon.', 'answer': 'unhappily'}
{'question': 'What did I hope to have left them in?', 'source': 'I hoped to have left them in perfect safety, and then to have quitted Paris.', 'answer': 'in perfect safety'}
{'question': 'Who has such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you?', 'source': 'She has such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did Carton gently press?', 'source': 'He gave him his hand, and Carton gently pressed it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What was his boot still upon?', 'source': 'His indifference to fire was sufficiently remarkable to elicit a word of remonstrance from Mr. Lorry; his boot was still upon the hot embers of the flaming log, when it had broken under the weight of his foot.', 'answer': 'upon the hot embers of the flaming log'}
{'question': 'Who did his daughter draw closer to?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette sat down, with his eyes looking around, and his lips trembling; his daughter drew closer to him.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What did he lay the scrap of before him giving this citizen?', 'source': 'Giving this citizen, too, good night, as he confronted him at his counter, he laid the scrap of paper before him.', 'answer': 'of paper'}
{'question': 'What are you free from?', 'source': "You are free from that misfortune, however.''", 'answer': 'from that misfortune'}
{'question': 'Who has at length done all that I can do here?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who may I say that I was when a boy?', 'source': "Indeed, I may say that I was a man of business when a boy.''", 'answer': 'a man of business'}
{'question': "Who said, ``It is all I could do''?", 'source': "``It is all I could do,'' said Carton.", 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'Who left him there?', 'source': 'Carton left him there; but lingered at a little distance, and turned back to the gate again when it was shut, and touched it.', 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients what and how can without?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': 'a honest tradesman rightly have one without t ` other'}
{'question': 'Do the President examine a man?', 'source': 'I examine it, very closely.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do his fingers perpetually hovering about?', 'source': 'Eager and prominent among them, one man with a craving face, and his fingers perpetually hovering about his lips, whose appearance gave great satisfaction to the spectators.', 'answer': 'about his lips'}
{'question': 'Have a man at length done all that I can do here?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who said to you when I first came?', 'source': 'As I said to you when I first came, I had better not see her.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'What may I say that I was a man of when a boy?', 'source': "Indeed, I may say that I was a man of business when a boy.''", 'answer': 'of business'}
{'question': 'Who did he carry over?', 'source': 'He carried the child over, and before the timid arm was loosed from his neck asked her for a kiss.', 'answer': 'the child'}
{'question': 'Do Ha ha!', 'source': 'Ha, ha, ha!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would any of them only add to?', 'source': "``She might think a thousand things,'' Carton said, ``and any of them would only add to her trouble.", 'answer': 'to her trouble'}
{'question': 'Who will find a place for me?', 'source': 'My Spy will find a place for me.', 'answer': "a man's Spy"}
{'question': 'Can a man put my hand out?', 'source': 'I can put my hand out, to do any little helpful work for her that my hand can find to do, without that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is glad of that?', 'source': '``I am glad of that.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he walk by?', 'source': 'He walked by the stream, far from the houses, and in the light and warmth of the sun fell asleep on the bank.', 'answer': 'by the stream'}
{'question': "What 'd he never have no good of?", 'source': "He 'd never have no good of it; he 'd want all along to be out of the line, if he, could see his way out, being once in-- even if it wos so.''", 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': "What doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch 'em at!", 'source': "Whereas them medical doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch 'em at it!", 'answer': 'at it'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; a man's sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken them?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who thinks they would be?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who might think it was contrived?', 'source': "She might think it was contrived, in case of the worse, to convey to him the means of anticipating the sentence.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What was this short examination quick with?', 'source': 'This short examination followed, for the court was quick with its work.', 'answer': 'with its work'}
{'question': "Who 'll I walk with to her gate?", 'source': "``I 'll walk with you to her gate.", 'answer': 'with you'}
{'question': "Who 'd want all along to be out of the line being once in-- even if it wos so?", 'source': "He 'd never have no good of it; he 'd want all along to be out of the line, if he, could see his way out, being once in-- even if it wos so.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'If I should prowl about the streets a long time when shall; I reappear?', 'source': 'If I should prowl about the streets a long time, do not be uneasy; I shall reappear in the morning.', 'answer': 'in the morning'}
{'question': 'Who will my Spy find a place for?', 'source': 'My Spy will find a place for me.', 'answer': 'for me'}
{'question': 'Who do you know the accused to be?', 'source': 'You know the accused to be the husband of my daughter.', 'answer': 'the husband of my daughter'}
{'question': 'What did the stream carry on to the sea?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What was my young way never?', 'source': '``I am not old, but my young way was never the way to age.', 'answer': 'the way to age'}
{'question': "What doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch at it!", 'source': "Whereas them medical doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch 'em at it!", 'answer': "'em"}
{'question': "Did the glorious sun seem to strike those words to there's heart in its long bright rays?", 'source': 'But, the glorious sun, rising, seemed to strike those words, that burden of the night, straight and warm to his heart in its long bright rays.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he return?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': 'the look'}
{'question': 'Who are far dearer to me than my life?', 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': "Ernest Defarge's daughter, and those dear to her,"}
{'question': 'Who did a man say to when I first came?', 'source': 'As I said to you when I first came, I had better not see her.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Who gave him his hand?', 'source': 'He gave him his hand, and Carton gently pressed it.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'Were the last words with a slip?', 'source': 'Though he said the last words, with a slip into his usual manner, there was a true feeling and respect both in his tone and in his touch, that Mr. Lorry, who had never seen the better side of him, was wholly unprepared for.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who are Ernest Defarge's daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to than my life?", 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': 'to me'}
{'question': 'Did all hang loose about a man?', 'source': 'He wore the white riding-coat and top-boots, then in vogue, and the light of the fire touching their light surfaces made him look very pale, with his long brown hair, all untrimmed, hanging loose about him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have a man been a man?', 'source': '``I have been a man of business, ever since I have been a man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does Three voice?', 'source': '``Three voices.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When do you go?', 'source': "You go to the Court to-morrow?''", 'answer': 'to the Court to-morrow'}
{'question': 'Who carried the child over?', 'source': 'He carried the child over, and before the timid arm was loosed from his neck asked her for a kiss.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch 'em at it!", 'source': "Whereas them medical doctors ' wives do not flop-- catch 'em at it!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What hung loose about him?', 'source': 'He wore the white riding-coat and top-boots, then in vogue, and the light of the fire touching their light surfaces made him look very pale, with his long brown hair, all untrimmed, hanging loose about him.', 'answer': 'all'}
{'question': "Did a few minutes bring them to Mr. Lorry's destination?", 'source': "A few minutes brought them to Mr. Lorry's destination.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she sit beside?', 'source': 'She was there, sitting beside her father.', 'answer': 'beside her father'}
{'question': 'Did the stream absorb there?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients what how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': 'and'}
{'question': 'When had he followed his father?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': 'to the grave'}
{'question': 'What was it obviously?', 'source': 'It was obviously the weakness of the position.', 'answer': 'the weakness of the position'}
{'question': 'What was he strongly reminded of?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': 'of that expression'}
{'question': 'Were frantic acclamations again raised?', 'source': 'Frantic acclamations were again raised.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``I forgot it''?", 'source': "``I forgot it,'' he said.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Who will a man's Spy find a place for?", 'source': 'My Spy will find a place for me.', 'answer': 'for me'}
{'question': 'Shall a man be there?', 'source': '``I shall be there, but only as one of the crowd.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who evidently understood it?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients what and how can you rightly have one without?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': 'without t ` other'}
{'question': 'Who knows my vagabond and restless habits?', 'source': 'You know my vagabond and restless habits.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Has a stone been replaced?', 'source': 'In a hole in the chimney, where a stone has been worked out and replaced, I find a written paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he say the last words into?', 'source': 'Though he said the last words, with a slip into his usual manner, there was a true feeling and respect both in his tone and in his touch, that Mr. Lorry, who had never seen the better side of him, was wholly unprepared for.', 'answer': 'into his usual manner'}
{'question': 'Do a man speak the truth!', 'source': "Patriots, I speak the truth!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has seen him at work?', 'source': "You have seen him at work?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'If it should go ill with the prisoner, what have I ensured?', 'source': "If it should go ill with the prisoner, I have ensured access to him, once.''", 'answer': 'access to him'}
{'question': 'Have the President made this my business to examine some specimens of the writing of Doctor Manette?', 'source': 'I have made it my business to examine some specimens of the writing of Doctor Manette.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said ``She came out here''?", 'source': "``She came out here,'' he said, looking about him, ``turned this way, must have trod on these stones often.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Would a man not get much by all?', 'source': 'Then, wot with undertakers, and wot with parish clerks, and wot with sextons, and wot with private watchmen (all awaricious and all in it), a man would not get much by it, even if it wos so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who must be very desolate to-night?', 'source': "She must be very desolate to-night.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Had she stood hundreds of times at La Force?', 'source': "It was ten o'clock at night when he stood before the prison of La Force, where she had stood hundreds of times.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was him?', 'source': 'And wot little a man did get, would never prosper with him, Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, what would you have?', 'source': '``If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, you would have no duty but to sacrifice her.', 'answer': 'no duty but to sacrifice her'}
{'question': "Is a man's heart touched now! )", 'source': 'My heart is touched now, by many remembrances that had long fallen asleep, of my pretty young mother (and I so old! )', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is Tellson to be?', 'source': "And which it is to be took into account that if it wos, it would not, even then, be all o ' one side.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who lingered there yet a little longer?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What do we call?', 'source': ", and by many associations of the days when what we call the World was not so real with me, and my faults were not confirmed in me.''", 'answer': 'the World'}
{'question': 'Were the streets quiet?', 'source': 'Now, that the streets were quiet, and the night wore on, the words were in the echoes of his feet, and were in the air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would only add to her trouble?', 'source': "``She might think a thousand things,'' Carton said, ``and any of them would only add to her trouble.", 'answer': 'any of them'}
{'question': "What are Ernest Defarge's daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to me than?", 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': 'than my life'}
{'question': 'Was a man an old man now?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who have I been?', 'source': '``I have been a man of business, ever since I have been a man.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'What may be that I shall yet stand your friend, and repent in action?', 'source': 'It may be that I shall yet stand your friend, if you deserve it, and repent in action-- not in words.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients what and how can you rightly have without t ` other?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': 'one'}
{'question': 'Has a stone been worked out?', 'source': 'In a hole in the chimney, where a stone has been worked out and replaced, I find a written paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he sometimes repeat them to as he walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': 'Shall unhappily mount to a hundred soon?', 'source': 'We shall mount to a hundred soon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he say into his usual manner?', 'source': 'Though he said the last words, with a slip into his usual manner, there was a true feeling and respect both in his tone and in his touch, that Mr. Lorry, who had never seen the better side of him, was wholly unprepared for.', 'answer': 'the last words'}
{'question': 'Was Doctor Manette seen in the midst of it?', 'source': 'A great uproar took place in the court, and in the midst of it, Doctor Manette was seen, pale and trembling, standing where he had been seated.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did a man's tears fall?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could a man not sit by?', 'source': 'I could not see my father weep, and sit by, careless.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he know himself by no other name than One Hundred and Five, North Tower, when he made shoes under my care?', 'source': 'He knew himself by no other name than One Hundred and Five, North Tower, when he made shoes under my care.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who means the Guillotine?', 'source': '``You mean the Guillotine.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Is Ha ha?', 'source': 'Ha, ha, ha!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it easy to surmise where the good old man was gone?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry was already out when he got back, and it was easy to surmise where the good old man was gone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest,"}
{'question': 'Did the night wear on?', 'source': 'Now, that the streets were quiet, and the night wore on, the words were in the echoes of his feet, and were in the air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might she think was contrived?', 'source': "She might think it was contrived, in case of the worse, to convey to him the means of anticipating the sentence.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who heard them always?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did all untrimmed?', 'source': 'He wore the white riding-coat and top-boots, then in vogue, and the light of the fire touching their light surfaces made him look very pale, with his long brown hair, all untrimmed, hanging loose about him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did every eye then gleam at approvingly?', 'source': 'Every eye then sought some other eye in the crowd, and gleamed at it approvingly; and heads nodded at one another, before bending forward with a strained attention.', 'answer': 'at it'}
{'question': 'Am a man not old?', 'source': '``I am not old, but my young way was never the way to age.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were both silent?', 'source': 'They were both silent.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did he sometimes repeat to himself as he walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who has my Leave to Pass?', 'source': 'I have my Leave to Pass.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do a man want no more words?', 'source': "I want no more words.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did not seek it?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Who did he say ``came out here''?", 'source': "``She came out here,'' he said, looking about him, ``turned this way, must have trod on these stones often.", 'answer': 'She'}
{'question': 'Who did he repeat?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who do I think would be?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who would not get much by it?', 'source': 'Then, wot with undertakers, and wot with parish clerks, and wot with sextons, and wot with private watchmen (all awaricious and all in it), a man would not get much by it, even if it wos so.', 'answer': 'a man'}
{'question': 'Who repeated them?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who hopes you are going to her?', 'source': 'You are going to her, I hope?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who have you seen at work?', 'source': "You have seen him at work?''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What were both silent?', 'source': 'They were both silent.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Do a man say truly?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I hope are going to her?', 'source': 'You are going to her, I hope?', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who speaks the truth!', 'source': "Patriots, I speak the truth!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do I hope you are going to?', 'source': 'You are going to her, I hope?', 'answer': 'to her'}
{'question': 'What did he repeat?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he sometimes repeat to himself as he walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What do I think would be?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What is this that written?', 'source': 'This is that written paper.', 'answer': 'paper'}
{'question': 'Who has been a man?', 'source': '``I have been a man of business, ever since I have been a man.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Had last night's mother died?", 'source': 'His mother had died, years before.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his indifference to fire sufficiently remarkable to elicit a word of remonstrance from Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'His indifference to fire was sufficiently remarkable to elicit a word of remonstrance from Mr. Lorry; his boot was still upon the hot embers of the flaming log, when it had broken under the weight of his foot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it The Vengeance who, amidst the warm commendations of the audience?', 'source': 'It was The Vengeance who, amidst the warm commendations of the audience, thus assisted the proceedings.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was it?', 'source': 'It was The Vengeance who, amidst the warm commendations of the audience, thus assisted the proceedings.', 'answer': 'The Vengeance who, amidst the warm commendations of the audience'}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was the settled manner of a tired man, who had wandered and struggled and got lost, but who at length struck into his road and saw its end.', 'answer': 'the settled manner of a tired man'}
{'question': 'What do I speak!', 'source': "Patriots, I speak the truth!''", 'answer': 'the truth'}
{'question': "Was it ten o'clock at night when he stood before the prison of La Force?", 'source': "It was ten o'clock at night when he stood before the prison of La Force, where she had stood hundreds of times.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you mean?', 'source': '``You mean the Guillotine.', 'answer': 'the Guillotine'}
{'question': "What 'll I walk with you to?", 'source': "``I 'll walk with you to her gate.", 'answer': 'to her gate'}
{'question': 'Who was he now?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': 'an old man'}
{'question': 'Was a man ready to go?', 'source': "I was ready to go.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who could not respect your sorrow more?', 'source': 'And I could not respect your sorrow more, if you were my father.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did a man give him his hand?', 'source': 'He gave him his hand, and Carton gently pressed it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is a man's arm sir?", 'source': "Take my arm, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were Mr. Lorry's eyes again attracted to his face?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes were again attracted to his face.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he evidently understand?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who did I say to when I first came?', 'source': 'As I said to you when I first came, I had better not see her.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'What have I at done all that I can do here?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': 'at length'}
{'question': "Did an excited woman screech from the crowd: ``You were one of the best patriots there''?", 'source': 'Here, an excited woman screeched from the crowd: ``You were one of the best patriots there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a man say to you when I first came?', 'source': 'As I said to you when I first came, I had better not see her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do a man have Leave to Pass?', 'source': 'I have my Leave to Pass.', 'answer': 'my'}
{'question': 'President, what do I indignantly protest to you?', 'source': '``President, I indignantly protest to you that this is a forgery and a fraud.', 'answer': 'that this is a forgery and a fraud'}
{'question': 'Who wants no more words?', 'source': "I want no more words.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was he having the expression of?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': "of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind"}
{'question': 'Who is my arm?', 'source': "Take my arm, sir.''", 'answer': 'sir'}
{'question': 'Whose faces fresh in his mind was he having the expression of?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': "of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind"}
{'question': 'Can last night not sleep?', 'source': "I cannot sleep.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does a man fall?', 'source': 'It falls.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would your seventy-eight years be seventy-eight heavy curses?', 'source': "your seventy-eight years would be seventy-eight heavy curses; would they not?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will my Spy find for me?', 'source': 'My Spy will find a place for me.', 'answer': 'a place'}
{'question': "Did Carton say, ``You are a good man and a true friend''?", 'source': "``You are a good man and a true friend,'' said Carton, in an altered voice.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he not seek?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What would not enable Her to go to see him?', 'source': 'It would not enable Her to go to see him.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who went down the dark streets?', 'source': "These solemn words, which had been read at his father's grave, arose in his mind as he went down the dark streets, among the heavy shadows, with the moon and the clouds sailing on high above him.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What absorbed it?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'the stream'}
{'question': "What 'd he never have?", 'source': "He 'd never have no good of it; he 'd want all along to be out of the line, if he, could see his way out, being once in-- even if it wos so.''", 'answer': 'no good of it'}
{'question': 'Who did he hear always?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who are my daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to than my life?', 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': 'to me'}
{'question': 'When must she be?', 'source': "She must be very desolate to-night.''", 'answer': 'very desolate to-night'}
{'question': "Did his lips's appearance give great satisfaction to the spectators?", 'source': 'Eager and prominent among them, one man with a craving face, and his fingers perpetually hovering about his lips, whose appearance gave great satisfaction to the spectators.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What am I?', 'source': '``I am glad of that.', 'answer': 'glad of that'}
{'question': 'Who knew it from himself?', 'source': 'I knew it from himself.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "What said, ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me'', ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me''?", 'source': "``Adieu, Mr. Barsad,'' said the former; ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me.''", 'answer': 'the former'}
{'question': 'What did he hear always?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What do I have Leave to Pass?', 'source': 'I have my Leave to Pass.', 'answer': 'my'}
{'question': "Who did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did the Public prosecutor to this effect in as few or fewer words?', 'source': 'To this effect, in as few or fewer words, the Public Prosecutor.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would it not enable to go to see him?', 'source': 'It would not enable Her to go to see him.', 'answer': 'Her'}
{'question': 'Did not ill.?', 'source': 'Not ill. .', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would it not enable Her to go to see?', 'source': 'It would not enable Her to go to see him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What can I put out?', 'source': 'I can put my hand out, to do any little helpful work for her that my hand can find to do, without that.', 'answer': 'my hand'}
{'question': 'What did the stream absorb?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was the cogitation accompanied with an intent look at his patron?', 'source': "After some cogitation, accompanied with an intent look at his patron, Mr. Cruncher conceived the luminous idea of replying, ``Agicultooral character.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have you seen him at?', 'source': "You have seen him at work?''", 'answer': 'at work'}
{'question': 'Were the former alone?', 'source': 'When they were alone, Mr. Lorry asked him what he had done?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you among the first to enter the accursed fortress when it fell?', 'source': 'You were a cannonier that day there, and you were among the first to enter the accursed fortress when it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can you not sarse?', 'source': 'For you cannot sarse the goose and not the gander.', 'answer': 'the goose and not the gander'}
{'question': "Did it seem as if Creation were delivered over to Death's dominion?", 'source': "Then, the night, with the moon and the stars, turned pale and died, and for a little while it seemed as if Creation were delivered over to Death's dominion.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did Sydney turn his eyes again upon the fire:?', 'source': 'Sydney turned his eyes again upon the fire, and, after a silence of a few moments, said:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a trading-boat then glide into his view?', 'source': 'A trading-boat, with a sail of the softened color of a dead leaf, then glided into his view, floated by him, and died away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life?', 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': "Ernest Defarge's daughter, and those dear to her,"}
{'question': 'Have I made it my business to examine some specimens of the writing of Doctor Manette?', 'source': 'I have made it my business to examine some specimens of the writing of Doctor Manette.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did last night lay the scrap of paper before him giving this citizen?', 'source': 'Giving this citizen, too, good night, as he confronted him at his counter, he laid the scrap of paper before him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will miss you when you leave it?', 'source': "How many people will miss you when you leave it empty!''", 'answer': 'many people'}
{'question': 'What was he having?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': "the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind"}
{'question': "Who did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; a man's sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'If there had been any eyes to notice the influence, would it have been seen to be the same influence exactly?', 'source': 'If there had been any eyes to notice the influence of her look, on Sydney Carton, it would have been seen to be the same influence exactly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he watch?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'an eddy that turned and turned purposeless'}
{'question': 'Did the grinning little man hold out the pipe he was smoking?', 'source': 'As the grinning little man held out the pipe he was smoking, to explain how he timed the executioner, Carton was so sensible of a rising desire to strike the life out of him, that he turned away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are my daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to me than?', 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': 'than my life'}
{'question': 'President, do I indignantly protest to you that this is a forgery and a fraud?', 'source': '``President, I indignantly protest to you that this is a forgery and a fraud.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were they?', 'source': 'They were both silent.', 'answer': 'both silent'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; a man's sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What do I examine?', 'source': 'I examine it, very closely.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who examines it?', 'source': 'I examine it, very closely.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Had the solemn words been read at his father's grave?", 'source': "These solemn words, which had been read at his father's grave, arose in his mind as he went down the dark streets, among the heavy shadows, with the moon and the clouds sailing on high above him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit down in a chair on the hearth?', 'source': 'He sat down in a chair on the hearth, over against Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a solitary old bachelor shake his head?', 'source': "``A solitary old bachelor,'' answered Mr. Lorry, shaking his head.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you know?', 'source': 'You know my vagabond and restless habits.', 'answer': 'my vagabond and restless habits'}
{'question': 'Was him Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'And wot little a man did get, would never prosper with him, Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did I know it from?', 'source': 'I knew it from himself.', 'answer': 'from himself'}
{'question': 'Did he shave the sixty-three to-day!', 'source': 'Figure this to yourself, citizen; he shaved the sixty-three to-day, in less than two pipes!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he know himself by?', 'source': 'He knew himself by no other name than One Hundred and Five, North Tower, when he made shoes under my care.', 'answer': 'by no other name than One Hundred and Five, North Tower, when he made shoes under my care'}
{'question': 'Did they go down-stairs and out in the streets?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry did so, and they went down-stairs and out in the streets.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I hope to have quitted Paris?', 'source': 'I hoped to have left them in perfect safety, and then to have quitted Paris.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these solemn words arise in his mind as the clouds sailing on high above him?', 'source': "These solemn words, which had been read at his father's grave, arose in his mind as he went down the dark streets, among the heavy shadows, with the moon and the clouds sailing on high above him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it the settled manner of a tired man?', 'source': 'It was the settled manner of a tired man, who had wandered and struggled and got lost, but who at length struck into his road and saw its end.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I find a written paper in a hole in the chimney?', 'source': 'In a hole in the chimney, where a stone has been worked out and replaced, I find a written paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the glorious sun seem to strike those words to his heart in its long bright rays?', 'source': 'But, the glorious sun, rising, seemed to strike those words, that burden of the night, straight and warm to his heart in its long bright rays.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the former say, ``the goose and not the gander's arrangement thus made, a man have nothing to fear from me'', ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me''?", 'source': "``Adieu, Mr. Barsad,'' said the former; ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could I not respect more?', 'source': 'And I could not respect your sorrow more, if you were my father.', 'answer': 'your sorrow'}
{'question': 'What do he read?', 'source': 'the chemist whistled softly, as he read it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was his boot still upon the hot embers of the flaming log?', 'source': 'His indifference to fire was sufficiently remarkable to elicit a word of remonstrance from Mr. Lorry; his boot was still upon the hot embers of the flaming log, when it had broken under the weight of his foot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I know from himself?', 'source': 'I knew it from himself.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, would you have no duty but to sacrifice her?', 'source': '``If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, you would have no duty but to sacrifice her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was this short examination quick with its work?', 'source': 'This short examination followed, for the court was quick with its work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President confide this paper?', 'source': "I confide this paper, in the writing of Doctor Manette, to the hands of the President.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this the writing of Doctor Manette?', 'source': 'This is the writing of Doctor Manette.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I want?', 'source': "I want no more words.''", 'answer': 'no more words'}
{'question': 'Who read it?', 'source': 'the chemist whistled softly, as he read it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did a bridge of light appear to span the air between him and the sun?', 'source': 'And looking along them, with reverently shaded eyes, a bridge of light appeared to span the air between him and the sun, while the river sparkled under it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do no favourable leaning in that quarter to-day?', 'source': 'No favourable leaning in that quarter to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Indictment deliver to him last night?', 'source': 'Indictment delivered to him last night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I think?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': 'they would be'}
{'question': 'Does it seem to be one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way?', 'source': 'It seems to be one of the kind smoothings and preparings of the way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does Mr. Cruncher wipe his forehead with his arm?', 'source': "That, Mr. Lorry,'' said Mr. Cruncher, wiping his forehead with his arm, as an announcement that he had arrived at the peroration of his discourse, ``is wot I would respectfully offer to you, sir.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I confide this paper?', 'source': "I confide this paper, in the writing of Doctor Manette, to the hands of the President.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the words in the echoes of his feet?', 'source': 'Now, that the streets were quiet, and the night wore on, the words were in the echoes of his feet, and were in the air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might she think?', 'source': "She might think it was contrived, in case of the worse, to convey to him the means of anticipating the sentence.''", 'answer': 'it was contrived'}
{'question': 'What may I say?', 'source': "Indeed, I may say that I was a man of business when a boy.''", 'answer': 'that I was a man of business when a boy'}
{'question': 'Who will many people miss when you leave it?', 'source': "How many people will miss you when you leave it empty!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What seemed to be?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did these solemn words arise in his mind as he went down the dark streets?', 'source': "These solemn words, which had been read at his father's grave, arose in his mind as he went down the dark streets, among the heavy shadows, with the moon and the clouds sailing on high above him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is not old?', 'source': '``I am not old, but my young way was never the way to age.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Were the words that burden of the night, straight and warm?', 'source': 'But, the glorious sun, rising, seemed to strike those words, that burden of the night, straight and warm to his heart in its long bright rays.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he glance upward at the moon, ``until to-morrow''?", 'source': "``There is nothing more to do,'' said he, glancing upward at the moon, ``until to-morrow.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a bridge of light look along them?', 'source': 'And looking along them, with reverently shaded eyes, a bridge of light appeared to span the air between him and the sun, while the river sparkled under it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the timid arm loosed from his neck?', 'source': 'He carried the child over, and before the timid arm was loosed from his neck asked her for a kiss.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was my young way never the way to age?', 'source': '``I am not old, but my young way was never the way to age.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What may a man say?', 'source': "Indeed, I may say that I was a man of business when a boy.''", 'answer': 'that I was a man of business when a boy'}
{'question': 'Did loud acclamations hail this rebuke?', 'source': 'Loud acclamations hailed this rebuke.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the people pour cheerfully out as he passed?', 'source': 'But, the theaters were all well filled, and the people poured cheerfully out as he passed, and went chatting home.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If it should go ill with the prisoner, have I ensured access to him?', 'source': "If it should go ill with the prisoner, I have ensured access to him, once.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lay the scrap of paper before him giving this citizen?', 'source': 'Giving this citizen, too, good night, as he confronted him at his counter, he laid the scrap of paper before him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May I say that I was a man of business when a boy?', 'source': "Indeed, I may say that I was a man of business when a boy.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he watch an eddy that turned and turned purposeless?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will my Spy find a place for me?', 'source': 'My Spy will find a place for me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it obviously the weakness of the position?', 'source': 'It was obviously the weakness of the position.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who went on?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did he look quickly at Carton to see if it were in his mind?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry had not thought of that, and he looked quickly at Carton to see if it were in his mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the President serve my gun that day?', 'source': 'As I serve my gun that day, I resolve, when the place shall fall, to examine that cell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I not quite mean?', 'source': "I did not quite mean what I said.''", 'answer': 'what I said'}
{'question': 'Did he put them in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them?', 'source': 'He put them, one by one, in the breast of his inner coat, counted out the money for them, and deliberately left the shop.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who shall mount to a hundred soon?', 'source': 'We shall mount to a hundred soon.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What have a man at length done all?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': 'that I can do here'}
{'question': 'Was a little wood-sawyer smoking his pipe at his shop-door?', 'source': 'A little wood-sawyer, having closed his shop, was smoking his pipe at his shop-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton gently press it?', 'source': 'He gave him his hand, and Carton gently pressed it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who says truly?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What shall we mount to soon?', 'source': 'We shall mount to a hundred soon.', 'answer': 'to a hundred'}
{'question': 'Are you free from that misfortune?', 'source': "You are free from that misfortune, however.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is so droll?', 'source': 'He is so droll, that Samson.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Could nothing worse happen to him if he were denounced?', 'source': "``To propose too much, would be to put this man's head under the axe, and, as he himself said, nothing worse could happen to him if he were denounced.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did its silent track in the water disappear?', 'source': "As its silent track in the water disappeared, the prayer that had broken up out of his heart for a merciful consideration of all his poor blindnesses and errors, ended in the words, ``I am the resurrection and the life.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton leave him there?', 'source': 'Carton left him there; but lingered at a little distance, and turned back to the gate again when it was shut, and touched it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who cannot sleep?', 'source': "I cannot sleep.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do you go to the Court to-morrow?', 'source': "You go to the Court to-morrow?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who awoke?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Do I mount to the cell?', 'source': 'I mount to the cell, with a fellow-citizen who is one of the Jury, directed by a gaoler.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the little man call after him?', 'source': "``But go and see that droll dog,'' the little man persisted, calling after him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did a man not quite mean?', 'source': "I did not quite mean what I said.''", 'answer': 'what I said'}
{'question': 'What have I at length done all?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': 'that I can do here'}
{'question': 'Had a little wood-sawyer closed his shop?', 'source': 'A little wood-sawyer, having closed his shop, was smoking his pipe at his shop-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he walk by the stream?', 'source': 'He walked by the stream, far from the houses, and in the light and warmth of the sun fell asleep on the bank.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he taking?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': 'note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features'}
{'question': 'Had he heard of her going to the prison every day?', 'source': 'He had heard of her going to the prison every day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who passed?', 'source': 'But, the theaters were all well filled, and the people poured cheerfully out as he passed, and went chatting home.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Do his fingers perpetually hovering about his lips?', 'source': 'Eager and prominent among them, one man with a craving face, and his fingers perpetually hovering about his lips, whose appearance gave great satisfaction to the spectators.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will many people miss you when you leave it?', 'source': "How many people will miss you when you leave it empty!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are a man free from that misfortune?', 'source': "You are free from that misfortune, however.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sometimes repeat them to himself as he walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton turn back to the gate again when it was shut, and touched it?', 'source': 'Carton left him there; but lingered at a little distance, and turned back to the gate again when it was shut, and touched it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who walked?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the stream carry it on to the sea?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you a cannonier that day?', 'source': 'You were a cannonier that day there, and you were among the first to enter the accursed fortress when it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I hope to have left them in perfect safety?', 'source': 'I hoped to have left them in perfect safety, and then to have quitted Paris.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May it be that I shall yet stand your friend, and repent in action?', 'source': 'It may be that I shall yet stand your friend, if you deserve it, and repent in action-- not in words.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he return the look?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is this?', 'source': 'This is that written paper.', 'answer': 'that written paper'}
{'question': 'Was a man strongly reminded of that expression?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the reckless manner the manner in which he said these words aloud?', 'source': 'It was not a reckless manner, the manner in which he said these words aloud under the fast-sailing clouds, nor was it more expressive of negligence than defiance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he carry the child over?', 'source': 'He carried the child over, and before the timid arm was loosed from his neck asked her for a kiss.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If I should prowl about the streets a long time shall; I reappear in the morning?', 'source': 'If I should prowl about the streets a long time, do not be uneasy; I shall reappear in the morning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the river sparkle under it?', 'source': 'And looking along them, with reverently shaded eyes, a bridge of light appeared to span the air between him and the sun, while the river sparkled under it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I walk with you to her gate?", 'source': "``I 'll walk with you to her gate.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do we call the World?', 'source': ", and by many associations of the days when what we call the World was not so real with me, and my faults were not confirmed in me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were a man a cannonier that day?', 'source': 'You were a cannonier that day there, and you were among the first to enter the accursed fortress when it fell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the reckless manner the manner in which last night said these words aloud?', 'source': 'It was not a reckless manner, the manner in which he said these words aloud under the fast-sailing clouds, nor was it more expressive of negligence than defiance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you not sarse the goose and not the gander?', 'source': 'For you cannot sarse the goose and not the gander.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I glad of that?', 'source': '``I am glad of that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know the consequences of mixing them?', 'source': "You know the consequences of mixing them?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must she be very desolate to-night?', 'source': "She must be very desolate to-night.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who himself said?', 'source': "``To propose too much, would be to put this man's head under the axe, and, as he himself said, nothing worse could happen to him if he were denounced.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Do you know the accused to be the husband of my daughter?', 'source': 'You know the accused to be the husband of my daughter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he strongly reminded of that expression?', 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was afoot again?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What falls?', 'source': 'It falls.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Was he having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind?", 'source': "Taking note of the wasted air which clouded the naturally handsome features, and having the expression of prisoners ' faces fresh in his mind, he was strongly reminded of that expression.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Carton say, ``It is all I could do''?", 'source': "``It is all I could do,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should the Republic demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself?', 'source': '``If the Republic should demand of you the sacrifice of your child herself, you would have no duty but to sacrifice her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she have such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you?', 'source': 'She has such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am a man glad of that?', 'source': '``I am glad of that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he followed his father to the grave?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they both silent?', 'source': 'They were both silent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he say ?', 'source': "``She came out here,'' he said, looking about him, ``turned this way, must have trod on these stones often.", 'answer': 'She came out here'}
{'question': 'Who is Mr. Lorry wot to?', 'source': "That, Mr. Lorry,'' said Mr. Cruncher, wiping his forehead with his arm, as an announcement that he had arrived at the peroration of his discourse, ``is wot I would respectfully offer to you, sir.", 'answer': 'I would respectfully offer to you'}
{'question': 'Was his view floated by him?', 'source': 'A trading-boat, with a sail of the softened color of a dead leaf, then glided into his view, floated by him, and died away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is to be?', 'source': "And which it is to be took into account that if it wos, it would not, even then, be all o ' one side.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did his daughter draw closer to him?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette sat down, with his eyes looking around, and his lips trembling; his daughter drew closer to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you mean the Guillotine?', 'source': '``You mean the Guillotine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Are Ernest Defarge's daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to me than my life?", 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were alone?', 'source': 'When they were alone, Mr. Lorry asked him what he had done?', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did all hang loose about him?', 'source': 'He wore the white riding-coat and top-boots, then in vogue, and the light of the fire touching their light surfaces made him look very pale, with his long brown hair, all untrimmed, hanging loose about him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise?', 'source': 'Long ago, when he had been famous among his earliest competitors as a youth of great promise, he had followed his father to the grave.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say, ``I forgot it''?", 'source': "``I forgot it,'' he said.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I been a man?', 'source': '``I have been a man of business, ever since I have been a man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he linger there yet a little longer?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this that written paper?', 'source': 'This is that written paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall I be there?', 'source': '``I shall be there, but only as one of the crowd.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the stream absorb it?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his tears fall?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I hope you are going to her?', 'source': 'You are going to her, I hope?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does she have?', 'source': 'She has such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you.', 'answer': 'such a strong attachment to you and reliance on you'}
{'question': 'Would any of them only add to her trouble?', 'source': "``She might think a thousand things,'' Carton said, ``and any of them would only add to her trouble.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I speak the truth!', 'source': "Patriots, I speak the truth!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall we mount to a hundred soon?', 'source': 'We shall mount to a hundred soon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would a man not get much by it?', 'source': 'Then, wot with undertakers, and wot with parish clerks, and wot with sextons, and wot with private watchmen (all awaricious and all in it), a man would not get much by it, even if it wos so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she sit beside her father?', 'source': 'She was there, sitting beside her father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he an old man now?', 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might she think it was contrived?', 'source': "She might think it was contrived, in case of the worse, to convey to him the means of anticipating the sentence.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say the last words into his usual manner?', 'source': 'Though he said the last words, with a slip into his usual manner, there was a true feeling and respect both in his tone and in his touch, that Mr. Lorry, who had never seen the better side of him, was wholly unprepared for.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go on?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'d he never have no good of it?", 'source': "He 'd never have no good of it; he 'd want all along to be out of the line, if he, could see his way out, being once in-- even if it wos so.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could I not sit by?', 'source': 'I could not see my father weep, and sit by, careless.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do samson and his men complain sometimes?', 'source': 'Samson and his men complain sometimes, of being exhausted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I not old?', 'source': '``I am not old, but my young way was never the way to age.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know my vagabond and restless habits?', 'source': 'You know my vagabond and restless habits.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he repeat them?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you say truly?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it seem to be?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I want no more words?', 'source': "I want no more words.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my arm sir?', 'source': "Take my arm, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I not quite mean what I said?', 'source': "I did not quite mean what I said.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think they would be?', 'source': "``You say truly, Mr. Carton; I think they would be.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my heart touched now! )', 'source': 'My heart is touched now, by many remembrances that had long fallen asleep, of my pretty young mother (and I so old! )', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could I not see my father weep?', 'source': 'I could not see my father weep, and sit by, careless.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she there?', 'source': 'She was there, sitting beside her father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go down the dark streets?', 'source': "These solemn words, which had been read at his father's grave, arose in his mind as he went down the dark streets, among the heavy shadows, with the moon and the clouds sailing on high above him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If they flop goes in favor of more patients and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'source': 'Or, if they flop, their floppings goes in favor of more patients, and how can you rightly have one without t ` other?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weaken them?", 'source': "Mr. Lorry's eyes gradually sought the fire; his sympathy with his darling, and the heavy disappointment of his second arrest, gradually weakened them; he was an old man now, overborne with anxiety of late, and his tears fell.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I serve my gun that day?', 'source': 'As I serve my gun that day, I resolve, when the place shall fall, to examine that cell.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his mother died?', 'source': 'His mother had died, years before.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say ``She came out here''?", 'source': "``She came out here,'' he said, looking about him, ``turned this way, must have trod on these stones often.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he give him his hand?', 'source': 'He gave him his hand, and Carton gently pressed it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I ready to go?', 'source': "I was ready to go.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he evidently understand it?', 'source': 'It seemed to be; he returned the look, and evidently understood it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it not enable Her to go to see him?', 'source': 'It would not enable Her to go to see him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I say to you when I first came?', 'source': 'As I said to you when I first came, I had better not see her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I put my hand out?', 'source': 'I can put my hand out, to do any little helpful work for her that my hand can find to do, without that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I at length done all that I can do here?', 'source': 'As I was telling you last night when Lucie came in so unexpectedly, I have at length done all that I can do here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'d he want all along to be out of the line being once in-- even if it wos so?", 'source': "He 'd never have no good of it; he 'd want all along to be out of the line, if he, could see his way out, being once in-- even if it wos so.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he not seek it?', 'source': 'He did not seek it, but repeated them and went on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are my daughter, and those dear to her, far dearer to me than my life?', 'source': 'My daughter, and those dear to her, are far dearer to me than my life.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hear them always?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have my Leave to Pass?', 'source': 'I have my Leave to Pass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What may it be in?', 'source': 'It may be that I shall yet stand your friend, if you deserve it, and repent in action-- not in words.', 'answer': 'that I shall yet stand your friend, and repent in action'}
{'question': 'Was she likewise much commended?', 'source': 'wherein she was likewise much commended.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not sleep?', 'source': "I cannot sleep.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I know it from himself?', 'source': 'I knew it from himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he so droll?', 'source': 'He is so droll, that Samson.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have you seen him at work?', 'source': "You have seen him at work?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could I not respect your sorrow more?', 'source': 'And I could not respect your sorrow more, if you were my father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pass?', 'source': 'But, the theaters were all well filled, and the people poured cheerfully out as he passed, and went chatting home.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I examine it?', 'source': 'I examine it, very closely.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the former say, ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me'', ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me''?", 'source': "``Adieu, Mr. Barsad,'' said the former; ``our arrangement thus made, you have nothing to fear from me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he awake?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he walk?', 'source': 'Perfectly calm and steady, he sometimes repeated them to himself as he walked; but, he heard them always.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he read it?', 'source': 'the chemist whistled softly, as he read it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does it fall?', 'source': 'It falls.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it to be?', 'source': "And which it is to be took into account that if it wos, it would not, even then, be all o ' one side.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he afoot again?', 'source': 'When he awoke and was afoot again, he lingered there yet a little longer, watching an eddy that turned and turned purposeless, until the stream absorbed it, and carried it on to the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they alone?', 'source': 'When they were alone, Mr. Lorry asked him what he had done?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he himself say?', 'source': "``To propose too much, would be to put this man's head under the axe, and, as he himself said, nothing worse could happen to him if he were denounced.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who presently said, ``Now your dinner is done''?", 'source': "``Now your dinner is done,'' Carton presently said, ``why do not you call a health, Mr. Darnay; why do not you give your toast?''", 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'Who do not wonder at this?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'the innocent Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Did Darnay answer not a word?', 'source': 'Again Darnay answered not a word.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the careless rejoinder nothing to do?', 'source': '``It was nothing to do, in the first place; and I do not know why I did it, in the second.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What places with him?', 'source': 'Change places with him, and would you have been looked at by those blue eyes as he was, and commiserated by that agitated face as he was?', 'answer': 'Change'}
{'question': 'Must Mr. Carton say so?', 'source': "``Since I must say so, I know it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do then wake me at?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': 'at ten'}
{'question': 'What come?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': 'then'}
{'question': "Where does why it's?", 'source': "``Why, it's on the tip of your tongue.", 'answer': 'on the tip of your tongue'}
{'question': 'What wake me at ten?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': 'then'}
{'question': 'Who do I care for?', 'source': "I care for no man on earth, and no man on earth cares for me.''", 'answer': 'for no man on earth'}
{'question': 'What did he drink in a few minutes?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': 'it all'}
{'question': 'Was Mr. Carton?', 'source': 'Change places with him, and would you have been looked at by those blue eyes as he was, and commiserated by that agitated face as he was?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it shiver to; then at Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'to pieces'}
{'question': 'Is the same wine drawer?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are not our own masters?', 'source': 'We men of business, who serve a House, are not our own masters.', 'answer': 'men of business'}
{'question': 'What was he the better for it in appearance?', 'source': 'He was unrobed, and was none the better for it in appearance.', 'answer': 'none'}
{'question': 'What were those numskulls deliberating?', 'source': 'I dined, myself, while those numskulls were deliberating which world you should belong to-- this, or some other.', 'answer': 'which world the innocent Mr. Lorry should belong to-- this, or some other'}
{'question': 'What did this strange being take up?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': 'a candle'}
{'question': "Who does that's!", 'source': "``That's a fair young lady to be pitied by and wept for by!", 'answer': 'a fair young lady to be pitied by'}
{'question': 'What was he none the better for it in?', 'source': 'He was unrobed, and was none the better for it in appearance.', 'answer': 'in appearance'}
{'question': 'Who is frightfully confused regarding time and place?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did he take down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so?', 'source': 'Drawing his arm through his own, he took him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so, up a covered way, into a tavern.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What am I frightfully confused regarding?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': 'time and place'}
{'question': 'What did his daughter have?', 'source': 'Only his daughter had the power of charming this black brooding from his mind.', 'answer': 'the power of charming this black brooding from his mind'}
{'question': 'What shivered to pieces; then at Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he resort to for consolation?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': 'to his pint of wine'}
{'question': 'Was a hackney-coach called?', 'source': 'A hackney-coach was called, and the father and daughter departed in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does he show what you have the man fallen away from?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who supposes she was?', 'source': "Not that she showed she was pleased, but I suppose she was.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What is a strange chance that throws you and me together?', 'source': '``This is a strange chance that throws you and me together.', 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Darnay square himself at to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': 'at his late client'}
{'question': 'What surveyed himself minutely in it?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': 'this strange being'}
{'question': 'What I _ do not think I do, said Carton?', 'source': "'' _ I _ do not think I do,'' said Carton.", 'answer': '_'}
{'question': 'Who has been present all day?', 'source': 'you have been present all day, and you ought to know.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who said it; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again?', 'source': "It clearly being incumbent on some one to say, ``Much better,'' Mr. Lorry said it; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who does not know what it may come to?', 'source': 'Do not let your sober face elate you, however; you do not know what it may come to.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did the father and daughter depart in?', 'source': 'A hackney-coach was called, and the father and daughter departed in it.', 'answer': 'in it'}
{'question': 'Did the allusion serve as a timely reminder to Darnay that this disagreeable companion had assisted him in the strait of the day?', 'source': 'The allusion served as a timely reminder to Darnay that this disagreeable companion had, of his own free will, assisted him in the strait of the day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do we have to think of more than ourselves?', 'source': "We have to think of the House more than ourselves.''", 'answer': 'of the House'}
{'question': 'What had his thoughts wandered away with?', 'source': 'With this strange expression on him his thoughts had wandered away.', 'answer': 'with this strange expression on him'}
{'question': 'Is the disappointed drudge sir?', 'source': 'I am a disappointed drudge, sir.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were pretty far advanced on your way to another?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who begins to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.?', 'source': "Indeed, I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who asked her the question pointedly at her father?', 'source': 'He asked her the question pointedly, and with a glance at her father.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he resort to his pint of wine for?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': 'for consolation'}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry say; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again?', 'source': "It clearly being incumbent on some one to say, ``Much better,'' Mr. Lorry said it; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What could have looked at him twice?', 'source': 'Yet, no one could have looked at him twice, without looking again: even though the opportunity of observation had not extended to the mournful cadence of his low grave voice, and to the abstraction that overclouded him fitfully, without any apparent reason.', 'answer': 'no one'}
{'question': 'If business imposes its restraints and its silences and impediments what does Mr. Darnay as a young gentleman of generosity know for?', 'source': 'And, sir, if business imposes its restraints and its silences and impediments, Mr. Darnay as a young gentleman of generosity knows how to make allowance for that circumstance.', 'answer': 'how to make allowance for that circumstance'}
{'question': 'Who do _ I _ do not think I do, said?', 'source': "'' _ I _ do not think I do,'' said Carton.", 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'Who know that?', 'source': 'There is nothing in you to like; you know that.', 'answer': 'Mr. Carton'}
{'question': "Did Doctor Manette's daughter have the power of charming this black brooding from his mind?", 'source': 'Only his daughter had the power of charming this black brooding from his mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did Carton say ``A last word: you think?''?", 'source': "Without returning the wish, Carton rose too, with something of a threat of defiance in his manner, and said, ``A last word, Mr. Darnay: you think I am drunk?''", 'answer': 'I am drunk'}
{'question': 'Do the innocent Mr. Lorry hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life?', 'source': 'I hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who might have used your talents better?', 'source': "You might have used your talents better.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who turned to her?', 'source': 'He slowly shook the shadow off, and turned to her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What is my father?', 'source': "``Shall we go home, my father?''", 'answer': 'home'}
{'question': 'What did he slowly shake off?', 'source': 'He slowly shook the shadow off, and turned to her.', 'answer': 'the shadow'}
{'question': 'What would it have been difficult by?', 'source': 'It would have been difficult by a far brighter light, to recognize in Doctor Manette, intellectual of face and upright of bearing, the shoemaker of the garret in Paris.', 'answer': 'by a far brighter light'}
{'question': 'Who knows I have been drinking?', 'source': "You know I have been drinking.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who are not much alike in that particular?', 'source': 'So we are not much alike in that particular.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What am I so far mended as to feel?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': 'that'}
{'question': 'Who said it bitterly?', 'source': 'He said it bitterly, and filled up his glass again: which was a large one.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who has made in yourself!', 'source': 'What a change you have made in yourself!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did a fair young lady to hand to a coach in the dark, Mr. Darnay turn the dialogue to that point?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did this strange being go to?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': 'to a glass that hung against the wall'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Stryver left them in the passages?', 'source': 'Mr. Stryver had left them in the passages, to shoulder his way back to the robing-room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does not think you do?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who thanked him for it?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who do I begin to think are not much alike in any particular, you and I.?', 'source': "Indeed, I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'When did he drink it all?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': 'in a few minutes'}
{'question': 'Who do I suppose was?', 'source': "Not that she showed she was pleased, but I suppose she was.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did he ask her the question pointedly at?', 'source': 'He asked her the question pointedly, and with a glance at her father.', 'answer': 'at her father'}
{'question': 'Did he now step up to where Mr. Lorry and Mr. Darnay stood upon the pavement?', 'source': 'He now stepped up to where Mr. Lorry and Mr. Darnay stood upon the pavement.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What has no good in it for the innocent Mr. Lorry-- except wine like this-- nor I for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'Who is a disappointed drudge?', 'source': 'I am a disappointed drudge, sir.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Must this be a strange night to the innocent Mr. Lorry?', 'source': "This must be a strange night to you, standing alone here with your counterpart on these street stones?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who softly lied her hand on his?', 'source': "``My father,'' said Lucie, softly laying her hand on his.", 'answer': 'my father'}
{'question': 'Who does he show what you might have been?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who hates the fellow?', 'source': "You hate the fellow.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did Lucie Manette walk between her father and Mr. Darnay?', 'source': 'Walking between her father and Mr. Darnay, Lucie Manette passed into the open air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had Mr. Darnay's thoughts wandered away with this strange expression on him?", 'source': 'With this strange expression on him his thoughts had wandered away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do Mr. Carton know?', 'source': "You know I have been drinking.''", 'answer': 'I have been drinking'}
{'question': 'What did he fall asleep on?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': 'on his arms'}
{'question': 'Who drank the toast?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What does this have no good in it for the innocent Mr. Lorry-- except for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'except wine like this-- nor I'}
{'question': 'Who do you hate?', 'source': "You hate the fellow.''", 'answer': 'the fellow'}
{'question': "What does why it's on?", 'source': "``Why, it's on the tip of your tongue.", 'answer': 'on the tip of your tongue'}
{'question': 'What does Mr. Carton show you?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': 'what you have the man fallen away from'}
{'question': 'Who is so far mended as to feel that?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did he turn to?', 'source': 'He slowly shook the shadow off, and turned to her.', 'answer': 'to her'}
{'question': 'What had nobody known of?', 'source': "Nobody had made any acknowledgment of Mr. Carton's part in the day's proceedings; nobody had known of it.", 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'Did he warmly thank Mr. Stryver?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay had kissed her hand fervently and gratefully, and had turned to Mr. Stryver, whom he warmly thanked.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the question now?', 'source': "``But ask yourself the question now.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he ask pointedly at her father?', 'source': 'He asked her the question pointedly, and with a glance at her father.', 'answer': 'her the question'}
{'question': 'Who does not wonder at it?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who are you?', 'source': "You are a man of business, too.''", 'answer': 'a man of business'}
{'question': 'Did this strange being survey Mr. Carton minutely in a candle?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you know have been drinking?', 'source': "You know I have been drinking.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "If you 'll excuse me for saying so, who really does not know that it is your business?", 'source': "If you 'll excuse me, as very much your elder, for saying so, I really do not know that it is your business.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do I not think do?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did my father softly lie her hand on?', 'source': "``My father,'' said Lucie, softly laying her hand on his.", 'answer': 'on his'}
{'question': 'Who has acted as if you do?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did Charles Darnay wish him good night?', 'source': 'The bill being paid, Charles Darnay rose and wished him good night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he say bitterly?', 'source': 'He said it bitterly, and filled up his glass again: which was a large one.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Were those numskulls deliberating which world the innocent Mr. Lorry should belong to-- this, or some other?', 'source': 'I dined, myself, while those numskulls were deliberating which world you should belong to-- this, or some other.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are we not much alike in?', 'source': 'So we are not much alike in that particular.', 'answer': 'in that particular'}
{'question': 'Who does not know why I did it?', 'source': '``It was nothing to do, in the first place; and I do not know why I did it, in the second.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who have you made in!', 'source': 'What a change you have made in yourself!', 'answer': 'in yourself'}
{'question': "Did Charles Darnay, ``to belong to this world again return, ``I hardly seem yet''?", 'source': "``I hardly seem yet,'' returned Charles Darnay, ``to belong to this world again.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did my father softly lie on his?', 'source': "``My father,'' said Lucie, softly laying her hand on his.", 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'If business imposes its restraints and its silences and impediments does Mr. Darnay as a young gentleman of generosity know how to make allowance for that circumstance?', 'source': 'And, sir, if business imposes its restraints and its silences and impediments, Mr. Darnay as a young gentleman of generosity knows how to make allowance for that circumstance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he drink?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'the toast'}
{'question': 'What do I hope for?', 'source': 'I hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life.', 'answer': 'you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life'}
{'question': 'Then shall Mr. Carton likewise know why?', 'source': '``Then you shall likewise know why.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he thank for it?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did he square himself at his late client to?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': 'to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Darnay kissed her hand fervently and gratefully?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay had kissed her hand fervently and gratefully, and had turned to Mr. Stryver, whom he warmly thanked.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do then bring Mr. Carton another pint of this same wine?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who am I?', 'source': 'I am a disappointed drudge, sir.', 'answer': 'a disappointed drudge'}
{'question': 'What did his late client take?', 'source': "``You have laid me under an obligation to you for life-- in two senses,'' said his late client, taking his hand.", 'answer': 'his hand'}
{'question': 'Were face and upright?', 'source': 'His face had become frozen, as it were, in a very curious look at Darnay: an intent look, deepening into a frown of dislike and distrust, not even unmixed with fear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might you have used better?', 'source': "You might have used your talents better.''", 'answer': 'your talents'}
{'question': 'What has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What does it have no good in it for me-- except for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'except wine like this-- nor I'}
{'question': 'What did he thank him for?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': 'Did this strange being go to a glass that hung against the wall?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Darnay square himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he draw his arm through?', 'source': 'Drawing his arm through his own, he took him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so, up a covered way, into a tavern.', 'answer': 'through his own'}
{'question': "Was the careless rejoinder, ``I neither want any thanks, nor merit any''?", 'source': "``I neither want any thanks, nor merit any,'' was the careless rejoinder.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'As to me, what is to forget that I belong to it?', 'source': '``As to me, the greatest desire I have, is to forget that I belong to it.', 'answer': 'the greatest desire I have,'}
{'question': 'What did he draw through his own?', 'source': 'Drawing his arm through his own, he took him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so, up a covered way, into a tavern.', 'answer': 'his arm'}
{'question': "What's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another?", 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did it shiver to pieces; then at?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'at Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall'}
{'question': 'What do I not wonder at?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'at it'}
{'question': 'What do I begin to think we are not much alike in?', 'source': "Indeed, I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.''", 'answer': 'in any particular, you and I.'}
{'question': 'Do then come?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': '``It was nothing to do, in the first place; and I do not know why I did it, in the second.', 'answer': 'nothing to do'}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Darnay bless you!', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay, good night, God bless you, sir!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's a fair young lady to be pitied by!", 'source': "``That's a fair young lady to be pitied by and wept for by!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knows that?', 'source': 'There is nothing in you to like; you know that.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What looked his companion full in the face while he drank the toast?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': 'Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall'}
{'question': 'What does it have no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': 'What does this have no good in it for the innocent Mr. Lorry-- except wine like this-- nor I for?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': "If you 'll excuse me for saying so, what do I really not know that it is?", 'source': "If you 'll excuse me, as very much your elder, for saying so, I really do not know that it is your business.''", 'answer': 'your business'}
{'question': 'Did he square himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the innocent Mr. Lorry not wonder at this?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Charles Darnay, ``to belong to this world again return, ``the innocent Mr. Lorry hardly seem yet''?", 'source': "``I hardly seem yet,'' returned Charles Darnay, ``to belong to this world again.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he fill?', 'source': 'he said, filling his new goblet.', 'answer': 'his new goblet'}
{'question': 'Do I hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life?', 'source': 'I hope you have been this day preserved for a prosperous and happy life.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were you pretty far advanced on?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': 'on your way to another'}
{'question': "Did Stryver say, ``I have a night's work to do yet''?", 'source': "``Speak for yourself, Mr. Lorry,'' said Stryver; ``I have a night's work to do yet.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall look his companion full in the face while he drank the toast?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he still have on?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': 'his wig and gown'}
{'question': 'Must this be a strange night to you?', 'source': "This must be a strange night to you, standing alone here with your counterpart on these street stones?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it have been difficult by a far brighter light?', 'source': 'It would have been difficult by a far brighter light, to recognize in Doctor Manette, intellectual of face and upright of bearing, the shoemaker of the garret in Paris.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he answer ``Yes with a long breath''?", 'source': "With a long breath, he answered ``Yes.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does no man on earth care for me?', 'source': "I care for no man on earth, and no man on earth cares for me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I suppose?', 'source': "Not that she showed she was pleased, but I suppose she was.''", 'answer': 'she was'}
{'question': 'Do I care for no man on earth?', 'source': "I care for no man on earth, and no man on earth cares for me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this strange being take up a candle?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were those numskulls deliberating which world you should belong to-- this, or some other?', 'source': 'I dined, myself, while those numskulls were deliberating which world you should belong to-- this, or some other.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall ring the bell?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am the innocent Mr. Lorry so far mended as to feel that?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Carton know that?', 'source': 'There is nothing in you to like; you know that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do then bring me another pint of this same wine?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he show you what you have the man fallen away from?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did you know in?', 'source': "``If you knew what a conflict goes on in the business mind, when the business mind is divided between good-natured impulse and business appearances, you would be amused, Mr. Darnay.''", 'answer': 'what a conflict goes on in the business mind'}
{'question': 'Did it shiver to pieces; then at Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the father and daughter depart in it?', 'source': 'A hackney-coach was called, and the father and daughter departed in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were the innocent Mr. Lorry pretty far advanced on this's way to another?", 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn the dialogue to that point?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Carton say bless you, _ I _ have no business?', 'source': "Bless you, _ I _ have no business,'' said Mr. Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did you know what a conflict goes on in the business mind?', 'source': "``If you knew what a conflict goes on in the business mind, when the business mind is divided between good-natured impulse and business appearances, you would be amused, Mr. Darnay.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you not know?', 'source': 'Do not let your sober face elate you, however; you do not know what it may come to.', 'answer': 'what it may come to'}
{'question': 'Does Change place with him?', 'source': 'Change places with him, and would you have been looked at by those blue eyes as he was, and commiserated by that agitated face as he was?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his daughter have the power of charming this black brooding from his mind?', 'source': 'Only his daughter had the power of charming this black brooding from his mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he none the better for it in appearance?', 'source': 'He was unrobed, and was none the better for it in appearance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I not think?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': 'you do'}
{'question': 'Am I frightfully confused regarding time and place?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are men of business not our own masters?', 'source': 'We men of business, who serve a House, are not our own masters.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you know?', 'source': "You know I have been drinking.''", 'answer': 'I have been drinking'}
{'question': "Does this's not so long since the innocent Mr. Lorry were pretty far advanced on your way to another?", 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who speaks faintly?', 'source': "You speak faintly.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Have you been present all day?', 'source': 'you have been present all day, and you ought to know.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his thoughts wandered away with this strange expression on him?', 'source': 'With this strange expression on him his thoughts had wandered away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Lucie softly lie her hand on his?', 'source': "``My father,'' said Lucie, softly laying her hand on his.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you a man of business?', 'source': "You are a man of business, too.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do then wake me at ten?', 'source': "On his answering in the affirmative, ``Then bring me another pint of this same wine, drawer, and come and wake me at ten.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the opportunity of observation not extended to the mournful cadence of his low grave voice?', 'source': 'Yet, no one could have looked at him twice, without looking again: even though the opportunity of observation had not extended to the mournful cadence of his low grave voice, and to the abstraction that overclouded him fitfully, without any apparent reason.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the friends of the acquitted prisoner have dispersed-- that he would not be released that night?', 'source': 'The friends of the acquitted prisoner had dispersed, under the impression-- which he himself had originated-- that he would not be released that night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could no one have looked at him twice?', 'source': 'Yet, no one could have looked at him twice, without looking again: even though the opportunity of observation had not extended to the mournful cadence of his low grave voice, and to the abstraction that overclouded him fitfully, without any apparent reason.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Then what shall you likewise know?', 'source': '``Then you shall likewise know why.', 'answer': 'why'}
{'question': 'What does he show you?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': 'what you have the man fallen away from'}
{'question': 'Am I a disappointed drudge?', 'source': 'I am a disappointed drudge, sir.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'The opportunity of observation had not to the abstraction that overclouded him fitfully?', 'source': 'Yet, no one could have looked at him twice, without looking again: even though the opportunity of observation had not extended to the mournful cadence of his low grave voice, and to the abstraction that overclouded him fitfully, without any apparent reason.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do we have to think of the House more than ourselves?', 'source': "We have to think of the House more than ourselves.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he slowly shake the shadow off?', 'source': 'He slowly shook the shadow off, and turned to her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does why it's on the tip of your tongue?", 'source': "``Why, it's on the tip of your tongue.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this strange being survey himself minutely in it?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'As to me, is the greatest desire I have, to forget that I belong to it?', 'source': '``As to me, the greatest desire I have, is to forget that I belong to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we not much alike in that particular?', 'source': 'So we are not much alike in that particular.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I so far mended as to feel that?', 'source': "``I am frightfully confused regarding time and place; but I am so far mended as to feel that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.?', 'source': "Indeed, I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does this have no good in it for the innocent Mr. Lorry-- except wine like this-- nor I for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he show you what you might have been?', 'source': 'A good reason for taking to a man, that he shows you what you have fallen away from, and what you might have been!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it nothing to do?', 'source': '``It was nothing to do, in the first place; and I do not know why I did it, in the second.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is home my father?', 'source': "``Shall we go home, my father?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he drink it all in a few minutes?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he ask her the question pointedly at her father?', 'source': 'He asked her the question pointedly, and with a glance at her father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he resort to his pint of wine for consolation?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he draw his arm through his own?', 'source': 'Drawing his arm through his own, he took him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so, up a covered way, into a tavern.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do _ I _ do not think I do, said Carton?', 'source': "'' _ I _ do not think I do,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did my father softly lie her hand on his?', 'source': "``My father,'' said Lucie, softly laying her hand on his.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you hate the fellow?', 'source': "You hate the fellow.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'You ought to know?', 'source': 'you have been present all day, and you ought to know.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this a strange chance that throws you and me together?', 'source': '``This is a strange chance that throws you and me together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he drink the toast?', 'source': 'Looking his companion full in the face while he drank the toast, Carton flung his glass over his shoulder against the wall, where it shivered to pieces; then, rang the bell, and ordered in another.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know that?', 'source': 'There is nothing in you to like; you know that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he fall asleep on his arms?', 'source': 'He resorted to his pint of wine for consolation, drank it all in a few minutes, and fell asleep on his arms, with his hair straggling over the table, and a long winding-sheet in the candle dripping down upon him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so?', 'source': 'Drawing his arm through his own, he took him down Ludgate-hill to Fleet-street, and so, up a covered way, into a tavern.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you not know what it may come to?', 'source': 'Do not let your sober face elate you, however; you do not know what it may come to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I dine?', 'source': 'I dined, myself, while those numskulls were deliberating which world you should belong to-- this, or some other.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I suppose she was?', 'source': "Not that she showed she was pleased, but I suppose she was.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he thank him for it?', 'source': 'He turned the dialogue to that point, and thanked him for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he unrobed?', 'source': 'He was unrobed, and was none the better for it in appearance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry say it; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again?', 'source': "It clearly being incumbent on some one to say, ``Much better,'' Mr. Lorry said it; perhaps not quite disinterestedly, but with the interested object of squeezing himself back again.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn to her?', 'source': 'He slowly shook the shadow off, and turned to her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might you have used your talents better?', 'source': "You might have used your talents better.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say it bitterly?', 'source': 'He said it bitterly, and filled up his glass again: which was a large one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he still have his wig and gown on?', 'source': 'He still had his wig and gown on, and he said, squaring himself at his late client to that degree that he squeezed the innocent Mr. Lorry clean out of the group: ``I am glad to have brought you off with honor, Mr. Darnay.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have you made in yourself!', 'source': 'What a change you have made in yourself!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "If you 'll excuse me for saying so, do I really not know that it is your business?", 'source': "If you 'll excuse me, as very much your elder, for saying so, I really do not know that it is your business.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his late client take his hand?', 'source': "``You have laid me under an obligation to you for life-- in two senses,'' said his late client, taking his hand.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you speak faintly?', 'source': "You speak faintly.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know I have been drinking?', 'source': "You know I have been drinking.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not know why I did it?', 'source': '``It was nothing to do, in the first place; and I do not know why I did it, in the second.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does it have no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it?', 'source': 'It has no good in it for me-- except wine like this-- nor I for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not think you do?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another?", 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he fill his new goblet?', 'source': 'he said, filling his new goblet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you pretty far advanced on your way to another?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not wonder at it?', 'source': "``I do not wonder at it; it's not so long since you were pretty far advanced on your way to another.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have you acted as if you do?', 'source': "``You have acted as if you do; but I do not think you do.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he left alone?', 'source': 'When he was left alone, this strange being took up a candle, went to a glass that hung against the wall, and surveyed himself minutely in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must I say so?', 'source': "``Since I must say so, I know it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say?', 'source': 'he said, filling his new goblet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did you have?', 'source': "``If you had,'' pursued Mr. Lorry, ``perhaps you would attend to it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "If you 'll excuse me for saying so, what do I really not know?", 'source': "If you 'll excuse me, as very much your elder, for saying so, I really do not know that it is your business.''", 'answer': 'that it is your business'}
{'question': 'Was he?', 'source': 'Change places with him, and would you have been looked at by those blue eyes as he was, and commiserated by that agitated face as he was?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were it?', 'source': 'His face had become frozen, as it were, in a very curious look at Darnay: an intent look, deepening into a frown of dislike and distrust, not even unmixed with fear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Then shall you likewise know why?', 'source': '``Then you shall likewise know why.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is this?', 'source': '``This is a strange chance that throws you and me together.', 'answer': 'a strange chance that throws you and me together'}
{'question': 'What do I begin to think in?', 'source': "Indeed, I begin to think we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.''", 'answer': 'we are not much alike in any particular, you and I.'}
{'question': 'Who were we fellow-students in?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': 'in the Student-Quarter of Paris'}
{'question': 'What did this man stand still on across a silent terrace?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': 'on his way'}
{'question': 'What was its pillow wet with?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': 'with wasted tears'}
{'question': 'What put his hands in his waistband again?', 'source': 'When the repast was fully discussed, the lion put his hands in his waistband again, and lay down to meditate.', 'answer': 'the lion'}
{'question': 'What did they go into?', 'source': 'They went into a dingy room lined with books and littered with papers, where there was a blazing fire.', 'answer': 'into a dingy room lined with books'}
{'question': "Was ten o'clock sir?", 'source': "``Ten o'clock, sir,'' said the man at the tavern, whom he had charged to wake him-- ``ten o'clock, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has fallen into mine?', 'source': "``Before Shrewsbury, and at Shrewsbury, and ever since Shrewsbury,'' pursued Carton, ``you have fallen into your rank, and I have fallen into mine.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who returned with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity from these pilgrimages to the jug and basin?', 'source': 'From these pilgrimages to the jug and basin, he returned with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity.', 'answer': 'the Stryver clerk'}
{'question': 'Who was the Sessions not born there, was?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did the lion put his hands in again?', 'source': 'When the repast was fully discussed, the lion put his hands in his waistband again, and lay down to meditate.', 'answer': 'in his waistband'}
{'question': 'What did he throw himself down in his clothes on?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': 'on a neglected bed'}
{'question': 'What was a loose bed-gown, and his throat bare for?', 'source': 'He had his slippers on, and a loose bed-gown, and his throat was bare for his greater ease.', 'answer': 'for his greater ease'}
{'question': 'What have I fallen into?', 'source': "``Before Shrewsbury, and at Shrewsbury, and ever since Shrewsbury,'' pursued Carton, ``you have fallen into your rank, and I have fallen into mine.", 'answer': 'into mine'}
{'question': 'Who did his host follow out on the staircase with a candle?', 'source': 'When his host followed him out on the staircase with a candle, to light him down the stairs, the day was coldly looking in through its grimy windows.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did most men drink hard?', 'source': 'Those were drinking days, and most men drank hard.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'the Stryver clerk'}
{'question': "What 'll I get to?", 'source': "And now I 'll have no more drink; I 'll get to bed.''", 'answer': 'to bed'}
{'question': "Does Sydney's not worth your while to apostrophise the Sessions, or the air, about it?", 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the lion take it with, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it?', 'source': 'The lion took it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it, and the jackal assisted both.', 'answer': 'with care and caution'}
{'question': 'When did this man see?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': 'for a moment'}
{'question': 'Do and down the next; now in spirits and now in despondency up one minute?', 'source': "Up one minute and down the next; now in spirits and now in despondency!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where did this man lie?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': 'in the wilderness before him'}
{'question': 'What did he fold them on his head in!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'in a manner hideous to behold'}
{'question': 'Do a girl deny the beauty?', 'source': 'I pledge you, but I deny the beauty.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he throw down in his clothes on a neglected bed?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Do the Sessions not gainsay every question?', 'source': '``I do not gainsay it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did a girl's host follow out on the staircase with a candle?", 'source': 'When his host followed him out on the staircase with a candle, to light him down the stairs, the day was coldly looking in through its grimy windows.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who was a golden-haired doll!', 'source': "She was a golden-haired doll!''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Do the Sessions do?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What proceeded to offer it to him?', 'source': 'At length the jackal had got together a compact repast for the lion, and proceeded to offer it to him.', 'answer': 'the jackal'}
{'question': 'What was the wilderness before him?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': 'a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance'}
{'question': 'Has what roughened your temper?', 'source': 'What has roughened your temper?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was I not born there, was?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Did the jackal loosened the Stryver clerk's dress, come back with a large jug of cold water, a basin, and a towel or two?", 'source': 'Sullenly enough, the jackal loosened his dress, went into an adjoining room, and came back with a large jug of cold water, a basin, and a towel or two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he fold on his head in a manner hideous to behold!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Partly through paying the Sessions to help you, do I suppose?', 'source': '``Partly through paying me to help you, I suppose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What 'll I have?", 'source': "And now I 'll have no more drink; I 'll get to bed.''", 'answer': 'no more drink'}
{'question': 'Was to-night Memory?', 'source': "``Not much boiling down to be done to-night, Memory,'' said Mr. Stryver, gaily, as he looked among his papers.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``but my opinion is you were''?", 'source': "``I was not present at the ceremony; but my opinion is you were,'' said Carton.", 'answer': 'Carton'}
{'question': 'What did he sit down at!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'at the table'}
{'question': 'What did he fold them on in a manner hideous to behold!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'on his head'}
{'question': 'What did I do?', 'source': "Even then, I did exercises for other boys, and seldom did my own.''", 'answer': 'exercises for other boys'}
{'question': 'What did I have to get into?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': 'into the front rank'}
{'question': 'Was the air cold and sad?', 'source': 'When he got out of the house, the air was cold and sad, the dull sky overcast, the river dark and dim, the whole scene like a lifeless desert.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does God know?', 'source': '``God knows.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he fold on his head in a manner hideous to behold!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he throw himself down in on a neglected bed?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': 'in his clothes'}
{'question': 'What did he look at?', 'source': 'He sat, with his hands in his pockets and his legs stretched out before him, looking at the fire.', 'answer': 'at the fire'}
{'question': 'What did the Sessions seldom do?', 'source': "Even then, I did exercises for other boys, and seldom did my own.''", 'answer': 'my own'}
{'question': 'Was the Sessions always behind?', 'source': "You were always in the front rank, and I was always behind.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the lion then composed the Stryver clerk on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table glass ready to his hand?', 'source': 'The lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table, while the jackal sat at his own paper-bestrewn table proper, on the other side of it, with the bottles and glasses ready to his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who denies the beauty?', 'source': 'I pledge you, but I deny the beauty.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What were you always in?', 'source': "You were always in the front rank, and I was always behind.''", 'answer': 'in the front rank'}
{'question': 'Did every question tell?', 'source': "Every question told.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What's a gloomy thing?", 'source': "It's a gloomy thing, however, to talk about one's own past, with the day breaking.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What do I deny?', 'source': 'I pledge you, but I deny the beauty.', 'answer': 'the beauty'}
{'question': 'Partly through paying me to help you, who supposes?', 'source': '``Partly through paying me to help you, I suppose.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Did the lion take eke at the Sessions, Mr. Stryver with care and caution, made the Stryver clerk's selections from it, and his remarks upon it?", 'source': 'The lion took it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it, and the jackal assisted both.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the repast fully discussed?', 'source': 'When the repast was fully discussed, the lion put his hands in his waistband again, and lay down to meditate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he look down into?', 'source': "``Pretty witness,'' he muttered, looking down into his glass.", 'answer': 'into his glass'}
{'question': 'What did his host follow him out on the staircase with?', 'source': 'When his host followed him out on the staircase with a candle, to light him down the stairs, the day was coldly looking in through its grimy windows.', 'answer': 'with a candle'}
{'question': 'Who did your honor tell to call you?', 'source': "Your honor told me to call you.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who did your honor tell me to call?', 'source': "Your honor told me to call you.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Do the Sessions want to do?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When were those?', 'source': 'Those were drinking days, and most men drank hard.', 'answer': 'drinking days'}
{'question': "What does it's?", 'source': "It's a gloomy thing, however, to talk about one's own past, with the day breaking.", 'answer': 'a gloomy thing'}
{'question': 'Who summones no energy and purpose?', 'source': 'You summon no energy and purpose.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he get out of?', 'source': 'When he got out of the house, the air was cold and sad, the dull sky overcast, the river dark and dim, the whole scene like a lifeless desert.', 'answer': 'of the house'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Stryver say, ``And now we have done, Sydney, fill a bumper of punch''?", 'source': "``And now we have done, Sydney, fill a bumper of punch,'' said Mr. Stryver.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who got out of the house?', 'source': 'When he got out of the house, the air was cold and sad, the dull sky overcast, the river dark and dim, the whole scene like a lifeless desert.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who supposes it was my way?', 'source': "It was my way, I suppose.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he have on?', 'source': 'He had his slippers on, and a loose bed-gown, and his throat was bare for his greater ease.', 'answer': 'his slippers'}
{'question': 'What do you summon?', 'source': 'You summon no energy and purpose.', 'answer': 'no energy and purpose'}
{'question': 'What did he toss on?', 'source': 'After a few dull efforts to get to sleep again, which the man dexterously combated by stirring the fire continuously for five minutes, he got up, tossed his hat on, and walked out.', 'answer': 'his hat'}
{'question': 'Who was partially wringing them out?', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did I think I should have been?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': 'much the same sort of fellow'}
{'question': 'What did the lion take with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it?', 'source': 'The lion took it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it, and the jackal assisted both.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Did Stryver say, ``You are a little late, Memory''?", 'source': "``You are a little late, Memory,'' said Stryver.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did this man lie in?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': 'in the wilderness before him'}
{'question': 'Did the two drink together?', 'source': "What the two drank together, between Hilary Term and Michaelmas, might have floated a king's ship.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it?", 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did a remarkable improvement come upon eke at the Sessions, Mr. Stryver as to this?', 'source': 'But, a remarkable improvement came upon him as to this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I seldom do?', 'source': "Even then, I did exercises for other boys, and seldom did my own.''", 'answer': 'my own'}
{'question': 'Were the Sessions very sound in the matter of those crown witnesses to-day?', 'source': '``You were very sound, Sydney, in the matter of those crown witnesses to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the jackal loosened his dress, go into an adjoining room?', 'source': 'Sullenly enough, the jackal loosened his dress, went into an adjoining room, and came back with a large jug of cold water, a basin, and a towel or two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he shake?', 'source': 'Mr. Stryver laughed till he shook his precocious paunch.', 'answer': 'his precocious paunch'}
{'question': 'What told me to call you?', 'source': "Your honor told me to call you.''", 'answer': 'your honor'}
{'question': "Who is not sure that it was not yours, ``Upon my soul''?", 'source': '``Upon my soul, I am not sure that it was not yours.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did they go into a dingy room littered with papers?', 'source': 'They went into a dingy room lined with books and littered with papers, where there was a blazing fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does not gainsay it?', 'source': '``I do not gainsay it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was always nowhere?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Were you very sound in the matter of those crown witnesses to-day?', 'source': '``You were very sound, Sydney, in the matter of those crown witnesses to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they go into a dingy room lined with books?', 'source': 'They went into a dingy room lined with books and littered with papers, where there was a blazing fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were always somewhere?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who did I think he was?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': 'rather a handsome fellow'}
{'question': "What does it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about?", 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': 'about it'}
{'question': 'Who was he partially wringing out?', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did the jackal remove the towels from his head?', 'source': 'The jackal removed the towels from his head, which had been steaming again, shook himself, yawned, shivered, and complied.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was she!', 'source': "She was a golden-haired doll!''", 'answer': 'a golden-haired doll'}
{'question': 'What was he partially wringing out?', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': "Did Carton say, ``I was not present at the ceremony''?", 'source': "``I was not present at the ceremony; but my opinion is you were,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I suppose was my way?', 'source': "It was my way, I suppose.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What do I suppose it was?', 'source': "It was my way, I suppose.''", 'answer': 'my way'}
{'question': 'Were we fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he the tavern charged to wake him?', 'source': "``Ten o'clock, sir,'' said the man at the tavern, whom he had charged to wake him-- ``ten o'clock, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who for became gloomy again?', 'source': 'Apparently not, for he became gloomy again.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who was gardens?', 'source': 'In the fair city of this vision, there were airy galleries from which the loves and graces looked upon him, gardens in which the fruits of life hung ripening, waters of Hope that sparkled in his sight.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What do I not gainsay?', 'source': '``I do not gainsay it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the jackal loosened his dress, come back with a large jug of cold water, a basin, and a towel or two?', 'source': 'Sullenly enough, the jackal loosened his dress, went into an adjoining room, and came back with a large jug of cold water, a basin, and a towel or two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What glasses ready to his hand?', 'source': 'The lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table, while the jackal sat at his own paper-bestrewn table proper, on the other side of it, with the bottles and glasses ready to his hand.', 'answer': 'the lion then composed the Stryver clerk on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table'}
{'question': 'Was its pillow wet with wasted tears?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was him?', 'source': 'In the fair city of this vision, there were airy galleries from which the loves and graces looked upon him, gardens in which the fruits of life hung ripening, waters of Hope that sparkled in his sight.', 'answer': 'gardens'}
{'question': 'Did the jackal sit at his own paper-bestrewn table proper?', 'source': 'The lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table, while the jackal sat at his own paper-bestrewn table proper, on the other side of it, with the bottles and glasses ready to his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I do exercises for other boys?', 'source': "Even then, I did exercises for other boys, and seldom did my own.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Am Sydney Carton not sure that that was not yours, ``Upon my soul''?", 'source': '``Upon my soul, I am not sure that it was not yours.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he throw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed?', 'source': 'Climbing to a high chamber in a well of houses, he threw himself down in his clothes on a neglected bed, and its pillow was wet with wasted tears.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did we pick up?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': 'French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of'}
{'question': 'Did he fold them on his head in a manner hideous to behold!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does the lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table glass ready to?', 'source': 'The lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table, while the jackal sat at his own paper-bestrewn table proper, on the other side of it, with the bottles and glasses ready to his hand.', 'answer': 'to his hand'}
{'question': 'Did this man stand still on his way across a silent terrace?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What She _ pretty?', 'source': "'' _ She _ pretty?''", 'answer': '_'}
{'question': 'Did I have to get into the front rank?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I fallen into mine?', 'source': "``Before Shrewsbury, and at Shrewsbury, and ever since Shrewsbury,'' pursued Carton, ``you have fallen into your rank, and I have fallen into mine.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a remarkable improvement come upon him as to this?', 'source': 'But, a remarkable improvement came upon him as to this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I get to bed?", 'source': "And now I 'll have no more drink; I 'll get to bed.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he steeping the towels in the water?', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the Stryver clerk think?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': 'he was rather a handsome fellow'}
{'question': 'What was the Sessions not born?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': 'there, was I'}
{'question': 'Who remembers?', 'source': 'I remember.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did this man lie in the wilderness before him?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the wilderness before him a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "If a girl swoons within a yard or two of a man's nose, can he see it without a perspective-glass?", 'source': "If a girl, doll or no doll, swoons within a yard or two of a man's nose, he can see it without a perspective-glass.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I have no more drink?", 'source': "And now I 'll have no more drink; I 'll get to bed.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she a golden-haired doll!', 'source': "She was a golden-haired doll!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a loose bed-gown, and his throat bare for his greater ease?', 'source': 'He had his slippers on, and a loose bed-gown, and his throat was bare for his greater ease.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this man see for a moment?', 'source': 'Waste forces within him, and a desert all around, this man stood still on his way across a silent terrace, and saw for a moment, lying in the wilderness before him, a mirage of honorable ambition, self-denial, and perseverance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were those drinking days?', 'source': 'Those were drinking days, and most men drank hard.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the lion take it with care and caution, made?', 'source': 'The lion took it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it, and the jackal assisted both.', 'answer': 'his selections from it, and his remarks upon it'}
{'question': 'Did he sit down at the table!', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you always in the front rank?', 'source': "You were always in the front rank, and I was always behind.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who wants to do?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did he look at the fire?', 'source': 'He sat, with his hands in his pockets and his legs stretched out before him, looking at the fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do turn me in some other direction before I go?', 'source': "Turn me in some other direction before I go.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the jackal proceed to offer it to him?', 'source': 'At length the jackal had got together a compact repast for the lion, and proceeded to offer it to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's a gloomy thing?", 'source': "It's a gloomy thing, however, to talk about one's own past, with the day breaking.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I think I should have been much the same sort of fellow?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his host follow him out on the staircase with a candle?', 'source': 'When his host followed him out on the staircase with a candle, to light him down the stairs, the day was coldly looking in through its grimy windows.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was gone?', 'source': 'A moment, and it was gone.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Do I deny the beauty?', 'source': 'I pledge you, but I deny the beauty.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the lion put his hands in his waistband again?', 'source': 'When the repast was fully discussed, the lion put his hands in his waistband again, and lay down to meditate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was I not born?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': 'there, was I'}
{'question': 'Did we pick up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his head been steaming again?', 'source': 'The jackal removed the towels from his head, which had been steaming again, shook himself, yawned, shivered, and complied.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I always nowhere?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Carton say, ``but my opinion is you were''?", 'source': "``I was not present at the ceremony; but my opinion is you were,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it?", 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I think he was rather a handsome fellow?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he get out of the house?', 'source': 'When he got out of the house, the air was cold and sad, the dull sky overcast, the river dark and dim, the whole scene like a lifeless desert.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were you always somewhere?', 'source': "Even when we were fellow-students in the Student-Quarter of Paris, picking up French, and French law, and other French crumbs that we did not get much good of, you were always somewhere, and I was always nowhere.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did your honor tell me to call you?', 'source': "Your honor told me to call you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Stryver clerk return with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity from these pilgrimages to the jug and basin?', 'source': 'From these pilgrimages to the jug and basin, he returned with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you summon no energy and purpose?', 'source': 'You summon no energy and purpose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do two to-night I think?', 'source': '``Two to-night, I think.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he shake his precocious paunch?', 'source': 'Mr. Stryver laughed till he shook his precocious paunch.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have his slippers on?', 'source': 'He had his slippers on, and a loose bed-gown, and his throat was bare for his greater ease.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both laugh?', 'source': 'At this, he laughed again, and they both laughed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he walk out?', 'source': 'After a few dull efforts to get to sleep again, which the man dexterously combated by stirring the fire continuously for five minutes, he got up, tossed his hat on, and walked out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look down into his glass?', 'source': "``Pretty witness,'' he muttered, looking down into his glass.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the lion take it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it?', 'source': 'The lion took it with care and caution, made his selections from it, and his remarks upon it, and the jackal assisted both.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did for he become gloomy again?', 'source': 'Apparently not, for he became gloomy again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he get up?', 'source': 'After a few dull efforts to get to sleep again, which the man dexterously combated by stirring the fire continuously for five minutes, he got up, tossed his hat on, and walked out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I think?', 'source': "``I thought he was rather a handsome fellow, and I thought I should have been much the same sort of fellow, if I had had any luck.''", 'answer': 'he was rather a handsome fellow'}
{'question': 'Did he toss his hat on?', 'source': 'After a few dull efforts to get to sleep again, which the man dexterously combated by stirring the fire continuously for five minutes, he got up, tossed his hat on, and walked out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Partly through paying me to help you, do I suppose?', 'source': '``Partly through paying me to help you, I suppose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I not born there, was I?', 'source': "``I had to get into the front rank; I was not born there, was I?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table glass ready to his hand?', 'source': 'The lion then composed himself on his back on a sofa on one side of the drinking-table, while the jackal sat at his own paper-bestrewn table proper, on the other side of it, with the bottles and glasses ready to his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I seldom do my own?', 'source': "Even then, I did exercises for other boys, and seldom did my own.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit?', 'source': 'He sat, with his hands in his pockets and his legs stretched out before him, looking at the fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he laugh again?', 'source': 'At this, he laughed again, and they both laughed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I suppose it was my way?', 'source': "It was my way, I suppose.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say, ``Now I am ready!''", 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Am I not sure that it was not yours, ``Upon my soul''?", 'source': '``Upon my soul, I am not sure that it was not yours.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do _ She _ pretty?', 'source': "'' _ She _ pretty?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "When does it's not about it?", 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': 'worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air,'}
{'question': 'Was I always behind?', 'source': "You were always in the front rank, and I was always behind.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was him gardens?', 'source': 'In the fair city of this vision, there were airy galleries from which the loves and graces looked upon him, gardens in which the fruits of life hung ripening, waters of Hope that sparkled in his sight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it begin to get about?', 'source': 'At last, it began to get about, among such as were interested in the matter, that although Sydney Carton would never be a lion, he was an amazingly good jackal, and that he rendered suit and service to Stryver in that humble capacity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he partially wringing them out?', 'source': "Steeping the towels in the water, and partially wringing them out, he folded them on his head in a manner hideous to behold, sat down at the table, and said, ``Now I am ready!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I remember?', 'source': 'I remember.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you want to do?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you do?', 'source': "But it's not worth your while to apostrophise me, or the air, about it; what you want to do, you do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it gone?', 'source': 'A moment, and it was gone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not gainsay it?', 'source': '``I do not gainsay it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he return with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity from these pilgrimages to the jug and basin?', 'source': 'From these pilgrimages to the jug and basin, he returned with such eccentricities of damp headgear as no words can describe; which were made the more ludicrous by his anxious gravity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mary's mother bear eight children?", 'source': 'Although her mother bore eight children, only Mary and her younger sister Anne survived into adulthood.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did William III and II become the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694?', 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was her husband and first cousin?', 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': 'William III and II'}
{'question': 'Did the Glorious Revolution result in the deposition of her Roman Catholic father?', 'source': 'Mary, a Protestant, came to the thrones following the Glorious Revolution, which resulted in the deposition of her Roman Catholic father, James II and VII.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mary do?', 'source': 'She did, however, govern the realms alone when William was engaged in military campaigns abroad, proving herself to be a powerful, firm, and effective ruler.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did her mother bear?', 'source': 'Although her mother bore eight children, only Mary and her younger sister Anne survived into adulthood.', 'answer': 'eight children'}
{'question': 'Who was her sister?', 'source': "Although there was no evidence to support the allegation, Mary publicly challenged the boy's legitimacy, sending a pointed list of questions to her sister, Anne, regarding the circumstances of the birth.", 'answer': 'Anne'}
{'question': 'Who largely exercised its power alone?', 'source': 'Though she shared the post with her husband, she largely exercised its power alone.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "Do Popular histories usually refer to the joint reigns as those of ``William and Mary''?", 'source': "Popular histories usually refer to the joint reigns as those of ``William and Mary''.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her father take as his second wife the Catholic Mary of Modena?', 'source': "Mary's mother died in 1671; her father remarried in 1673, taking as his second wife the Catholic Mary of Modena, also known as Mary Beatrice d' Este.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she rule England as its Supreme Governor?', 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she very active in the Church of England?', 'source': 'She was very active in the Church of England, which she ruled as its Supreme Governor.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Duke of York assume that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants?', 'source': 'Pressured by Parliament, the Duke of York agreed to the marriage, falsely assuming that it would improve his popularity amongst Protestants.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she share?', 'source': 'Though she shared the post with her husband, she largely exercised its power alone.', 'answer': 'the post with her husband'}
{'question': 'Did her father remarry in 1673?', 'source': "Mary's mother died in 1671; her father remarried in 1673, taking as his second wife the Catholic Mary of Modena, also known as Mary Beatrice d' Este.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her husband and first cousin William III and II?', 'source': 'Mary reigned jointly with her husband and first cousin, William III and II, who became the sole ruler of both countries upon her death in 1694.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she largely exercise alone?', 'source': 'Though she shared the post with her husband, she largely exercised its power alone.', 'answer': 'its power'}
{'question': 'Did William prove herself to be a powerful, firm, and effective ruler?', 'source': 'She did, however, govern the realms alone when William was engaged in military campaigns abroad, proving herself to be a powerful, firm, and effective ruler.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did William cede most of her authority to her husband?', 'source': 'Mary, the blood sovereign, wielded less power than William during the parts of her reign when William remained in England, ceding most of her authority to her husband, though he heavily relied on her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her sister Anne?', 'source': "Although there was no evidence to support the allegation, Mary publicly challenged the boy's legitimacy, sending a pointed list of questions to her sister, Anne, regarding the circumstances of the birth.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her mother bear eight children?', 'source': 'Although her mother bore eight children, only Mary and her younger sister Anne survived into adulthood.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she share the post with her husband?', 'source': 'Though she shared the post with her husband, she largely exercised its power alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she do?', 'source': 'She did, however, govern the realms alone when William was engaged in military campaigns abroad, proving herself to be a powerful, firm, and effective ruler.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she largely exercise its power alone?', 'source': 'Though she shared the post with her husband, she largely exercised its power alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'Who was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was the corner in shadow?', 'source': 'The summer light struck into the corner brilliantly in the earlier part of the day; but, when the streets grew hot, the corner was in shadow, though not in shadow so remote but that you could see beyond it into a glare of brightness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do people in a dark room always do?', 'source': 'They spoke low, as people watching and waiting mostly do; as people in a dark room, watching and waiting for Lightning, always do.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does he never say a word of?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'of the true reason'}
{'question': 'How many letters was his last work?', 'source': 'Upon a corner stone in an angle of the wall, one prisoner, who seemed to have gone to execution, had cut as his last work, three letters.', 'answer': 'three letters'}
{'question': 'What do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': 'now'}
{'question': 'Did the hurry of footsteps coming and going become more and more rapid?', 'source': 'The footsteps were incessant, and the hurry of them became more and more rapid.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who _es make no stipulations?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Were hundreds sitting under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did they all look out?', 'source': 'When the tea-table was done with, they all moved to one of the windows, and looked out into the heavy twilight.', 'answer': 'into the heavy twilight'}
{'question': 'Had one prisoner written something?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did mysterious backs and ends of houses peep at them as they talked?', 'source': 'Mysterious backs and ends of houses peeped at them as they talked, and the plane-tree whispered to them in its own way above their heads.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was one prisoner's last work three letters?", 'source': 'Upon a corner stone in an angle of the wall, one prisoner, who seemed to have gone to execution, had cut as his last work, three letters.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was she not unfrequently the victim of?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': 'of this disorder'}
{'question': 'What is with another fit of the jerks upon her, and yet no Hundreds of people?', 'source': 'Tea-time, and Miss Pross making tea, with another fit of the jerks upon her, and yet no Hundreds of people.', 'answer': 'tea'}
{'question': 'Who is a woman of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who did Lucie recover so quickly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself so quickly, however, that Mr. Lorry had doubts of his business eye.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Who has imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who kept his glass replenished?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What are you a woman of?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': 'of business'}
{'question': "What did Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon have its weight in?", 'source': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon (deducting a mere trifle for this slight mistake) was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry, and had its weight in his good opinion of her.", 'answer': 'in his good opinion of her'}
{'question': 'What had the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro set going?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who told you it was a foolish fancy?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was it that whenever her original proposition was questioned?', 'source': 'It was characteristic of this lady (as of some other people before her time and since) that whenever her original proposition was questioned, she exaggerated it.', 'answer': 'characteristic of this lady'}
{'question': 'Who _es ask no questions?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What does he get up in?', 'source': 'Sometimes, he gets up in the dead of the night, and will be heard, by us overhead there, walking up and down, walking up and down, in his room.', 'answer': 'in the dead of the night'}
{'question': 'What revolved about her?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'everything'}
{'question': 'Who hurries to him?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who is my mind?', 'source': 'Yet, a doubt lurks in my mind, Miss Pross, whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him.', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'What are now intimate?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'so many little adornments'}
{'question': 'Do so many little adornments go walking up and down together in silence?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What walks up and down together?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'so many little adornments'}
{'question': 'Who went out under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Is Doctor Manette unquestionably innocent of any crime as so many little adornments are all well assured Mr. Lorry is?', 'source': 'To return to business:-- Is it not remarkable that Doctor Manette, unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is, should never touch upon that question?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would echoes of other steps that never came die away for good when they seemed close at hand?', 'source': 'Not only would the echoes die away, as though the steps had gone; but, echoes of other steps that never came would be heard in their stead, and would die away for good when they seemed close at hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who told me a curious thing when I was there?', 'source': "They told me a curious thing when I was there.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What is a doubt this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes Miss Pross that has led me to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': "to so many little adornments's present confidence"}
{'question': 'What did they go out under?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'under the plane-tree'}
{'question': 'Did Lucie recover himself almost instantly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself almost instantly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they all move to?', 'source': 'When the tea-table was done with, they all moved to one of the windows, and looked out into the heavy twilight.', 'answer': 'to one of the windows'}
{'question': 'Who had he hidden it away to keep it from?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'from the gaoler'}
{'question': 'Who did its revival in the floating whispers of his story, bring?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette received such patients here as his old reputation, and its revival in the floating whispers of his story, brought him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What are only impressive as we originate them?', 'source': 'Such whims are only impressive as we originate them, I think; they are not to be communicated.', 'answer': 'such whims'}
{'question': 'What went out under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had she ravaged?', 'source': "Miss Pross's friendship being of the thoroughly practical kind, she had ravaged Soho and the adjacent provinces, in search of impoverished French, who, tempted by shillings and half-crowns, would impart culinary mysteries to her.", 'answer': 'Soho and the adjacent provinces'}
{'question': 'What told me a curious thing when I was there?', 'source': "They told me a curious thing when I was there.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had it begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': 'of coming feet'}
{'question': 'Who will say with the fair daughter to who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross respond to Ladybird's pleasant face and pleasant efforts to please her?", 'source': "On this occasion, Miss Pross, responding to Ladybird's pleasant face and pleasant efforts to please her, unbent exceedingly; so the dinner was very pleasant, too.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What turned upon her?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'everything'}
{'question': 'Who did the Hundreds of people not present?', 'source': 'Still, the Hundreds of people did not present themselves.', 'answer': 'themselves'}
{'question': 'Was the dinner very pleasant?', 'source': "On this occasion, Miss Pross, responding to Ladybird's pleasant face and pleasant efforts to please her, unbent exceedingly; so the dinner was very pleasant, too.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was it a profounder remark than Mr. Lorry had looked for?', 'source': 'It was a profounder remark than Mr. Lorry had looked for.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was?', 'source': 'It was characteristic of this lady (as of some other people before her time and since) that whenever her original proposition was questioned, she exaggerated it.', 'answer': 'her original proposition'}
{'question': 'Was the tea-table done with?', 'source': 'When the tea-table was done with, they all moved to one of the windows, and looked out into the heavy twilight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had one prisoner hidden something else besides ` indeed away to keep from the gaoler?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did his loss of himself grow out of it besides?', 'source': 'Besides that, his loss of himself grew out of it.', 'answer': 'besides that'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross unbend exceedingly on this occasion?', 'source': "On this occasion, Miss Pross, responding to Ladybird's pleasant face and pleasant efforts to please her, unbent exceedingly; so the dinner was very pleasant, too.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the Hundreds of people not present?', 'source': 'Still, the Hundreds of people did not present themselves.', 'answer': 'themselves'}
{'question': 'Who had installed herself?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Were the curtains long and white?', 'source': 'The curtains were long and white, and some of the thunder-gusts that whirled into the corner, caught them up to the ceiling, and waved them like spectral wings.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did such times sit side by side?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did ends of houses talk?', 'source': 'Mysterious backs and ends of houses peeped at them as they talked, and the plane-tree whispered to them in its own way above their heads.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who did I tell it was a foolish fancy?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What had he written?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'something'}
{'question': 'What is it it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'this doubt and the uneasiness'}
{'question': 'Who recovered himself almost instantly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself almost instantly.', 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'What did they sit by side?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': 'side'}
{'question': 'Who instantly changes for the worse?', 'source': '``Touch that string, and he instantly changes for the worse.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they sit side by?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': 'by side'}
{'question': 'What did he show with rain-drops on it?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': 'the back of his hand'}
{'question': 'Had the unknown prisoner written?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, bring him otherwise into?', 'source': 'His scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, brought him otherwise into moderate request, and he earned as much as he wanted.', 'answer': 'into moderate request'}
{'question': 'What did he add?', 'source': 'He added the last words, after there had been a vivid flash which had shown him lounging in the window.', 'answer': 'the last words'}
{'question': 'What really is doubly and trebly hard to have crowds and multitudes of people turning up after him?', 'source': "But it really is doubly and trebly hard to have crowds and multitudes of people turning up after him (I could have forgiven him), to take Ladybird's affections away from me.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What were its acoustical properties?', 'source': 'It was such a curious corner in its acoustical properties, such a peculiar Ear of a place, that as Mr. Lorry stood at the open window, looking for the father and daughter whose steps he heard, he fancied they would never approach.', 'answer': 'such a peculiar Ear of a place'}
{'question': "Were these things within Mr. Jarvis Lorry's knowledge, thoughts, and notice?", 'source': "These things were within Mr. Jarvis Lorry's knowledge, thoughts, and notice, when he rang the door-bell of the tranquil house in the corner, on the fine Sunday afternoon.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do Lucie's manner and his look quite terrify them all?", 'source': 'His manner and his look quite terrified them all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What's plain enough why he may be?", 'source': "``It's plain enough, I should think, why he may be.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What could roar of rain that it stopped him be heard in?', 'source': 'It was the rush and roar of rain that he typified, and it stopped him, for no voice could be heard in it.', 'answer': 'in it'}
{'question': 'What did he show the back of his hand with on it?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': 'with rain-drops'}
{'question': 'What is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who is unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is?', 'source': 'To return to business:-- Is it not remarkable that Doctor Manette, unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is, should never touch upon that question?', 'answer': 'Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'Who were sitting under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What do I _ ask?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': 'no questions'}
{'question': 'What were they sitting under?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': 'under the plane-tree'}
{'question': 'What does he instantly change for?', 'source': '``Touch that string, and he instantly changes for the worse.', 'answer': 'for the worse'}
{'question': 'Who sat side by side?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who asked for it?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'When have I sometimes sat alone here, listening?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': 'of an evening'}
{'question': 'Was Miss Pross ready at the street door to receive them?', 'source': 'However, father and daughter did at last appear, and Miss Pross was ready at the street door to receive them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is Doctor Manette unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured?', 'source': 'To return to business:-- Is it not remarkable that Doctor Manette, unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is, should never touch upon that question?', 'answer': 'he is'}
{'question': 'What is Doctor Manette?', 'source': 'To return to business:-- Is it not remarkable that Doctor Manette, unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is, should never touch upon that question?', 'answer': 'unquestionably innocent of any crime as so many little adornments are all well assured Mr. Lorry is'}
{'question': 'What did they sit under?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'under the plane-tree'}
{'question': 'Who is it this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who is it this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes that has led me to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What do I _ make?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': 'no stipulations'}
{'question': 'What sat under the plane-tree?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who does she hurry to?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Who did Miss Pross have business relations many years ago with?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with me many years ago'}
{'question': 'What did I tell you was a foolish fancy?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did she keep replenished?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'his glass'}
{'question': 'Who has sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do they go walking up and down together in?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'in silence'}
{'question': 'What was very agreeable to trace the likeness?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who made me start?', 'source': 'There are large drops of rain falling, and they made me start.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who go walking up and down together in silence?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did everything revolve about?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'about her'}
{'question': 'What should they sit there in?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': 'in the air'}
{'question': 'What do I see them-- by?', 'source': "There is a great crowd bearing down upon us, Miss Manette, and I see them-- by the Lightning.''", 'answer': 'by the Lightning'}
{'question': 'Who did his scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, bring otherwise into moderate request?', 'source': 'His scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, brought him otherwise into moderate request, and he earned as much as he wanted.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What have I made out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': 'the echoes'}
{'question': 'What quite terrified them all?', 'source': 'His manner and his look quite terrified them all.', 'answer': "Lucie's manner and his look"}
{'question': 'What made me start?', 'source': 'There are large drops of rain falling, and they made me start.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Would impoverished French impart culinary mysteries to her?', 'source': "Miss Pross's friendship being of the thoroughly practical kind, she had ravaged Soho and the adjacent provinces, in search of impoverished French, who, tempted by shillings and half-crowns, would impart culinary mysteries to her.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they sit with open?', 'source': 'The night was so very sultry, that although they sat with doors and windows open, they were overpowered by heat.', 'answer': 'with doors and windows'}
{'question': 'Did she carry the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I tell you it was?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'a foolish fancy'}
{'question': 'Do now not be angry at Miss Pross asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did everything turn upon?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': 'upon her'}
{'question': 'Who did Lucie recover almost instantly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself almost instantly.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What sat with doors and windows open?', 'source': 'The night was so very sultry, that although they sat with doors and windows open, they were overpowered by heat.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Do so many little adornments go on together?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had she installed?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': 'herself'}
{'question': 'Did the storm break?', 'source': 'There was a great hurry in the streets of people speeding away to get shelter before the storm broke; the wonderful corner for echoes resounded with the echoes of footsteps coming and going, yet not a footstep was there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who should sit there in the air?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did they make start?', 'source': 'There are large drops of rain falling, and they made me start.', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who was the night myself?', 'source': "``I never see the night myself, master-- nor yet I do not expect to-- what would do that,'' answered Jerry.", 'answer': 'master'}
{'question': 'Did the phrase walk up and down?', 'source': "Notwithstanding Miss Pross's denial of her own imagination, there was a perception of the pain of being monotonously haunted by one sad idea, in her repetition of the phrase, walking up and down, which testified to her possessing such a thing.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I made the echoes out to be the echoes of?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': 'of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives'}
{'question': 'What is it this doubt and the uneasiness sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What have I made the echoes out to be?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': 'the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives'}
{'question': "What's a dreadful remembrance?", 'source': "It's a dreadful remembrance.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What had he hidden it away to keep from the gaoler?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What had he hidden away to keep it from the gaoler?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say, ``and that was my brother Solomon''?", 'source': "``There never was, nor will be, but one man worthy of Ladybird,'' said Miss Pross; ``and that was my brother Solomon, if he had not made a mistake in life.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does he never say?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'a word of the true reason'}
{'question': 'Had the steps gone?', 'source': 'Not only would the echoes die away, as though the steps had gone; but, echoes of other steps that never came would be heard in their stead, and would die away for good when they seemed close at hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What should sit there in the air?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did he show the back of his hand with rain-drops on?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': 'on it'}
{'question': 'Who have seen enough of it?', 'source': "We have seen enough of it, to know that it teems with interest; little more.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What leave it alone?', 'source': 'Better leave it alone.', 'answer': 'Better'}
{'question': 'What did you ask for?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': 'What leave that string alone?', 'source': 'Better leave it alone.', 'answer': 'Better'}
{'question': 'Who is us?', 'source': "``Are all these footsteps destined to come to all of us, Miss Manette, or are we to divide them among us?''", 'answer': 'Miss Manette'}
{'question': 'Did it proceed from Miss Pross?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are such whims not to be communicated?', 'source': 'Such whims are only impressive as we originate them, I think; they are not to be communicated.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the streets grow hot?', 'source': 'The summer light struck into the corner brilliantly in the earlier part of the day; but, when the streets grew hot, the corner was in shadow, though not in shadow so remote but that you could see beyond it into a glare of brightness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'to our present confidence'}
{'question': 'What did his loss of himself grow out of besides that?', 'source': 'Besides that, his loss of himself grew out of it.', 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': "Who supposes, ``It was not ending it''?", 'source': '``It was not ending it, I suppose?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Had the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro set where the Doctor lived going?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he recover so quickly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself so quickly, however, that Mr. Lorry had doubts of his business eye.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'When was it?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': 'an oppressive day'}
{'question': 'What did he show the back of with rain-drops on it?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': 'of his hand'}
{'question': 'Was every stone of its inner wall covered by inscriptions which had been carved by prisoners-- dates, names, complaints, and prayers?', 'source': 'Every stone of its inner wall was covered by inscriptions which had been carved by prisoners-- dates, names, complaints, and prayers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was his last work?', 'source': 'Upon a corner stone in an angle of the wall, one prisoner, who seemed to have gone to execution, had cut as his last work, three letters.', 'answer': 'three letters'}
{'question': "Did the front windows of the Doctor's lodgings command a pleasant little vista of street that had a congenial air of retirement on it?", 'source': "There was no way through it, and the front windows of the Doctor's lodgings commanded a pleasant little vista of street that had a congenial air of retirement on it.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is at home myself?', 'source': "``As I am at home myself,'' said Mr. Lorry, ``I 'll go upstairs.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who is it?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'Who finds it best not to hint at it to him?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Had he first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who am I?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': 'a mere dull man of business'}
{'question': 'What do _ I _ began?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Pross shake her head?', 'source': "``Ca not be helped,'' said Miss Pross, shaking her head.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who may know what it is?', 'source': "We may know what it is.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Who does a doubt lurk in my mind for?', 'source': 'Yet, a doubt lurks in my mind, Miss Pross, whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him.', 'answer': 'whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him'}
{'question': 'Who are you?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': 'a woman of business'}
{'question': 'Was the night so very sultry?', 'source': 'The night was so very sultry, that although they sat with doors and windows open, they were overpowered by heat.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she call?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who was me?', 'source': "Believe me, Miss Pross, I do not approach the topic with you, out of curiosity, but out of zealous interest.''", 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'What did he have with me many years ago?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'business relations'}
{'question': 'What were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French?', 'source': 'Her dinners, of a very modest quality, were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French, that nothing could be better.', 'answer': 'her dinners'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say ``I do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird''?", 'source': "``I do not want dozens of people who are not at all worthy of Ladybird, to come here looking after her,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Darnay sit beside her?', 'source': 'Lucie sat by her father; Darnay sat beside her; Carton leaned against a window.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who I am at home?', 'source': "``As I am at home myself,'' said Mr. Lorry, ``I 'll go upstairs.''", 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'Was it suggested that the letters were not initials, but the complete word at length?', 'source': 'At length, it was suggested that the letters were not initials, but the complete word, DIG.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were her dinners so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in French?', 'source': 'Her dinners, of a very modest quality, were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French, that nothing could be better.', 'answer': 'in their contrivances, half English and half'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Darnay present himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were her dinners of?', 'source': 'Her dinners, of a very modest quality, were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French, that nothing could be better.', 'answer': 'of a very modest quality'}
{'question': "What does it's?", 'source': "It's a dreadful remembrance.", 'answer': 'a dreadful remembrance'}
{'question': "Was Mr. Lorry with meekness; ``how are you?''?", 'source': "``I am pretty well, I thank you,'' answered Mr. Lorry, with meekness; ``how are you?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have we seen enough of?', 'source': "We have seen enough of it, to know that it teems with interest; little more.''", 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'Did Doctor Manette receive him kindly?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette received him kindly, and so did Lucie.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had set it going?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': 'the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro'}
{'question': 'What is a doubt this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes Miss Pross to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': "that has led me to so many little adornments's present confidence"}
{'question': 'Does so many little adornments walk up and down together?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he make?', 'source': 'Mr. Carton had lounged in, but he made only Two.', 'answer': 'only Two'}
{'question': 'Who does she find it best not to hint at it to?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What did she appear to have innately derived from that ability to make much of little means is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': 'from it'}
{'question': 'Are so many little adornments now intimate?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will not say with me?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'Miss Pross'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross's loss of himself grow out of that besides that?", 'source': 'Besides that, his loss of himself grew out of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who now shall have hundreds of people pretty soon?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, rising to break up the conference; ``and now we shall have hundreds of people pretty soon!''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What _ began it?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': '_ I'}
{'question': 'Was it a cool spot a wonderful place for echoes, and a very harbor from the raging streets?', 'source': 'It was a cool spot, staid but cheerful, a wonderful place for echoes, and a very harbor from the raging streets.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who called it?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did Lucie sit by her father?', 'source': 'Lucie sat by her father; Darnay sat beside her; Carton leaned against a window.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will Miss Pross not say with?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with me'}
{'question': 'Does a doubt lurk in my mind whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him?', 'source': 'Yet, a doubt lurks in my mind, Miss Pross, whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has yielded myself to it?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What shall now we have hundreds of pretty soon?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, rising to break up the conference; ``and now we shall have hundreds of people pretty soon!''", 'answer': 'of people'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry shake his head; using that important part of himself as a sort of fairy cloak that would fit anything?', 'source': 'Not seeing with precision what was very hard, Mr. Lorry shook his head; using that important part of himself as a sort of fairy cloak that would fit anything.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does she find it best not to hint at to him?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'at it'}
{'question': 'Was the quiet street-corner the sunny part of his life?', 'source': "After several relapses into business-absorption, Mr. Lorry had become the Doctor's friend, and the quiet street-corner was the sunny part of his life.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she appear to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means is?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': 'one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics'}
{'question': 'What does she find best not to hint at it to him?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who have her love and company brought to himself?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who did he have business relations many years ago with?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with me many years ago'}
{'question': 'Had she ravaged Soho and the adjacent provinces?', 'source': "Miss Pross's friendship being of the thoroughly practical kind, she had ravaged Soho and the adjacent provinces, in search of impoverished French, who, tempted by shillings and half-crowns, would impart culinary mysteries to her.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry answer ``I am pretty well''?", 'source': "``I am pretty well, I thank you,'' answered Mr. Lorry, with meekness; ``how are you?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who have her love and company brought him to?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': 'What grew out of it besides that?', 'source': 'Besides that, his loss of himself grew out of it.', 'answer': 'his loss of himself'}
{'question': 'What did she appear to have innately derived from it?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': 'that ability to make much of little means is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon have its weight in his good opinion of her?", 'source': "Miss Pross's fidelity of belief in Solomon (deducting a mere trifle for this slight mistake) was quite a serious matter with Mr. Lorry, and had its weight in his good opinion of her.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does Mr. Lorry pause in his looking about?', 'source': "``I wonder,'' said Mr. Lorry, pausing in his looking about, ``that he keeps that reminder of his sufferings about him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the phrase testify to her possessing such a thing?', 'source': "Notwithstanding Miss Pross's denial of her own imagination, there was a perception of the pain of being monotonously haunted by one sad idea, in her repetition of the phrase, walking up and down, which testified to her possessing such a thing.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it suggested at length?', 'source': 'At length, it was suggested that the letters were not initials, but the complete word, DIG.', 'answer': 'that the letters were not initials, but the complete word'}
{'question': 'Who spoke low?', 'source': 'They spoke low, as people watching and waiting mostly do; as people in a dark room, watching and waiting for Lightning, always do.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did he recover almost instantly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself almost instantly.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Did they all look out into the heavy twilight?', 'source': 'When the tea-table was done with, they all moved to one of the windows, and looked out into the heavy twilight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Carton say, ``It comes surely''?", 'source': "``It comes surely,'' said Carton.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had the Doctor's daughter known nothing of the country of her birth?", 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry always retain Jerry for this service: though it was usually performed a good two hours earlier?', 'source': 'There were solitary patches of road on the way between Soho and Clerkenwell, and Mr. Lorry, mindful of foot-pads, always retained Jerry for this service: though it was usually performed a good two hours earlier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was such a curious corner in its acoustical properties, such a peculiar Ear of a place, that as Mr. Lorry stood at the open window, looking for the father and daughter whose steps he heard, he fancied they would never approach.', 'answer': 'such a curious corner in its acoustical properties'}
{'question': 'Who have I yielded to it?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'Do _ do _ dozens come for that purpose?', 'source': "'' _ Do _ dozens come for that purpose?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have brought him to himself?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'her love and company'}
{'question': 'Has Ladybird learned to know then that his mind is walking up and down, walking up and down?', 'source': 'Ladybird has learned to know then that his mind is walking up and down, walking up and down, in his old prison.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do his manner and his look quite terrify?', 'source': 'His manner and his look quite terrified them all.', 'answer': 'them all'}
{'question': 'Who will I say with to whom he is so devotedly attached?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with the fair daughter'}
{'question': 'What have I yielded myself to?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': 'to it'}
{'question': "Did Miss Pross say and it's really very hard?", 'source': "And it's really very hard,'' said Miss Pross.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a memorable storm of thunder and lightning break with that sweep of water?', 'source': "A memorable storm of thunder and lightning broke with that sweep of water, and there was not a moment's interval in crash, and fire, and rain, until after the moon rose at midnight.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my mind Miss Pross?', 'source': 'Yet, a doubt lurks in my mind, Miss Pross, whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who yes is very much put out?', 'source': "Yes, I am very much put out.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Does he get up in the dead of the night?', 'source': 'Sometimes, he gets up in the dead of the night, and will be heard, by us overhead there, walking up and down, walking up and down, in his room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the resemblance between him and Lucie very strong at such times?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is us Miss Manette?', 'source': "``Are all these footsteps destined to come to all of us, Miss Manette, or are we to divide them among us?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is a doubt this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes Miss Pross that has led me to so many little adornments's present confidence?", 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it Miss Pross?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will seem nothing to you?', 'source': '``It will seem nothing to you.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What do _ I _?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': 'began it'}
{'question': 'Did they all move to one of the windows?', 'source': 'When the tea-table was done with, they all moved to one of the windows, and looked out into the heavy twilight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I tell you it was a foolish fancy?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has been alone?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Were its acoustical properties such a peculiar Ear of a place?', 'source': 'It was such a curious corner in its acoustical properties, such a peculiar Ear of a place, that as Mr. Lorry stood at the open window, looking for the father and daughter whose steps he heard, he fancied they would never approach.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was me Miss Pross?', 'source': "Believe me, Miss Pross, I do not approach the topic with you, out of curiosity, but out of zealous interest.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': 'only One'}
{'question': 'What was it characteristic of this lady?', 'source': 'It was characteristic of this lady (as of some other people before her time and since) that whenever her original proposition was questioned, she exaggerated it.', 'answer': 'that whenever her original proposition was questioned'}
{'question': 'Who will it seem nothing to?', 'source': '``It will seem nothing to you.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Am I a mere dull man of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was she?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': 'not unfrequently the victim of this disorder'}
{'question': 'Who does not know?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did they tell me a curious thing when I was there?', 'source': "They told me a curious thing when I was there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are not to be communicated?', 'source': 'Such whims are only impressive as we originate them, I think; they are not to be communicated.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who go on together?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who will I say with to who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with the fair daughter'}
{'question': 'Did they go out under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they done with some very poor instrument, and hurriedly, with an unsteady hand?', 'source': 'They were done with some very poor instrument, and hurriedly, with an unsteady hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are now intimate?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What shall now we have pretty soon?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, rising to break up the conference; ``and now we shall have hundreds of people pretty soon!''", 'answer': 'hundreds of people'}
{'question': 'What did she appear to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means is one of?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': 'of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics'}
{'question': 'What may we know?', 'source': "We may know what it is.''", 'answer': 'what it is'}
{'question': 'Had it begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he show the back of his hand with rain-drops on it?', 'source': 'Rain was really falling in large drops, and he showed the back of his hand with rain-drops on it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he never say a word of the true reason?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been talking all day?', 'source': 'He had been talking all day, on many subjects, and with unusual vivacity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do now not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What brought him?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette received such patients here as his old reputation, and its revival in the floating whispers of his story, brought him.', 'answer': 'its revival in the floating whispers of his story,'}
{'question': 'Was it characteristic of this lady that whenever her original proposition was questioned?', 'source': 'It was characteristic of this lady (as of some other people before her time and since) that whenever her original proposition was questioned, she exaggerated it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had better go in?', 'source': "We had better go in.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Did they sit with doors and windows open?', 'source': 'The night was so very sultry, that although they sat with doors and windows open, they were overpowered by heat.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were these only the exceptions required to prove the rule that the sparrows in the plane-tree behind the house, and the echoes in the corner before it, had their own way from Sunday morning unto Saturday night?', 'source': 'These, however, were only the exceptions required to prove the rule that the sparrows in the plane-tree behind the house, and the echoes in the corner before it, had their own way from Sunday morning unto Saturday night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him?', 'source': 'Yet, a doubt lurks in my mind, Miss Pross, whether it is good for Doctor Manette to have that suppression always shut up within him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I _ make no stipulations?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it an oppressive day?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he written something?', 'source': "What the unknown prisoner had written will never be read, but he had written something, and hidden it away to keep it from the gaoler.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has fancied?', 'source': "``Sometimes, I have sat here of an evening, until I have fancied-- but even the shade of a foolish fancy makes me shudder to-night, when all is so black and solemn--''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did the hurry of them become more and more rapid?', 'source': 'The footsteps were incessant, and the hurry of them became more and more rapid.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were her dinners of a very modest quality?', 'source': 'Her dinners, of a very modest quality, were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French, that nothing could be better.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did everything revolve about her?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro set it going?', 'source': 'The corner has been mentioned as a wonderful corner for echoes; it had begun to echo so resoundingly to the tread of coming feet, that it seemed as though the very mention of that weary pacing to and fro had set it going.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could roar of rain that he typified be heard in it?', 'source': 'It was the rush and roar of rain that he typified, and it stopped him, for no voice could be heard in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she not unfrequently the victim of this disorder?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it such a curious corner in its acoustical properties?', 'source': 'It was such a curious corner in its acoustical properties, such a peculiar Ear of a place, that as Mr. Lorry stood at the open window, looking for the father and daughter whose steps he heard, he fancied they would never approach.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he add the last words?', 'source': 'He added the last words, after there had been a vivid flash which had shown him lounging in the window.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they sit under the plane-tree?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I see them-- by the Lightning?', 'source': "There is a great crowd bearing down upon us, Miss Manette, and I see them-- by the Lightning.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could roar of rain that it stopped him be heard in it?', 'source': 'It was the rush and roar of rain that he typified, and it stopped him, for no voice could be heard in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I _ ask no questions?', 'source': '_ I _ ask no questions and make no stipulations.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they sitting under the plane-tree?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he instantly change for the worse?', 'source': '``Touch that string, and he instantly changes for the worse.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did its revival in the floating whispers of his story, bring him?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette received such patients here as his old reputation, and its revival in the floating whispers of his story, brought him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did everything turn upon her?', 'source': 'As everything turned upon her, and revolved about her, they went out under the plane-tree, and she carried the wine down for the special benefit of Mr. Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you a woman of business?', 'source': "``Now do not be angry at my asking all these questions; because I am a mere dull man of business, and you are a woman of business.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall now we have hundreds of people pretty soon?', 'source': "said Miss Pross, rising to break up the conference; ``and now we shall have hundreds of people pretty soon!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they speak low?', 'source': 'They spoke low, as people watching and waiting mostly do; as people in a dark room, watching and waiting for Lightning, always do.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it very agreeable to trace the likeness?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who walks up and down together?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who is composed?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What may he never feel?', 'source': 'Not knowing how he lost himself, or how he recovered himself, he may never feel certain of not losing himself again.', 'answer': 'certain of not losing himself again'}
{'question': 'Who will be heard?', 'source': 'Sometimes, he gets up in the dead of the night, and will be heard, by us overhead there, walking up and down, walking up and down, in his room.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Do they go walking up and down together in silence?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she appear to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics?', 'source': "Although the Doctor's daughter had known nothing of the country of her birth, she appeared to have innately derived from it that ability to make much of little means, which is one of its most useful and most agreeable characteristics.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will I not say with?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': 'with me'}
{'question': 'Have I sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I tell you?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': 'it was a foolish fancy'}
{'question': 'What will it seem to you?', 'source': '``It will seem nothing to you.', 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': 'Should they sit there in the air?', 'source': 'It was an oppressive day, and, after dinner, Lucie proposed that the wine should be carried out under the plane-tree, and they should sit there in the air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will he be heard?', 'source': 'Sometimes, he gets up in the dead of the night, and will be heard, by us overhead there, walking up and down, walking up and down, in his room.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's a dreadful remembrance?", 'source': "It's a dreadful remembrance.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are such whims only impressive as we originate them?', 'source': 'Such whims are only impressive as we originate them, I think; they are not to be communicated.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is tea with another fit of the jerks upon her, and yet no Hundreds of people?', 'source': 'Tea-time, and Miss Pross making tea, with another fit of the jerks upon her, and yet no Hundreds of people.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it the rush?', 'source': 'It was the rush and roar of rain that he typified, and it stopped him, for no voice could be heard in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make only Two?', 'source': 'Mr. Carton had lounged in, but he made only Two.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they sit side by side?', 'source': 'The resemblance between him and Lucie was very strong at such times, and as they sat side by side, she leaning on his shoulder, and he resting his arm on the back of her chair, it was very agreeable to trace the likeness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Better leave it alone?', 'source': 'Better leave it alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, bring him otherwise into moderate request?', 'source': 'His scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, brought him otherwise into moderate request, and he earned as much as he wanted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she keep his glass replenished?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the night myself master?', 'source': "``I never see the night myself, master-- nor yet I do not expect to-- what would do that,'' answered Jerry.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Better leave that string alone?', 'source': 'Better leave it alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she find it best not to hint at it to him?', 'source': 'But he never says a word of the true reason of his restlessness, to her, and she finds it best not to hint at it to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his last work three letters?', 'source': 'Upon a corner stone in an angle of the wall, one prisoner, who seemed to have gone to execution, had cut as his last work, three letters.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have suddenly started up?', 'source': 'He had suddenly started up, with his hand to his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have business relations with me many years ago?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he since improved?', 'source': 'It proceeded from Miss Pross, the wild red woman, strong of hand, whose acquaintance he had first made at the Royal George Hotel at Dover, and had since improved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his loss of himself grow out of it besides that?', 'source': 'Besides that, his loss of himself grew out of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives?', 'source': "I have sometimes sat alone here of an evening, listening, until I have made the echoes out to be the echoes of all the footsteps that are coming by-and-bye into our lives.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is Doctor Manette unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is?', 'source': 'To return to business:-- Is it not remarkable that Doctor Manette, unquestionably innocent of any crime as we are all well assured he is, should never touch upon that question?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she hurry to him?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she installed herself?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Why he may be does it's plain enough?", 'source': "``It's plain enough, I should think, why he may be.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he add again?', 'source': 'he added again, after a peal of thunder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'d you have thought!", 'source': "You 'd have thought!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am yes I very much put out?', 'source': "Yes, I am very much put out.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her original proposition?', 'source': 'It was characteristic of this lady (as of some other people before her time and since) that whenever her original proposition was questioned, she exaggerated it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'that has led me to our present confidence'}
{'question': 'Was he only One?', 'source': 'Mr. Darnay presented himself while they were sitting under the plane-tree, but he was only One.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I say with the fair daughter to who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did you ask for it?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does my father's?", 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they make me start?', 'source': 'There are large drops of rain falling, and they made me start.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should I think?', 'source': "That alone would not make the subject pleasant, I should think.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do I suppose, ``It was not ending it''?", 'source': '``It was not ending it, I suppose?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do his manner and his look quite terrify them all?', 'source': 'His manner and his look quite terrified them all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is a doubt this doubt and the uneasiness to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': "it sometimes causes Miss Pross that has led me to so many little adornments's present confidence"}
{'question': 'Did he recover himself so quickly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself so quickly, however, that Mr. Lorry had doubts of his business eye.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it usually performed a good two hours earlier?', 'source': 'There were solitary patches of road on the way between Soho and Clerkenwell, and Mr. Lorry, mindful of foot-pads, always retained Jerry for this service: though it was usually performed a good two hours earlier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do _ I _ began it?', 'source': "'' _ I _ began it, Miss Pross?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he earn as much as he wanted?', 'source': 'His scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, brought him otherwise into moderate request, and he earned as much as he wanted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I been alone?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May he never feel certain of not losing himself again?', 'source': 'Not knowing how he lost himself, or how he recovered himself, he may never feel certain of not losing himself again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was this service usually performed a good two hours earlier?', 'source': 'There were solitary patches of road on the way between Soho and Clerkenwell, and Mr. Lorry, mindful of foot-pads, always retained Jerry for this service: though it was usually performed a good two hours earlier.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do they go on together?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she call it?', 'source': "She was not unfrequently the victim of this disorder, and she called it, in familiar conversation, ``a fit of the jerks.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are they not to be communicated?', 'source': 'Such whims are only impressive as we originate them, I think; they are not to be communicated.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'I am at home myself?', 'source': "``As I am at home myself,'' said Mr. Lorry, ``I 'll go upstairs.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not know?', 'source': '``I do not know, Mr. Darnay; I told you it was a foolish fancy, but you asked for it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have her love and company brought him to himself?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have we seen enough of it?', 'source': "We have seen enough of it, to know that it teems with interest; little more.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it really doubly and trebly hard to have crowds and multitudes of people turning up after him?', 'source': "But it really is doubly and trebly hard to have crowds and multitudes of people turning up after him (I could have forgiven him), to take Ladybird's affections away from me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we now intimate?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had we better go in?', 'source': "We had better go in.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will it seem nothing to you?', 'source': '``It will seem nothing to you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I yielded myself to it?', 'source': "When I have yielded myself to it, I have been alone, and then I have imagined them the footsteps of the people who are to come into my life, and my father's.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they talk?', 'source': "She had installed herself, some time before, as Mr. Lorry's cup-bearer; and while they sat under the plane-tree, talking, she kept his glass replenished.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were her dinners so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French?', 'source': 'Her dinners, of a very modest quality, were so well cooked and so well served, and so neat in their contrivances, half English and half French, that nothing could be better.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May we know what it is?', 'source': "We may know what it is.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I fancied?', 'source': "``Sometimes, I have sat here of an evening, until I have fancied-- but even the shade of a foolish fancy makes me shudder to-night, when all is so black and solemn--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he want?', 'source': 'His scientific knowledge, and his vigilance and skill in conducting ingenious experiments, brought him otherwise into moderate request, and he earned as much as he wanted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it this doubt and the uneasiness to?', 'source': "Indeed, it is this doubt and the uneasiness it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence.''", 'answer': 'it sometimes causes me that has led me to our present confidence'}
{'question': 'Does they walk up and down together?', 'source': "In silence they go walking up and down together, walking up and down together, till her love and company have brought him to himself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I not say with me?', 'source': 'I will not say with me, though he had business relations with me many years ago, and we are now intimate; I will say with the fair daughter to whom he is so devotedly attached, and who is so devotedly attached to him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May he be?', 'source': "``It's plain enough, I should think, why he may be.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he recover himself almost instantly?', 'source': 'He recovered himself almost instantly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he composed?', 'source': 'She hurries to him, and they go on together, walking up and down, walking up and down, until he is composed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he call with to come?', 'source': 'That, he called with confidence on the jury to come and do likewise.', 'answer': 'with confidence on the jury'}
{'question': "What's?", 'source': "No business of anybody's.", 'answer': 'no business of anybody'}
{'question': 'What would he have that the wigged gentleman with before him?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'with the papers'}
{'question': 'Did the jury turn to consider?', 'source': 'And now, the jury turned to consider, and the great flies swarmed again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was much sympathy with her father?', 'source': 'There was much commiseration for her as she was removed, and much sympathy with her father.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did yes Mr. have?', 'source': 'Yes, he had.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the father and daughter sit down together?', 'source': 'Mr. Attorney-General sat down, and the father and daughter sat down together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who could no longer cherish in his bosom?', 'source': "That, he had been the prisoner's friend, but, at once in an auspicious and an evil hour detecting his infamy, had resolved to immolate the traitor he could no longer cherish in his bosom, on the sacred altar of his country.", 'answer': 'this patriot'}
{'question': 'Did my Lord inquire of Mr. Stryver for treason?', 'source': "My Lord inquired of Mr. Stryver (the prisoner's counsel), whether they were next to try Mr. Carton (name of my learned friend) for treason?", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the jury turned back?', 'source': 'As he passed out, the jury, who had turned back and paused a moment, spoke, through their foreman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would the proof go back five years?', 'source': 'That, the proof would go back five years, and would show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the unimpeachable patriot toned down again?', 'source': 'When toned down again, the unimpeachable patriot appeared in the witness-box.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the blue-flies buzz again?', 'source': 'The blue-flies buzzed again, and Mr. Attorney-General called Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will get to Temple Bar long before I can?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the jury speak?', 'source': 'As he passed out, the jury, who had turned back and paused a moment, spoke, through their foreman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had engaged him?', 'source': 'He had asked the prisoner, aboard the Calais packet, if he wanted a handy fellow, and the prisoner had engaged him.', 'answer': 'the prisoner'}
{'question': "What did he say: ``Answer the questions make no remark upon them''?", 'source': "The plaintive tone of her compassion merged into the less musical voice of the Judge, as he said something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you, and make no remark upon them.''", 'answer': 'something fiercely'}
{'question': 'What did his efforts to control and steady his breathing shake from which the color rushed to his heart?', 'source': 'His hurried right hand parcelled out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden; and his efforts to control and steady his breathing shook the lips from which the color rushed to his heart.', 'answer': 'the lips'}
{'question': 'What sir!', 'source': '``Here, sir!', 'answer': 'here'}
{'question': 'What did it begin to be rumored a long while?', 'source': 'It began to be rumored that the jury would be out a long while.', 'answer': 'that the jury would be out'}
{'question': 'Who did not call it a particularly curious coincidence?', 'source': 'He did not call it a particularly curious coincidence; most coincidences were curious.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is your native country?', 'source': "``Has it been your misfortune to undergo a long imprisonment, without trial, or even accusation, in your native country, Doctor Manette?''", 'answer': 'Doctor Manette'}
{'question': 'When would the proof show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans?', 'source': 'That, the proof would go back five years, and would show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans.', 'answer': 'within a few weeks'}
{'question': 'Who thinks their withdrawing is in your favor?', 'source': "But I think their withdrawing is in your favor.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he begin to keep upon him?', 'source': 'He began to have suspicions of the prisoner, and to keep an eye upon him, soon afterwards.', 'answer': 'an eye'}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner sit down?', 'source': 'The spectators dropped off to get refreshment, and the prisoner withdrew to the back of the dock, and sat down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner come on board?', 'source': "``When the prisoner came on board, he noticed that my father,'' turning her eyes lovingly to him as he stood beside her, ``was much fatigued and in a very weak state of health.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are here?', 'source': "They are here.''", 'answer': 'a'}
{'question': 'Who did my Lord retire?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Had he seen the prisoner show these identical lists to French gentlemen at Calais, and similar lists to French gentlemen at Calais and Boulogne?', 'source': 'He had seen the prisoner show these identical lists to French gentlemen at Calais, and similar lists to French gentlemen, both at Calais and Boulogne.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did my Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lie aside?', 'source': 'My Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lay aside his wig, and giving no very gracious consent, the likeness became much more remarkable.', 'answer': 'his wig'}
{'question': 'Who followed him?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': 'Jerry'}
{'question': 'Who was a true Briton?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did my Lord show that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': 'some surprise'}
{'question': "What's the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest?", 'source': "``It's the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who do ask that?', 'source': '``I do ask it.', 'answer': 'Mr. Carton'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Cruncher add, I 'd hold half a guinea that _ he _ do not get no law-work to do?", 'source': "Mr. Cruncher made the observation to his next neighbor, and added, ``I 'd hold half a guinea that _ he _ do not get no law-work to do.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were french gentlemen both?', 'source': 'He had seen the prisoner show these identical lists to French gentlemen at Calais, and similar lists to French gentlemen, both at Calais and Boulogne.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the next pause the counsel?', 'source': 'Opening this piece of paper in the next pause, the counsel looked with great attention and curiosity at the prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had become familiar to me?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What no.?', 'source': 'Oh dear no. .', 'answer': 'dear'}
{'question': 'Was the weather stormy?', 'source': "The weather was stormy, and the passage long and rough, and I lay on a sofa, almost from shore to shore.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have you seen the worst of?', 'source': "You have seen the worst of her agitation.''", 'answer': 'of her agitation'}
{'question': 'What pauses when she stopped for the Judge to write it down, watched its effect upon the counsel for and against?', 'source': 'Her forehead was painfully anxious and intent as she gave this evidence, and, in the pauses when she stopped for the Judge to write it down, watched its effect upon the counsel for and against.', 'answer': 'intent as she gave this evidence'}
{'question': 'Does the great fly swarmed again?', 'source': 'And now, the jury turned to consider, and the great flies swarmed again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is my learned friend there?', 'source': "``Look well upon that gentleman, my learned friend there,'' pointing to him who had tossed the paper over, ``and then look well upon the prisoner.", 'answer': 'the gentleman'}
{'question': 'Who was it certain had?', 'source': 'That, it was certain the prisoner had, for longer than that, been in the habit of passing and repassing between France and England, on secret business of which he could give no honest account.', 'answer': 'the prisoner'}
{'question': 'Who was kind, and good, and useful to my father?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the Attorney-General cease?', 'source': 'When the Attorney-General ceased, a buzz arose in the court as if a cloud of great blue-flies were swarming about the prisoner, in anticipation of what he was soon to become.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was that this correspondence with the public enemy certain?', 'source': 'That, it was certain the prisoner had, for longer than that, been in the habit of passing and repassing between France and England, on secret business of which he could give no honest account.', 'answer': 'the prisoner had'}
{'question': "Does no business of anybody's?", 'source': "No business of anybody's.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who wants you to take the verdict back to the bank?', 'source': 'Do not be a moment behind them, for I want you to take the verdict back to the bank.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did ever kick downstairs?', 'source': 'Ever kicked downstairs?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I lie on?', 'source': "The weather was stormy, and the passage long and rough, and I lay on a sofa, almost from shore to shore.''", 'answer': 'on a sofa'}
{'question': 'What did he deem my Lord necessary?', 'source': "Mr. Attorney-General now signified to my Lord, that he deemed it necessary, as a matter of precaution and form, to call the young lady's father, Doctor Manette.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he hope there were?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': 'many like him'}
{'question': 'What is a blank, from some time time-- when I employed myself?', 'source': 'My mind is a blank, from some time-- I cannot even say what time-- when I employed myself, in my captivity, in making shoes, to the time when I found myself living in London with my dear daughter here.', 'answer': 'my mind'}
{'question': 'Who had some papers been handed about among?', 'source': "``Some papers had been handed about among them, but I do not know what papers.''", 'answer': 'among them'}
{'question': 'Who would this patriot be produced before?', 'source': 'That, this patriot would be produced before them.', 'answer': 'before them'}
{'question': 'What will not do for a respectable bank gentleman like you?', 'source': "It will not do for a respectable bank gentleman like you, to be seen speaking to him publicly, you know.''", 'answer': 'the better for being out of court'}
{'question': 'Who would Mr. have modestly withdrawn?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What might he take him backwards and forwards between for a long time to come?', 'source': "He said that this business had, within a few days, taken him to France, and might, at intervals, take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come.''", 'answer': 'between France and England'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Lorry gone out when the young lady and her father went out?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry, who had gone out when the young lady and her father went out, now reappeared, and beckoned to Jerry: who, in the slackened interest, could easily get near him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is quite unable even to say how she had become familiar?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do ever live by cheating at play?', 'source': 'Ever live by cheating at play?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had I made a bed for him on?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'on the deck near the cabin steps'}
{'question': 'Was the prisoner a very slight one?', 'source': 'Was not this intimacy with the prisoner, in reality a very slight one, forced upon the prisoner in coaches, inns, and packets?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did he express for my father's state?", 'source': "He expressed great gentleness and kindness for my father's state, and I am sure he felt it.", 'answer': 'great gentleness and kindness'}
{'question': 'What had some papers been handed about among?', 'source': "``Some papers had been handed about among them, but I do not know what papers.''", 'answer': 'among them'}
{'question': 'Who loved his country?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Have Might been?', 'source': 'Might have been.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would this patriot be produced before?', 'source': 'That, this patriot would be produced before them.', 'answer': 'before them'}
{'question': 'What did he knuckle it in?', 'source': 'Jerry had just enough forehead to knuckle, and he knuckled it in acknowledgment of this communication and a shilling.', 'answer': 'in acknowledgment of this communication and a shilling'}
{'question': 'Who had she become familiar to?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': 'to me'}
{'question': 'Who rose with her?', 'source': 'Her father rose with her, and kept her hand drawn through his arm.', 'answer': 'her father'}
{'question': 'What did her father keep drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'Her father rose with her, and kept her hand drawn through his arm.', 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'Who was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'my father'}
{'question': 'Who was as open in his confidence with me as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': 'the prisoner'}
{'question': 'What did he begin to have?', 'source': 'He began to have suspicions of the prisoner, and to keep an eye upon him, soon afterwards.', 'answer': 'suspicions of the prisoner'}
{'question': 'What do I have?', 'source': "I have no remembrance of the process.''", 'answer': 'no remembrance of the process'}
{'question': 'Who had he asked?', 'source': 'He had asked the prisoner, aboard the Calais packet, if he wanted a handy fellow, and the prisoner had engaged him.', 'answer': 'the prisoner'}
{'question': 'What did he say that it was?', 'source': "``He tried to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen, and he said that, so far as he could judge, it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part.", 'answer': "a wrong and foolish one on England's part"}
{'question': 'Who showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': 'my Lord'}
{'question': 'Do but keep in the way?', 'source': 'But, keep in the way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where will you get long before I can?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': 'to Temple Bar'}
{'question': 'Who do I want to take the verdict back to the bank?', 'source': 'Do not be a moment behind them, for I want you to take the verdict back to the bank.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who are you I know?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': 'the quickest messenger'}
{'question': 'What was that the manner of?', 'source': "That was the manner of our beginning to speak together.''", 'answer': "of a few questions's beginning to speak together"}
{'question': 'Who do?', 'source': 'Not more than other gentlemen do.', 'answer': 'more than other gentlemen'}
{'question': 'Who had given information?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did her father rise with?', 'source': 'Her father rose with her, and kept her hand drawn through his arm.', 'answer': 'with her'}
{'question': "What does it's?", 'source': "``It's the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest.", 'answer': 'the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest'}
{'question': 'Do ever live by play?', 'source': 'Ever live by play?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he given?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'information'}
{'question': 'Who did he deem it necessary?', 'source': "Mr. Attorney-General now signified to my Lord, that he deemed it necessary, as a matter of precaution and form, to call the young lady's father, Doctor Manette.", 'answer': 'my Lord'}
{'question': 'Where did I sit on the deck?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'at his side to take care of him'}
{'question': 'What does she feel?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': 'the better for being out of court'}
{'question': 'Who stood beside her?', 'source': "``When the prisoner came on board, he noticed that my father,'' turning her eyes lovingly to him as he stood beside her, ``was much fatigued and in a very weak state of health.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who sat on the deck at his side to take care of him?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What is come?', 'source': '-- Come, once again.', 'answer': 'once again'}
{'question': 'Who is comforting her?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': 'her father'}
{'question': 'Who was all eyes, ears, and spikes?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'When was that the manner?', 'source': "That was the manner of our beginning to speak together.''", 'answer': 'of our beginning to speak together'}
{'question': "Does here's a fight to get back again?", 'source': "It's a fight to get back again.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who hopes ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day?''", 'source': "I hope,'' bursting into tears, ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What would Mr. have with?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him'}
{'question': 'Was the night so dark?', 'source': "``Both were so wrapped up, and the night was so dark, and we were all so reserved, that I cannot undertake to say even that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were both so wrapped up?', 'source': "``Both were so wrapped up, and the night was so dark, and we were all so reserved, that I cannot undertake to say even that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I sit on at his side to take care of him?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'on the deck'}
{'question': 'What did no he scorn?', 'source': 'No, he scorned the base insinuation.', 'answer': 'the base insinuation'}
{'question': 'Who will be sure to hear when the jury come in?', 'source': 'You will be sure to hear when the jury come in.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What had it evidently been to him?', 'source': 'It had evidently been a great distress to him, to have the days of his imprisonment recalled.', 'answer': 'a great distress'}
{'question': "Who 'll I tell so?", 'source': "``I 'll tell the prisoner so.", 'answer': 'the prisoner'}
{'question': 'What do I think their withdrawing is in?', 'source': "But I think their withdrawing is in your favor.''", 'answer': 'in your favor'}
{'question': 'Will any strongly marked expression of face on the part of a chief actor in a scene of great interest to whom many eyes are directed, be unconsciously imitated by the spectators?', 'source': 'Any strongly marked expression of face on the part of a chief actor in a scene of great interest to whom many eyes are directed, will be unconsciously imitated by the spectators.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I think is in your favor?', 'source': "But I think their withdrawing is in your favor.''", 'answer': 'their withdrawing'}
{'question': 'Did Decidedly fall downstairs of his own accord?', 'source': 'Decidedly not; once received a kick on the top of a staircase, and fell downstairs of his own accord.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who retired himself?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': 'my Lord'}
{'question': 'Who is sure he felt it?', 'source': "He expressed great gentleness and kindness for my father's state, and I am sure he felt it.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Who 'll tell the prisoner so?", 'source': "``I 'll tell the prisoner so.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did the likeness become much more remarkable?', 'source': 'My Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lay aside his wig, and giving no very gracious consent, the likeness became much more remarkable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are you the quickest messenger?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': 'I know'}
{'question': 'What have you seen?', 'source': "You have seen the worst of her agitation.''", 'answer': 'the worst of her agitation'}
{'question': 'Who had not known how to do it well?', 'source': 'I had not known how to do it well, not understanding how the wind would set when we were out of the harbor.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he try to explain to me how?', 'source': "``He tried to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen, and he said that, so far as he could judge, it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part.", 'answer': 'that quarrel had arisen'}
{'question': 'What would show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans?', 'source': 'That, the proof would go back five years, and would show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans.', 'answer': 'the proof'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Attorney-General now signify to my Lord as a matter of precaution and form?', 'source': "Mr. Attorney-General now signified to my Lord, that he deemed it necessary, as a matter of precaution and form, to call the young lady's father, Doctor Manette.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was who called accordingly?', 'source': 'Who was called accordingly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he stand beside?', 'source': "``When the prisoner came on board, he noticed that my father,'' turning her eyes lovingly to him as he stood beside her, ``was much fatigued and in a very weak state of health.", 'answer': 'beside her'}
{'question': 'What would this shining citizen probably not have?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': 'one'}
{'question': 'Was the witness quite sure?', 'source': 'The witness was quite sure.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would he have modestly withdrawn?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': "What did he say: ``Answer the questions put to you''?", 'source': "The plaintive tone of her compassion merged into the less musical voice of the Judge, as he said something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you, and make no remark upon them.''", 'answer': 'something fiercely'}
{'question': 'What had you sent?', 'source': "``If you had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life, ' again,'' muttered Jerry, as he turned, ``I should have known what you meant, this time.''", 'answer': 'the message'}
{'question': 'Who will, if you ask it?', 'source': "I will, if you ask it.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was he?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': 'a true Briton'}
{'question': 'Was something to that effect said by the intoxicated liar who committed the assault?', 'source': 'Something to that effect was said by the intoxicated liar who committed the assault, but it was not true.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I want you to take the verdict back to?', 'source': 'Do not be a moment behind them, for I want you to take the verdict back to the bank.', 'answer': 'to the bank'}
{'question': 'Who does ask it?', 'source': '``I do ask it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who could not bear it?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he love?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'his country'}
{'question': 'If statues were decreed in Britain would this shining citizen assuredly have had one?', 'source': 'That, if statues were decreed in Britain, as in ancient Greece and Rome, to public benefactors, this shining citizen would assuredly have had one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were two all so reserved?', 'source': "``Both were so wrapped up, and the night was so dark, and we were all so reserved, that I cannot undertake to say even that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I want you to take back to the bank?', 'source': 'Do not be a moment behind them, for I want you to take the verdict back to the bank.', 'answer': 'the verdict'}
{'question': 'Where did he say?', 'source': "He said that this business had, within a few days, taken him to France, and might, at intervals, take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come.''", 'answer': 'that this business had taken him to France'}
{'question': "Did Jerry mutter ``If you had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life''?", 'source': "``If you had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life, ' again,'' muttered Jerry, as he turned, ``I should have known what you meant, this time.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who wished to retire?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner come forward directly?', 'source': 'The prisoner came forward directly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could this patriot no longer cherish in?', 'source': "That, he had been the prisoner's friend, but, at once in an auspicious and an evil hour detecting his infamy, had resolved to immolate the traitor he could no longer cherish in his bosom, on the sacred altar of his country.", 'answer': 'in his bosom'}
{'question': 'What wished to retire?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What will you get to long before I can?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': 'to Temple Bar'}
{'question': 'What did he say?', 'source': "``He tried to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen, and he said that, so far as he could judge, it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part.", 'answer': "that it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part"}
{'question': 'What would he have with?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him'}
{'question': 'What did I sit on the deck at?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'at his side to take care of him'}
{'question': 'Been ever kicked?', 'source': 'Ever been kicked?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do more than other gentlemen do?', 'source': 'Not more than other gentlemen do.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do dear no.?', 'source': 'Oh dear no. .', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Lorry redden as if he were conscious of having debated the point in his mind?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry reddened as if he were conscious of having debated the point in his mind, and Mr. Carton made his way to the outside of the bar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it certain?', 'source': 'That, it was certain the prisoner had, for longer than that, been in the habit of passing and repassing between France and England, on secret business of which he could give no honest account.', 'answer': 'the prisoner had'}
{'question': 'What would he probably not have?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': 'one'}
{'question': 'Were statues not so decreed?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it turn out to be?', 'source': 'He had never been suspected of stealing a silver tea-pot; he had been maligned respecting a mustard-pot, but it turned out to be only a plated one.', 'answer': 'only a plated one'}
{'question': 'Was the only passenger who came on board at that untimely hour the only passenger who came on board in the dead of the night?', 'source': "He was the only passenger who came on board in the dead of the night?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he shown strong internal agitation when he was questioned, and that pondering or brooding look which made him old, had been upon him?', 'source': 'He had shown strong internal agitation when he was questioned, and that pondering or brooding look which made him old, had been upon him, like a heavy cloud, ever since.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had he taken these lists from the drawer of the prisoner's desk?", 'source': "He had taken these lists from the drawer of the prisoner's desk.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this shining citizen call with confidence on the jury to come?', 'source': 'That, he called with confidence on the jury to come and do likewise.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could he not bear?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who did it for me?', 'source': 'He did it for me.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was he the only passenger who came on board in the dead of the night?', 'source': "He was the only passenger who came on board in the dead of the night?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I not know?', 'source': "``Some papers had been handed about among them, but I do not know what papers.''", 'answer': 'what papers'}
{'question': 'What do I ask?', 'source': '``I do ask it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the young lady stand up where she had sat?', 'source': 'The young lady, to whom all eyes had been turned before, and were now turned again, stood up where she had sat.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do here sir!', 'source': '``Here, sir!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you be sure to hear when the jury come in?', 'source': 'You will be sure to hear when the jury come in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could he no longer cherish in?', 'source': "That, he had been the prisoner's friend, but, at once in an auspicious and an evil hour detecting his infamy, had resolved to immolate the traitor he could no longer cherish in his bosom, on the sacred altar of his country.", 'answer': 'in his bosom'}
{'question': 'What was that?', 'source': "That was the manner of our beginning to speak together.''", 'answer': "the manner of a few questions's beginning to speak together"}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Cruncher by this time taken quite a lunch of rust off his fingers in his following of the evidence?', 'source': 'Mr. Cruncher had by this time taken quite a lunch of rust off his fingers in his following of the evidence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he call with confidence on the jury to come?', 'source': 'That, he called with confidence on the jury to come and do likewise.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the only passenger who came on board at that untimely hour lie on a sofa?', 'source': "The weather was stormy, and the passage long and rough, and I lay on a sofa, almost from shore to shore.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it begin to be rumored that the jury would be out a long while?', 'source': 'It began to be rumored that the jury would be out a long while.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the way out of court lie in that direction?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is come once again?', 'source': '-- Come, once again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did opening this piece of paper in the next pause look with great attention and curiosity at the prisoner?', 'source': 'Opening this piece of paper in the next pause, the counsel looked with great attention and curiosity at the prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I returning from France a few days afterwards?', 'source': "``I was returning from France a few days afterwards, and, at Calais, the prisoner came on board the packet-ship in which I returned, and made the voyage with me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does not know what papers?', 'source': "``Some papers had been handed about among them, but I do not know what papers.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was him?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': 'all eyes, ears, and spikes'}
{'question': 'Did the plaintive tone of her compassion merge into the less musical voice of the Judge?', 'source': "The plaintive tone of her compassion merged into the less musical voice of the Judge, as he said something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you, and make no remark upon them.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been maligned respecting a mustard-pot?', 'source': 'He had never been suspected of stealing a silver tea-pot; he had been maligned respecting a mustard-pot, but it turned out to be only a plated one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do ever pay?', 'source': 'Ever pay him?', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who had not put them there first?', 'source': 'He had not put them there first.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "What do I hope ``I may not repay him by doing?''", 'source': "I hope,'' bursting into tears, ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day.''", 'answer': 'him harm to-day'}
{'question': 'Had he never been suspected of stealing a silver tea-pot?', 'source': 'He had never been suspected of stealing a silver tea-pot; he had been maligned respecting a mustard-pot, but it turned out to be only a plated one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he do it for?', 'source': 'He did it for me.', 'answer': 'for me'}
{'question': 'Was that this correspondence with the public enemy certain the prisoner had?', 'source': 'That, it was certain the prisoner had, for longer than that, been in the habit of passing and repassing between France and England, on secret business of which he could give no honest account.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were all so reserved?', 'source': "``Both were so wrapped up, and the night was so dark, and we were all so reserved, that I cannot undertake to say even that.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': "If that this correspondence with the public enemy were in the nature of traitorous ways to thrive might the real wickedness and guilt of Mr. Attorney-General's business have remained undiscovered?", 'source': 'That, if it were in the nature of traitorous ways to thrive (which happily it never was), the real wickedness and guilt of his business might have remained undiscovered.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Jerry follow him?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this shining citizen call with confidence on the jury to do likewise?', 'source': 'That, he called with confidence on the jury to come and do likewise.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who added?', 'source': 'He added, in a jesting way, that perhaps George Washington might gain almost as great a name in history as George the Third.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is greatly distressed?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did he begin to have suspicions of the prisoner?', 'source': 'He began to have suspicions of the prisoner, and to keep an eye upon him, soon afterwards.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the hoarse messenger uncomfortably seated on a form after taking that refection?', 'source': 'The hoarse messenger, uncomfortably seated on a form after taking that refection, had dropped into a doze, when a loud murmur and a rapid tide of people setting up the stairs that led to the court, carried him along with them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the prisoner so good as to beg permission to advise me from the wind and weather?', 'source': 'The prisoner was so good as to beg permission to advise me how I could shelter my father from the wind and weather, better than I had done.', 'answer': 'how I could shelter my father'}
{'question': 'Who answered?', 'source': "He answered, in a low voice, ``There is.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did he call with confidence on the jury to do likewise?', 'source': 'That, he called with confidence on the jury to come and do likewise.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What am I quite unable even to say?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': 'how she had become familiar'}
{'question': 'Do I have no remembrance of the process?', 'source': "I have no remembrance of the process.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he see the prisoner with these lists?', 'source': 'Sure he saw the prisoner with these lists?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your native country Doctor Manette?', 'source': "``Has it been your misfortune to undergo a long imprisonment, without trial, or even accusation, in your native country, Doctor Manette?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he do for me?', 'source': 'He did it for me.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who were not agreed?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What was he?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': 'kind, and good, and useful to my father'}
{'question': 'What were not agreed?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Do and size, ``Like these in shape''?", 'source': "``Like these in shape and size?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his hurried right hand parcel out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden?', 'source': 'His hurried right hand parcelled out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden; and his efforts to control and steady his breathing shook the lips from which the color rushed to his heart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he have that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What she was?', 'source': 'There was much commiseration for her as she was removed, and much sympathy with her father.', 'answer': 'much sympathy with her father'}
{'question': 'What did he say to?', 'source': "He said that this business had, within a few days, taken him to France, and might, at intervals, take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come.''", 'answer': 'that this business had taken him to France'}
{'question': 'Had he taken service with the prisoner?', 'source': 'He had taken service with the prisoner, in good faith and simplicity, four years ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she feel the better for being out of court?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner come on board the packet-ship in which I returned, and made the voyage with me?', 'source': "``I was returning from France a few days afterwards, and, at Calais, the prisoner came on board the packet-ship in which I returned, and made the voyage with me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest?", 'source': "``It's the wisest thing to expect, and the likeliest.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say that it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part?", 'source': "``He tried to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen, and he said that, so far as he could judge, it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did my Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lie aside his wig?', 'source': 'My Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lay aside his wig, and giving no very gracious consent, the likeness became much more remarkable.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would this patriot be produced before them?', 'source': 'That, this patriot would be produced before them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my mind a blank, from some time time-- when I employed myself?', 'source': 'My mind is a blank, from some time-- I cannot even say what time-- when I employed myself, in my captivity, in making shoes, to the time when I found myself living in London with my dear daughter here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who lay aside his wig?', 'source': 'My Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend lay aside his wig, and giving no very gracious consent, the likeness became much more remarkable.', 'answer': 'my Lord being prayed to bid my learned friend'}
{'question': 'Who had he not put there first?', 'source': 'He had not put them there first.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Carton ask that?', 'source': '``I do ask it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he hope?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': 'there were many like him'}
{'question': 'Will you get to Temple Bar long before I can?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the story of his pure soul exactly what Mr. Attorney-General had described it to be exactly?', 'source': 'The story of his pure soul was exactly what Mr. Attorney-General had described it to be-- perhaps, if it had a fault, a little too exactly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What pay him?', 'source': 'Ever pay him?', 'answer': 'ever'}
{'question': "Did he say something fiercely: ``Answer the questions make no remark upon them''?", 'source': "The plaintive tone of her compassion merged into the less musical voice of the Judge, as he said something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you, and make no remark upon them.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he not put there first?', 'source': 'He had not put them there first.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did my Lord show some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was that the manner of a few questions's beginning to speak together?", 'source': "That was the manner of our beginning to speak together.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that the manner of our beginning to speak together?', 'source': "That was the manner of our beginning to speak together.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I lie on a sofa?', 'source': "The weather was stormy, and the passage long and rough, and I lay on a sofa, almost from shore to shore.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say that this business had taken him to France?', 'source': "He said that this business had, within a few days, taken him to France, and might, at intervals, take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will it not do for?', 'source': "It will not do for a respectable bank gentleman like you, to be seen speaking to him publicly, you know.''", 'answer': 'for a respectable bank gentleman like you'}
{'question': 'Did he try to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen?', 'source': "``He tried to explain to me how that quarrel had arisen, and he said that, so far as he could judge, it was a wrong and foolish one on England's part.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he known the last witness seven or eight years; that was merely a coincidence?', 'source': 'He had known the last witness seven or eight years; that was merely a coincidence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he a true Briton?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his efforts to control and steady his breathing shake the lips from which the color rushed to his heart?', 'source': 'His hurried right hand parcelled out the herbs before him into imaginary beds of flowers in a garden; and his efforts to control and steady his breathing shook the lips from which the color rushed to his heart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he deem my Lord it necessary?', 'source': "Mr. Attorney-General now signified to my Lord, that he deemed it necessary, as a matter of precaution and form, to call the young lady's father, Doctor Manette.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would Mr. have?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'modestly withdrawn himself'}
{'question': 'If it were in the nature of traitorous ways to thrive might the real wickedness and guilt of his business have remained undiscovered?', 'source': 'That, if it were in the nature of traitorous ways to thrive (which happily it never was), the real wickedness and guilt of his business might have remained undiscovered.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When is my mind?', 'source': 'My mind is a blank, from some time-- I cannot even say what time-- when I employed myself, in my captivity, in making shoes, to the time when I found myself living in London with my dear daughter here.', 'answer': 'a blank, from some time time-- when I employed myself'}
{'question': 'Are a here?', 'source': "They are here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was my father so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you''?", 'source': "The plaintive tone of her compassion merged into the less musical voice of the Judge, as he said something fiercely: ``Answer the questions put to you, and make no remark upon them.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her father keep her hand drawn through his arm?', 'source': 'Her father rose with her, and kept her hand drawn through his arm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand lounging with his elbow against the bar?', 'source': 'He stood, half turned from the prisoner, lounging with his elbow against the bar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it turn out to be only a plated one?', 'source': 'He had never been suspected of stealing a silver tea-pot; he had been maligned respecting a mustard-pot, but it turned out to be only a plated one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was removed?', 'source': 'There was much commiseration for her as she was removed, and much sympathy with her father.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did he knuckle it in acknowledgment of this communication and a shilling?', 'source': 'Jerry had just enough forehead to knuckle, and he knuckled it in acknowledgment of this communication and a shilling.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had he known?', 'source': 'He had known the last witness seven or eight years; that was merely a coincidence.', 'answer': 'the last witness seven or eight years; that was merely a coincidence'}
{'question': 'Was it certain the prisoner had?', 'source': 'That, it was certain the prisoner had, for longer than that, been in the habit of passing and repassing between France and England, on secret business of which he could give no honest account.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hope there were many like him?', 'source': 'He was a true Briton, and hoped there were many like him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he express great gentleness and kindness for my father's state?", 'source': "He expressed great gentleness and kindness for my father's state, and I am sure he felt it.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the prisoner engaged him?', 'source': 'He had asked the prisoner, aboard the Calais packet, if he wanted a handy fellow, and the prisoner had engaged him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he begin to keep an eye upon him?', 'source': 'He began to have suspicions of the prisoner, and to keep an eye upon him, soon afterwards.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did no he scorn the base insinuation?', 'source': 'No, he scorned the base insinuation.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have you seen the worst of her agitation?', 'source': "You have seen the worst of her agitation.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he given information?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he asked the prisoner?', 'source': 'He had asked the prisoner, aboard the Calais packet, if he wanted a handy fellow, and the prisoner had engaged him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think their withdrawing is in your favor?', 'source': "But I think their withdrawing is in your favor.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were not so decreed?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Jerry you can?', 'source': '``Jerry, if you wish to take something to eat, you can.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did my Lord show some surprise under?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': 'that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward'}
{'question': 'Do I remember them both to have been timorous of highwaymen?', 'source': "Except that I remember them both to have been-- like myself-- timorous of highwaymen, and the prisoner has not a timorous air.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did my Lord retire himself?', 'source': 'My Lord (perhaps with George Washington on his mind) showed some surprise that they were not agreed, but signified his pleasure that they should retire under watch and ward, and retired himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might he take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come?', 'source': "He said that this business had, within a few days, taken him to France, and might, at intervals, take him backwards and forwards between France and England for a long time to come.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I deeply sorry to have been the cause of it?', 'source': '``I am deeply sorry to have been the cause of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the prisoner so good as to beg permission to advise me how I could shelter my father from the wind and weather?', 'source': 'The prisoner was so good as to beg permission to advise me how I could shelter my father from the wind and weather, better than I had done.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the prisoner as open in as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': 'in his confidence with me'}
{'question': "Do I hope ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day?''", 'source': "I hope,'' bursting into tears, ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it evidently been a great distress to him?', 'source': 'It had evidently been a great distress to him, to have the days of his imprisonment recalled.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could this patriot no longer cherish in his bosom?', 'source': "That, he had been the prisoner's friend, but, at once in an auspicious and an evil hour detecting his infamy, had resolved to immolate the traitor he could no longer cherish in his bosom, on the sacred altar of his country.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was something to that effect not true?', 'source': 'Something to that effect was said by the intoxicated liar who committed the assault, but it was not true.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you the quickest messenger I know?', 'source': "You are the quickest messenger I know, and will get to Temple Bar long before I can.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do they wish to retire?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was him all eyes, ears, and spikes?', 'source': 'The way out of court lay in that direction, and Jerry followed him, all eyes, ears, and spikes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the prisoner as open in his confidence with me as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will it not do for a respectable bank gentleman like you?', 'source': "It will not do for a respectable bank gentleman like you, to be seen speaking to him publicly, you know.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is!', 'source': "most unhappily, I am!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Does intent as she gave this evidence pause when she stopped for the Judge to write it down, watched its effect upon the counsel for and against?', 'source': 'Her forehead was painfully anxious and intent as she gave this evidence, and, in the pauses when she stopped for the Judge to write it down, watched its effect upon the counsel for and against.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was my father so reduced of?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': 'that I was afraid to take him out of the air'}
{'question': 'Had I made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "'ll I tell the prisoner so?", 'source': "``I 'll tell the prisoner so.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he shown?', 'source': 'He had shown strong internal agitation when he was questioned, and that pondering or brooding look which made him old, had been upon him, like a heavy cloud, ever since.', 'answer': 'strong internal agitation when he was questioned, and that pondering or brooding look which made him old, had been upon him'}
{'question': 'Had she become familiar to me?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her forehead painfully anxious?', 'source': 'Her forehead was painfully anxious and intent as she gave this evidence, and, in the pauses when she stopped for the Judge to write it down, watched its effect upon the counsel for and against.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's a fight to get back again?", 'source': "It's a fight to get back again.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were this patriot's position and attitude?", 'source': 'That, his position and attitude were, on the whole, sublime.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would he have?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': 'modestly withdrawn himself'}
{'question': 'Do I want you to take the verdict back to the bank?', 'source': 'Do not be a moment behind them, for I want you to take the verdict back to the bank.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his position and attitude?', 'source': 'That, his position and attitude were, on the whole, sublime.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had I not known?', 'source': 'I had not known how to do it well, not understanding how the wind would set when we were out of the harbor.', 'answer': 'how to do it well'}
{'question': 'Had you sent the message?', 'source': "``If you had sent the message, ` Recalled to Life, ' again,'' muttered Jerry, as he turned, ``I should have known what you meant, this time.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would the proof show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans?', 'source': 'That, the proof would go back five years, and would show the prisoner already engaged in these pernicious missions, within a few weeks before the date of the very first action fought between the British troops and the Americans.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the gentleman my learned friend there?', 'source': "``Look well upon that gentleman, my learned friend there,'' pointing to him who had tossed the paper over, ``and then look well upon the prisoner.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would this shining citizen probably not have one?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I sit on the deck at his side to take care of him?', 'source': 'My father was so reduced that I was afraid to take him out of the air, and I had made a bed for him on the deck near the cabin steps, and I sat on the deck at his side to take care of him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her father rise with her?', 'source': 'Her father rose with her, and kept her hand drawn through his arm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I sure he felt it?', 'source': "He expressed great gentleness and kindness for my father's state, and I am sure he felt it.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not know what papers?', 'source': "``Some papers had been handed about among them, but I do not know what papers.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I quite unable even to say how she had become familiar?', 'source': 'She had become familiar to me, when a gracious God restored my faculties; but, I am quite unable even to say how she had become familiar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are here?', 'source': "They are here.''", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he add?', 'source': 'He added, in a jesting way, that perhaps George Washington might gain almost as great a name in history as George the Third.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they not agreed?', 'source': 'They were not agreed, and wished to retire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he not precisely remember where it was?', 'source': 'He did not precisely remember where it was.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did yes he have?', 'source': 'Yes, he had.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were we all so reserved?', 'source': "``Both were so wrapped up, and the night was so dark, and we were all so reserved, that I cannot undertake to say even that.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is she greatly distressed?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he not call it a particularly curious coincidence?', 'source': 'He did not call it a particularly curious coincidence; most coincidences were curious.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'She was much sympathy with her father?', 'source': 'There was much commiseration for her as she was removed, and much sympathy with her father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not true?', 'source': 'Something to that effect was said by the intoxicated liar who committed the assault, but it was not true.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he love his country?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pass out?', 'source': 'As he passed out, the jury, who had turned back and paused a moment, spoke, through their foreman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do ever pay him?', 'source': 'Ever pay him?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he no longer cherish in his bosom?', 'source': "That, he had been the prisoner's friend, but, at once in an auspicious and an evil hour detecting his infamy, had resolved to immolate the traitor he could no longer cherish in his bosom, on the sacred altar of his country.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is her father comforting her?', 'source': "``She is greatly distressed; but her father is comforting her, and she feels the better for being out of court.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he have modestly withdrawn himself?', 'source': 'Having released his noble bosom of its burden, he would have modestly withdrawn himself, but that the wigged gentleman with the papers before him, sitting not far from Mr. Lorry, begged to ask him a few questions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he answer?', 'source': "He answered, in a low voice, ``There is.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were those two passengers?', 'source': "Supposing him wrapped up as those two passengers were, is there anything in his bulk and stature to render it unlikely that he was one of them?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand beside her?', 'source': "``When the prisoner came on board, he noticed that my father,'' turning her eyes lovingly to him as he stood beside her, ``was much fatigued and in a very weak state of health.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he probably not have one?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he kind, and good, and useful to my father?', 'source': '``The prisoner was as open in his confidence with me-- which arose out of my helpless situation-- as he was kind, and good, and useful to my father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had I not known how to do it well?', 'source': 'I had not known how to do it well, not understanding how the wind would set when we were out of the harbor.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Yes, I could?', 'source': '``Yes, I could.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I!', 'source': "most unhappily, I am!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he do it for me?', 'source': 'He did it for me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he not bear it?', 'source': 'He loved his country, and could not bear it, and had given information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will do very well?', 'source': 'She will do very well.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was she removed?', 'source': 'There was much commiseration for her as she was removed, and much sympathy with her father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I ask it?', 'source': '``I do ask it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I think in?', 'source': "But I think their withdrawing is in your favor.''", 'answer': 'their withdrawing is in your favor'}
{'question': 'Were they not so decreed?', 'source': 'That, as they were not so decreed, he probably would not have one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will she do very well?', 'source': 'She will do very well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that this correspondence with the public enemy not a correspondence of to-day, or of yesterday, or even of last year, or of the year before?', 'source': 'That this correspondence with the public enemy was not a correspondence of to-day, or of yesterday, or even of last year, or of the year before.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Could these lists not be proved to be in the prisoner's handwriting; but that it was all the same; that it was rather the better for the prosecution?", 'source': "That, these lists could not be proved to be in the prisoner's handwriting; but that it was all the same; that, indeed, it was rather the better for the prosecution, as showing the prisoner to be artful in his precautions.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he not put them there first?', 'source': 'He had not put them there first.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are they here?', 'source': "They are here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What do I hope?''", 'source': "I hope,'' bursting into tears, ``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day.''", 'answer': '``I may not repay him by doing him harm to-day'}
{'question': 'What was possible to be?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'just over the little feminine nose'}
{'question': 'What does he settle at the ears?', 'source': "After a pause, he added, again settling the crisp flaxen wig at the ears, ``It is very difficult to begin.''", 'answer': 'the crisp flaxen wig'}
{'question': 'Do Miss manette!', 'source': "Miss Manette!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sir, do Gentleman thank you indeed?', 'source': '``Sir, I thank you indeed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she turn to?', 'source': 'she said, indignantly turning to Mr. Lorry; ``could not you tell her what you had to tell her, without frightening her to death?', 'answer': 'to Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What had so particularly attracted his notice, and which was now immovable, had?', 'source': 'The expression in the forehead, which had so particularly attracted his notice, and which was now immovable, had deepened into one of pain and horror.', 'answer': 'the forehead'}
{'question': 'What did the young forehead lift into that singular expression?', 'source': 'The young forehead lifted itself into that singular expression-- but it was pretty and characteristic, besides being singular-- and she raised her hand, as if with an involuntary action she caught at, or stayed some passing shadow.', 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': 'What was his breakfast-table drawn before?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': 'before the fire'}
{'question': 'Would a be so encouraging for instance?', 'source': 'If you could kindly mention now, for instance, what nine times ninepence are, or how many shillings in twenty guineas, it would be so encouraging.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig very difficult to begin after a pause?', 'source': "After a pause, he added, again settling the crisp flaxen wig at the ears, ``It is very difficult to begin.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who was I one of?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': 'of the trustees'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry extend them outwards with an argumentative smile?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry opened his hands, and extended them outwards with an argumentative smile.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the day decline into the afternoon?', 'source': "As the day declined into the afternoon, and the air, which had been at intervals clear enough to allow the French coast to be seen, became again charged with mist and vapor, Mr. Lorry's thoughts seemed to cloud too.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have Gentleman done my best to prepare myself?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Bed, sir?', 'source': "Bed, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did I inform that some intelligence-- or discovery--?', 'source': "``I received a letter from the Bank, sir, yesterday, informing me that some intelligence-- or discovery--''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What did only one thing more lie stress upon it as?', 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': "as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''"}
{'question': 'Is the friendship in them no particular interest?', 'source': 'These are mere business relations, miss; there is no friendship in them, no particular interest, nothing like sentiment.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is a scrap of writing openly referring to it?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it?', 'source': 'The air among the houses was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it, as sick people went down to be dipped in the sea.', 'answer': 'the air among the houses'}
{'question': 'Who was one of the trustees?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was that forenoon?', 'source': 'The coffee-room had no other occupant, that forenoon, than the gentleman in brown.', 'answer': 'the other occupant'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry bring his left hand from to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'from the back of the chair'}
{'question': 'Who carries about me?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What cares come easily off and on?', 'source': "But, perhaps the confidential bachelor clerks in Tellson's Bank were principally occupied with the cares of other people; and perhaps second-hand cares, like second-hand clothes, come easily off and on.", 'answer': 'perhaps second-hand'}
{'question': 'Who was your mother?', 'source': 'Miss Manette, your mother took this course with you.', 'answer': 'Miss Manette'}
{'question': 'Who naturally has a strong and eager interest to know what they are?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was the Bank sir?', 'source': "``I received a letter from the Bank, sir, yesterday, informing me that some intelligence-- or discovery--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the seat sir?', 'source': "``Pray take a seat, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was ever intended that I should go across salt water?', 'source': "``If it was ever intended that I should go across salt water, do you suppose Providence would have cast my lot in an island?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who caught his wrist with both her hands?', 'source': 'And she caught his wrist with both her hands.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Is the time for no feelings no chance of them?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who put it with some ceremony to his lips?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Will either word do?', 'source': "``The word is not material, miss; either word will do.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who not much in the habit of such travels yourself?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did it bring down?', 'source': 'It thundered at the town, and thundered at the cliffs, and brought the coast down, madly.', 'answer': 'the coast'}
{'question': 'What did it thunder at?', 'source': 'It thundered at the town, and thundered at the cliffs, and brought the coast down, madly.', 'answer': 'at the town'}
{'question': 'What are known to you?', 'source': 'The best and the worst are known to you, now.', 'answer': 'the best and the worst'}
{'question': 'Who do I think a messenger was sent after to beg the favor of his waiting for me here?', 'source': "The gentleman had left London, but I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here.''", 'answer': 'after him'}
{'question': 'Who were of a fine texture?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was the time sir?', 'source': "The George was in other hands at that time, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry, ``to be entrusted with the charge say, ``I was happy''?", 'source': "``I was happy,'' said Mr. Lorry, ``to be entrusted with the charge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What remained standing between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto'}
{'question': 'Who married-- an English lady?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was the daughter sir?', 'source': "``The little child was a daughter, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked down?', 'source': 'As he said the words he looked down, with an admiring pity, on the flowing golden hair; as if he pictured to himself that it might have been already tinged with gray.', 'answer': 'a young lady who may come here at any time to-day'}
{'question': 'Who did he marry--?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': 'an English lady'}
{'question': 'Is the new discovery of money?', 'source': "There has been no new discovery, of money, or of any other property; but--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was close her hold upon?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': 'upon his arm'}
{'question': 'What deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'the expression'}
{'question': 'What was before?', 'source': 'After this odd description of his daily routine of employment, Mr. Lorry flattened his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands (which was most unnecessary, for nothing could be flatter than its shining surface was before), and resumed his former attitude.', 'answer': "flatter's shining surface"}
{'question': 'What was close upon his arm?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': 'her hold'}
{'question': 'Who curtseyed to him?', 'source': 'She curtseyed to him (young ladies made curtseys in those days), with a pretty desire to convey to him that she felt how much older and wiser he was than she.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who has no time for them?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Who said, ``I hope she will do well now''?", 'source': "``I hope she will do well now,'' said Mr. Lorry.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What have Gentleman done to prepare myself?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'my best'}
{'question': 'Does the care of other people?', 'source': "But, perhaps the confidential bachelor clerks in Tellson's Bank were principally occupied with the cares of other people; and perhaps second-hand cares, like second-hand clothes, come easily off and on.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were our relations?', 'source': 'Our relations were business relations, but confidential.', 'answer': 'business relations'}
{'question': 'What did his face bear?', 'source': 'He had a healthy color in his cheeks, and his face, though lined, bore few traces of anxiety.', 'answer': 'few traces of anxiety'}
{'question': 'What do you kneel to me in?', 'source': "In Heaven's name why should you kneel to me!''", 'answer': "in Heaven's name"}
{'question': 'What will a shiver be-- not him!', 'source': "It will be his Ghost-- not him!''", 'answer': "a young lady who may come here at any time to-day's Ghost"}
{'question': 'What did Mr. Lorry bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on?', 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': "on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''"}
{'question': 'What did he put it with to his lips?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': 'with some ceremony'}
{'question': 'Who is a scrap of writing openly referring to all naming of the matter?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What was the air among the houses of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed went up to be dipped in it?', 'source': 'The air among the houses was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it, as sick people went down to be dipped in the sea.', 'answer': 'sick fish'}
{'question': 'What was he a little vain of?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'What was before my time here?', 'source': 'That was before my time here, sir.', 'answer': 'that'}
{'question': 'Who awaited his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Is me a scrap of writing openly referring to all naming of the matter?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will do?', 'source': "``The word is not material, miss; either word will do.''", 'answer': 'either word'}
{'question': 'Who is going to see his Ghost!', 'source': '``I am going to see his Ghost!', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was dark?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'no business whatever'}
{'question': 'Who passes my whole life?', 'source': "I pass my whole life, miss, in turning an immense pecuniary Mangle.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who wants a bedroom, and a barber?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Is the one line Recalled?', 'source': "My credentials, entries, and memoranda, are all comprehended in the one line, ` Recalled to Life; ' which may mean anything.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would only one thing more be worse than useless now to make any inquiries?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to make any inquiries, because it would be dangerous.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she take her seat thoughtfully in by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'thoughtfully in the chair'}
{'question': 'Who sat before the coffee-room fire?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Sir, who do Gentleman thank indeed?', 'source': '``Sir, I thank you indeed.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Who 'll let you know I will?", 'source': "I 'll let you know, if you do not bring smelling-salts, cold water, and vinegar, quick, I will.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who said to the drawer?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who do I carry about?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': 'about me'}
{'question': 'Who was he?', 'source': "He was a French gentleman; a scientific gentleman; a man of great acquirements-- a Doctor.''", 'answer': 'a French gentleman; a scientific gentleman; a man of great acquirements-- a Doctor'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry lie upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': 'stress'}
{'question': 'What are we quite?', 'source': "We are quite a French House, as well as an English one.''", 'answer': 'a French House'}
{'question': 'Who is the time for them no chance of?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'of them'}
{'question': 'Who is the time for no feelings no chance of?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'of them'}
{'question': 'Do Gentleman thank you very gratefully?', 'source': 'I thank you very gratefully.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was a large, dark room?', 'source': 'It was a large, dark room, furnished in a funereal manner with black horsehair, and loaded with heavy dark tables.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What are we going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': 'to life'}
{'question': 'Who do Gentleman think a messenger was sent after to beg the favor of his waiting for me here?', 'source': "The gentleman had left London, but I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here.''", 'answer': 'after him'}
{'question': 'Was just over the little feminine nose possible to be?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would it be so encouraging for?', 'source': 'If you could kindly mention now, for instance, what nine times ninepence are, or how many shillings in twenty guineas, it would be so encouraging.', 'answer': 'for instance'}
{'question': 'Who watched her as she mused?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who waited for the meal?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he say to?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'to the drawer'}
{'question': 'What was though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings?', 'source': 'His linen, though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings, was as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea.', 'answer': 'his linen'}
{'question': 'What did he call out loudly for without moving?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': 'loudly for assistance'}
{'question': 'Who did she curtsey to?', 'source': 'She curtseyed to him (young ladies made curtseys in those days), with a pretty desire to convey to him that she felt how much older and wiser he was than she.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': "What did Pray bring his left hand from to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'from the back of the chair'}
{'question': 'Who do I not much in the habit of such travel?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': 'yourself'}
{'question': 'What is the time for them no chance of?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'of them'}
{'question': 'What is the time for no feelings no chance of?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'of them'}
{'question': 'Who had a good leg?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What ran through her frame, and from it through his?', 'source': 'A shiver ran through her frame, and from it through his.', 'answer': 'a shiver'}
{'question': 'What did she take thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'her seat'}
{'question': 'Who has done my best to prepare myself?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Jarvis Lorry withdraw to consider it?', 'source': 'This being another question hard to answer, Mr. Jarvis Lorry withdrew to consider it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were he of?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'of a fine texture'}
{'question': 'What did he have in his cheeks?', 'source': 'He had a healthy color in his cheeks, and his face, though lined, bore few traces of anxiety.', 'answer': 'a healthy color'}
{'question': 'Who is alive?', 'source': 'He is alive.', 'answer': 'a young lady who may come here at any time to-day'}
{'question': 'Who has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he put with some ceremony to his lips?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was he a French gentleman; a scientific gentleman; a man of great acquirements-- a Doctor?', 'source': "He was a French gentleman; a scientific gentleman; a man of great acquirements-- a Doctor.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Have you been the ward of Tellson's House since?", 'source': "No; you have been the ward of Tellson's House since, and I have been busy with the other business of Tellson's House since.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I-- come last from?', 'source': "It is fifteen years since we-- since I-- came last from France.''", 'answer': 'from France'}
{'question': 'Who has passed from one to another, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was his mind busily?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'digging'}
{'question': 'What did he wait for?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': 'for the meal'}
{'question': 'When is it very difficult to begin?', 'source': "After a pause, he added, again settling the crisp flaxen wig at the ears, ``It is very difficult to begin.''", 'answer': 'after a pause'}
{'question': 'Did the moment go on?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I passed from one to, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'to another'}
{'question': 'Who raised her hand?', 'source': 'The young forehead lifted itself into that singular expression-- but it was pretty and characteristic, besides being singular-- and she raised her hand, as if with an involuntary action she caught at, or stayed some passing shadow.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was digging digging?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is I am not so much to look at?', 'source': 'I am not so much to look at, am I?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I want?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': 'a bedroom, and a barber'}
{'question': 'Who set down his glass untouched?', 'source': 'He set down his glass untouched.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who felt his wrist held closer?', 'source': 'He felt his wrist held closer, and he stopped.', 'answer': 'a young lady who may come here at any time to-day'}
{'question': 'Sir, who thankes you indeed?', 'source': '``Sir, I thank you indeed.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was no business whatever dark?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who 'll I let know I will?", 'source': "I 'll let you know, if you do not bring smelling-salts, cold water, and vinegar, quick, I will.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Who 'll I let you know will?", 'source': "I 'll let you know, if you do not bring smelling-salts, cold water, and vinegar, quick, I will.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What am I going to see!', 'source': '``I am going to see his Ghost!', 'answer': 'his Ghost'}
{'question': "Who brought his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'Pray'}
{'question': 'Who are we going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore to life?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': "Was there's damp and dirty straw its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, ?", 'source': 'The mildewy inside of the coach, with its damp and dirty straw, its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, was rather like a larger dog-kennel.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the word not material?', 'source': "``The word is not material, miss; either word will do.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Jarvis Lorry withdraw to consider this?', 'source': 'This being another question hard to answer, Mr. Jarvis Lorry withdrew to consider it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Pray bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on?', 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': "on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''"}
{'question': 'What was its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, ?', 'source': 'The mildewy inside of the coach, with its damp and dirty straw, its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, was rather like a larger dog-kennel.', 'answer': "there's damp and dirty straw"}
{'question': 'What shall I not go to till night?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': 'to bed'}
{'question': 'What did she catch with both her hands?', 'source': 'And she caught his wrist with both her hands.', 'answer': 'his wrist'}
{'question': 'What did he put it with some ceremony to?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': 'to his lips'}
{'question': 'What was the air among the houses of sick fish went up to be dipped in it?', 'source': 'The air among the houses was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it, as sick people went down to be dipped in the sea.', 'answer': 'of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed'}
{'question': 'What did he sit before?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'before the coffee-room fire'}
{'question': 'Who made her another bow?', 'source': 'He made her another bow.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'So far, miss, who is this the story of?', 'source': '``So far, miss (as you have remarked), this is the story of your regretted father.', 'answer': 'of your regretted father'}
{'question': 'What did he have?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'a good leg'}
{'question': "Have I been busy with the other business of Tellson's House since?", 'source': "No; you have been the ward of Tellson's House since, and I have been busy with the other business of Tellson's House since.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the coach-door's custom?", 'source': 'When the mail got successfully to Dover, in the course of the forenoon, the head drawer at the Royal George Hotel opened the coach-door as his custom was.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry say, ``I hope''?", 'source': "``I hope she will do well now,'' said Mr. Lorry.", 'answer': 'she will do well now'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry move in his chair?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry moved in his chair, and cast a troubled look towards the hospital procession of negro cupids.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What roused him?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'the arrival of his breakfast'}
{'question': 'Who am I am not so much to look at?', 'source': 'I am not so much to look at, am I?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'When shall I not go to bed?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': 'till night'}
{'question': 'Who is a mere machine?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Am Miss Manette I a man of business?', 'source': '``Miss Manette, I am a man of business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were it spun from?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': 'from filaments of silk or glass'}
{'question': 'What was it ever intended that I should go across?', 'source': "``If it was ever intended that I should go across salt water, do you suppose Providence would have cast my lot in an island?''", 'answer': 'across salt water'}
{'question': 'Who do Gentleman thank very gratefully?', 'source': 'I thank you very gratefully.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who had awaited his breakfast?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who have I done my best to prepare?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'What did I inform me that?', 'source': "``I received a letter from the Bank, sir, yesterday, informing me that some intelligence-- or discovery--''", 'answer': 'that some intelligence-- or discovery--'}
{'question': 'Who did he watch as she mused?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry lie stress upon as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': 'upon it'}
{'question': 'What have I passed from to another, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'from one'}
{'question': 'Who should be so much more at my ease about your state of mind?', 'source': "I should be so much more at my ease about your state of mind.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he await as he had awaited his breakfast?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'his dinner'}
{'question': 'What was the air among the houses of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed in?', 'source': 'The air among the houses was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it, as sick people went down to be dipped in the sea.', 'answer': 'sick fish went up to be dipped in it'}
{'question': 'What is it possible; though we will hope the best?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': 'almost a wreck'}
{'question': 'Did Miss Manette take this course with you?', 'source': 'Miss Manette, your mother took this course with you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Mr. Lorry quietly chafe the hands that held his arm?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry quietly chafed the hands that held his arm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she softly tend her with?', 'source': "There was an immediate dispersal for these restoratives, and she softly laid the patient on a sofa, and tended her with great skill and gentleness: calling her ``my precious!''", 'answer': 'with great skill and gentleness'}
{'question': 'What are my credentials?', 'source': "My credentials, entries, and memoranda, are all comprehended in the one line, ` Recalled to Life; ' which may mean anything.", 'answer': 'entries, and memoranda'}
{'question': 'Who has no feelings?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did she catch his wrist with?', 'source': 'And she caught his wrist with both her hands.', 'answer': 'with both her hands'}
{'question': 'Who do you confuse?', 'source': 'You confuse me, and how can I transact business if I am confused?', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What did the expression deepen as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry take the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does perhaps second-hand care come easily off and on?', 'source': "But, perhaps the confidential bachelor clerks in Tellson's Bank were principally occupied with the cares of other people; and perhaps second-hand cares, like second-hand clothes, come easily off and on.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did Mr. Lorry bring from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'his left hand'}
{'question': 'When do I have?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'no time for them'}
{'question': 'Is life duty?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is life rest?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who confuses me?', 'source': 'You confuse me, and how can I transact business if I am confused?', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Had other hands been?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was a large, dark room, furnished in a funereal manner with black horsehair, and loaded with heavy dark tables.', 'answer': 'a large, dark room'}
{'question': 'Is life comfort?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who can bear it?', 'source': "You can bear it?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who was I?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': 'one of the trustees'}
{'question': 'Who sat so still when he had very gently raised her?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What is the time for them?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': 'no chance of them'}
{'question': 'What was it remarkable?', 'source': 'Small tradesmen, who did no business whatever, sometimes unaccountably realized large fortunes, and it was remarkable that nobody in the neighborhood could endure a lamplighter.', 'answer': 'that nobody in the neighborhood could endure a lamplighter'}
{'question': 'What do I not much in travel yourself?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': 'in the habit of such'}
{'question': 'Who look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:?', 'source': 'Her look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What do I have?', 'source': 'I have a business charge to acquit myself of.', 'answer': 'a business charge to acquit myself of'}
{'question': 'Who was my time here?', 'source': 'That was before my time here, sir.', 'answer': 'sir'}
{'question': 'What did he say?', 'source': 'As he said the words he looked down, with an admiring pity, on the flowing golden hair; as if he pictured to himself that it might have been already tinged with gray.', 'answer': 'the words'}
{'question': 'Do I wish accommodation prepared for a young lady who may come here at any time to-day?', 'source': '``I wish accommodation prepared for a young lady who may come here at any time to-day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are _ collected?', 'source': '``You speak collectedly, and you-- _ are _ collected.', 'answer': 'you-- _'}
{'question': 'Who thankes you very gratefully?', 'source': 'I thank you very gratefully.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I pass?', 'source': "I pass my whole life, miss, in turning an immense pecuniary Mangle.''", 'answer': 'my whole life'}
{'question': 'Do here sir?', 'source': "Before our people's time here, sir.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the George in other hands at that time?', 'source': "The George was in other hands at that time, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sir, who do I thank indeed?', 'source': '``Sir, I thank you indeed.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry complete his resemblance to a man who was sitting for his portrait?', 'source': 'Completing his resemblance to a man who was sitting for his portrait, Mr. Lorry dropped off to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it remarkable that nobody in the neighborhood could endure a lamplighter?', 'source': 'Small tradesmen, who did no business whatever, sometimes unaccountably realized large fortunes, and it was remarkable that nobody in the neighborhood could endure a lamplighter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did a shiver run through her frame, and from it through?', 'source': 'A shiver ran through her frame, and from it through his.', 'answer': 'through his'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry resume his former attitude?', 'source': 'After this odd description of his daily routine of employment, Mr. Lorry flattened his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands (which was most unnecessary, for nothing could be flatter than its shining surface was before), and resumed his former attitude.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is life love?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who should hurt her?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What do I wish?', 'source': '``I wish accommodation prepared for a young lady who may come here at any time to-day.', 'answer': 'accommodation prepared for a young lady who may come here at any time to-day'}
{'question': 'What did she raise?', 'source': 'The young forehead lifted itself into that singular expression-- but it was pretty and characteristic, besides being singular-- and she raised her hand, as if with an involuntary action she caught at, or stayed some passing shadow.', 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'What are these?', 'source': 'These are mere business relations, miss; there is no friendship in them, no particular interest, nothing like sentiment.', 'answer': 'mere business relations'}
{'question': "Are my credentials all comprehended in the one line to Life; ' which may mean anything?", 'source': "My credentials, entries, and memoranda, are all comprehended in the one line, ` Recalled to Life; ' which may mean anything.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is this altogether?', 'source': 'This is a secret service altogether.', 'answer': 'a secret service'}
{'question': 'Who moved his chair to it?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is almost sure it was you?', 'source': "I am almost sure it was you.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry open his hands?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry opened his hands, and extended them outwards with an argumentative smile.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are you well on?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': 'on your way to the poor wronged gentleman'}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry flatten his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands?', 'source': 'After this odd description of his daily routine of employment, Mr. Lorry flattened his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands (which was most unnecessary, for nothing could be flatter than its shining surface was before), and resumed his former attitude.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was flatter's shining surface before?", 'source': 'After this odd description of his daily routine of employment, Mr. Lorry flattened his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands (which was most unnecessary, for nothing could be flatter than its shining surface was before), and resumed his former attitude.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were his affairs entirely in Tellson's hands?", 'source': "His affairs, like the affairs of many other French gentlemen and French families, were entirely in Tellson's hands.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does she not notice!', 'source': 'She does not notice a word!', 'answer': 'a word'}
{'question': "What did only one thing more lie upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': 'stress'}
{'question': 'Who does not notice a word!', 'source': 'She does not notice a word!', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What am I?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'a mere machine'}
{'question': "Important as they are to French credit do safe as an Englishman, and even Tellson's avoid all naming of the matter?", 'source': "Even I, safe as an Englishman, and even Tellson's, important as they are to French credit, avoid all naming of the matter.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do her look so discomposed that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:?', 'source': 'Her look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What do I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'what they are'}
{'question': 'Was it told me by the Bank that I must prepare myself to find them of a surprising nature?', 'source': 'It was told me by the Bank that the gentleman would explain to me the details of the business, and that I must prepare myself to find them of a surprising nature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he wear?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': 'an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig'}
{'question': 'What have I done to prepare myself?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'my best'}
{'question': "What did Pray bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What had he awaited?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': 'his breakfast'}
{'question': 'Would only one thing more be dangerous?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to make any inquiries, because it would be dangerous.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Monsieur Manette your father?', 'source': 'Like Monsieur Manette, your father, the gentleman was of Beauvais.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did Pray bring from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': 'his left hand'}
{'question': 'What did he make?', 'source': 'He made her another bow.', 'answer': 'her another bow'}
{'question': "Did the gentleman from Tellson's have nothing left for it?", 'source': "The gentleman from Tellson's had nothing left for it but to empty his glass with an air of stolid desperation, settle his odd little flaxen wig at the ears, and follow the waiter to Miss Manette's apartment.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who shall be more happy to execute it?', 'source': "I shall be more happy to execute it.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was his linen as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at?', 'source': 'His linen, though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings, was as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea.', 'answer': 'at sea'}
{'question': 'What did he set down?', 'source': 'He set down his glass untouched.', 'answer': 'his glass untouched'}
{'question': 'Is it fifteen years since we-- since I-- came last from France?', 'source': "It is fifteen years since we-- since I-- came last from France.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who should he hurt?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What can you bear?', 'source': "You can bear it?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did his face bear few traces of anxiety?', 'source': 'He had a healthy color in his cheeks, and his face, though lined, bore few traces of anxiety.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What should I be at my ease about your state of mind?', 'source': "I should be so much more at my ease about your state of mind.''", 'answer': 'so much more'}
{'question': 'What do I pass from one of our customers to?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'to another in the course of my business day'}
{'question': 'Who is sir?', 'source': "``Are you quite a stranger to me, sir?''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What did he feel?', 'source': 'He felt his wrist held closer, and he stopped.', 'answer': 'his wrist held closer'}
{'question': 'What did I have?', 'source': 'I had the honor of knowing him there.', 'answer': 'the honor of knowing him there'}
{'question': 'Was it told me by the Bank that the gentleman would explain to me the details of the business?', 'source': 'It was told me by the Bank that the gentleman would explain to me the details of the business, and that I must prepare myself to find them of a surprising nature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is so far, miss, this?', 'source': '``So far, miss (as you have remarked), this is the story of your regretted father.', 'answer': 'the story of your regretted father'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Lorry finished his breakfast?', 'source': 'When Mr. Lorry had finished his breakfast, he went out for a stroll on the beach.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she turn to Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'she said, indignantly turning to Mr. Lorry; ``could not you tell her what you had to tell her, without frightening her to death?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is me?', 'source': "``Are you quite a stranger to me, sir?''", 'answer': 'sir'}
{'question': 'Who speaks collectedly?', 'source': '``You speak collectedly, and you-- _ are _ collected.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who do I thank very gratefully?', 'source': 'I thank you very gratefully.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'As if _ do they _ had any help for anybody in their absurd baskets!', 'source': 'As if _ they _ had any help for anybody in their absurd baskets!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': 'a little vain of it'}
{'question': 'What did he move his chair to?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'to it'}
{'question': 'Has your father been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he settle the crisp flaxen wig at the ears?', 'source': "After a pause, he added, again settling the crisp flaxen wig at the ears, ``It is very difficult to begin.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did only one thing more lie stress upon as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': 'upon it'}
{'question': 'What should I be so much more at?', 'source': "I should be so much more at my ease about your state of mind.''", 'answer': 'at my ease about your state of mind'}
{'question': 'Did he go out for a stroll on the beach?', 'source': 'When Mr. Lorry had finished his breakfast, he went out for a stroll on the beach.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was an achievement to congratulate an adventurous traveller upon he did it with some flourish of ceremony in winter?', 'source': 'He did it with some flourish of ceremony, for a mail journey from London in winter was an achievement to congratulate an adventurous traveller upon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was his linen though of?', 'source': 'His linen, though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings, was as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea.', 'answer': 'though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings'}
{'question': 'Did he wear an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry shake himself out of it in chains of straw?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry, the passenger, shaking himself out of it in chains of straw, a tangle of shaggy wrapper, flapping hat, and muddy legs, was rather like a larger sort of dog.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall I not go to bed till night?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What 'll I let you know?", 'source': "I 'll let you know, if you do not bring smelling-salts, cold water, and vinegar, quick, I will.''", 'answer': 'I will'}
{'question': 'When would it be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know prisoner?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner.', 'answer': 'whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held'}
{'question': 'What did he move to it?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': 'his chair'}
{'question': 'What will (You find? )', 'source': '(You will find a fine sea-coal fire, sir. )', 'answer': 'a fine sea-coal fire'}
{'question': 'Who would it be worse than useless now to?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner.', 'answer': 'to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner'}
{'question': 'Was the coach with its damp and dirty straw?', 'source': 'The mildewy inside of the coach, with its damp and dirty straw, its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, was rather like a larger dog-kennel.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was no other occupant, that forenoon, than the gentleman in brown's breakfast-table drawn before the fire?", 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remain standing between?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': 'between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose'}
{'question': 'Who do Gentleman think after?', 'source': "The gentleman had left London, but I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here.''", 'answer': 'a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here'}
{'question': 'Will (You find a fine sea-coal fire? )', 'source': '(You will find a fine sea-coal fire, sir. )', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will relate to you the story of one of our customers?', 'source': "I will, with your leave, relate to you, miss, the story of one of our customers.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was it told me by the Bank of?', 'source': 'It was told me by the Bank that the gentleman would explain to me the details of the business, and that I must prepare myself to find them of a surprising nature.', 'answer': 'that I must prepare myself to find them of a surprising nature'}
{'question': 'Were his affairs like the affairs of many other French gentlemen and French families?', 'source': "His affairs, like the affairs of many other French gentlemen and French families, were entirely in Tellson's hands.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who I will relate to you?', 'source': "I will, with your leave, relate to you, miss, the story of one of our customers.''", 'answer': 'the story of one of our customers'}
{'question': 'Did the young forehead lift itself into that singular expression?', 'source': 'The young forehead lifted itself into that singular expression-- but it was pretty and characteristic, besides being singular-- and she raised her hand, as if with an involuntary action she caught at, or stayed some passing shadow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the sea do?', 'source': 'The beach was a desert of heaps of sea and stones tumbling wildly about, and the sea did what it liked, and what it liked was destruction.', 'answer': 'what it liked'}
{'question': 'Who thinks?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was Miss Manette your mother?', 'source': 'Miss Manette, your mother took this course with you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who passes from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do I naturally have?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': 'a strong and eager interest to know what they are'}
{'question': 'Did she softly lay the patient on a sofa?', 'source': "There was an immediate dispersal for these restoratives, and she softly laid the patient on a sofa, and tended her with great skill and gentleness: calling her ``my precious!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I pass from to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': 'from one of our customers'}
{'question': 'Who mused?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "Do you kneel to me in Heaven's name?", 'source': "In Heaven's name why should you kneel to me!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did which look far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he call out loudly for assistance without moving?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When was that?', 'source': 'That was before my time here, sir.', 'answer': 'before my time here'}
{'question': 'Did it thunder at the cliffs?', 'source': 'It thundered at the town, and thundered at the cliffs, and brought the coast down, madly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he put it with some ceremony to his lips?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took the hesitating little hand that confidingly advanced to take his, and he put it with some ceremony to his lips.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the air among the houses of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it?', 'source': 'The air among the houses was of so strong a piscatory flavor that one might have supposed sick fish went up to be dipped in it, as sick people went down to be dipped in the sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it bring the coast down?', 'source': 'It thundered at the town, and thundered at the cliffs, and brought the coast down, madly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are the best and the worst known to you?', 'source': 'The best and the worst are known to you, now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it possible; though we will hope the best almost a wreck?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were our relations business relations?', 'source': 'Our relations were business relations, but confidential.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his breakfast-table drawn before the fire?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked?', 'source': 'Very orderly and methodical he looked, with a hand on each knee, and a loud watch ticking a sonorous sermon under his flapped waist-coat, as though it pitted its gravity and longevity against the levity and evanescence of the brisk fire.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did he marry-- an English lady?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who said?', 'source': 'She said, in a low, distinct, awe-stricken voice, as if she were saying it in a dream,', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Are we quite a French House?', 'source': "We are quite a French House, as well as an English one.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who I will relate to the story of one of our customers?', 'source': "I will, with your leave, relate to you, miss, the story of one of our customers.''", 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Did it thunder at the town?', 'source': 'It thundered at the town, and thundered at the cliffs, and brought the coast down, madly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who sat so still?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is going to?', 'source': 'I am going to.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who will hope the best?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'What will we hope?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': 'the best'}
{'question': 'Were it spun from filaments of silk or glass?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were he of a fine texture?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are these mere business relations?', 'source': 'These are mere business relations, miss; there is no friendship in them, no particular interest, nothing like sentiment.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is me?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': 'a scrap of writing openly referring to all naming of the matter'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry lie stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I-- come last from France?', 'source': "It is fifteen years since we-- since I-- came last from France.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you-- _ _ collected?', 'source': '``You speak collectedly, and you-- _ are _ collected.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he set very close to?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': 'to his head: which wig was made of hair'}
{'question': 'Did he await his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were so much more steady than they had been?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': 'the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists'}
{'question': 'Do you have business before you; useful business?', 'source': 'You have business before you; useful business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here?', 'source': "The gentleman had left London, but I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where will you be soon?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': 'at his dear side'}
{'question': 'Would it be so encouraging for instance?', 'source': 'If you could kindly mention now, for instance, what nine times ninepence are, or how many shillings in twenty guineas, it would be so encouraging.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was its damp and dirty straw?', 'source': 'The mildewy inside of the coach, with its damp and dirty straw, its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, was rather like a larger dog-kennel.', 'answer': 'its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity,'}
{'question': 'Did he say to the drawer?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a large, dark room?', 'source': 'It was a large, dark room, furnished in a funereal manner with black horsehair, and loaded with heavy dark tables.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the other occupant that forenoon?', 'source': 'The coffee-room had no other occupant, that forenoon, than the gentleman in brown.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I want a bedroom, and a barber?', 'source': "``I shall not go to bed till night; but I want a bedroom, and a barber.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it very difficult to begin after a pause?', 'source': "After a pause, he added, again settling the crisp flaxen wig at the ears, ``It is very difficult to begin.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it be worse than useless now to make any inquiries?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to make any inquiries, because it would be dangerous.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do we have oftentimes the honor to entertain your gentlemen in their traveling backwards and forwards betwixt London and Paris?', 'source': 'We have oftentimes the honor to entertain your gentlemen in their traveling backwards and forwards betwixt London and Paris, sir.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will be his Ghost-- not him!', 'source': "It will be his Ghost-- not him!''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who will be soon at his dear side?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': 'a young lady who may come here at any time to-day'}
{'question': 'Who sat?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Had the forehead so particularly attracted his notice, and which was now immovable, had?', 'source': 'The expression in the forehead, which had so particularly attracted his notice, and which was now immovable, had deepened into one of pain and horror.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit before the coffee-room fire?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his mind busily digging?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he seem wilfully to mistake the word she had repeated?', 'source': 'He seemed wilfully to mistake the word she had repeated, when he added, in a hurry, ``Yes, customers; in the banking business we usually call our connection our customers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have a healthy color in his cheeks?', 'source': 'He had a healthy color in his cheeks, and his face, though lined, bore few traces of anxiety.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have a good leg?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she catch his wrist with both her hands?', 'source': 'And she caught his wrist with both her hands.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she take her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I one of the trustees?', 'source': 'He married-- an English lady-- and I was one of the trustees.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the arrival of his breakfast rouse him?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he wait for the meal?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have a business charge to acquit myself of?', 'source': 'I have a business charge to acquit myself of.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I a mere machine?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did?', 'source': 'She did, indeed, start.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'So far, miss, is this the story of your regretted father?', 'source': '``So far, miss (as you have remarked), this is the story of your regretted father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a shiver run through her frame, and from it through his?', 'source': 'A shiver ran through her frame, and from it through his.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry say, ``I hope she will do well now''?", 'source': "``I hope she will do well now,'' said Mr. Lorry.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that before my time here?', 'source': 'That was before my time here, sir.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it ever intended across?', 'source': "``If it was ever intended that I should go across salt water, do you suppose Providence would have cast my lot in an island?''", 'answer': 'that I should go across salt water'}
{'question': 'Who do I think after?', 'source': "The gentleman had left London, but I think a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here.''", 'answer': 'a messenger was sent after him to beg the favor of his waiting for me here'}
{'question': 'Did I have the honor of knowing him there?', 'source': 'I had the honor of knowing him there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do her look so discomposed him:?', 'source': 'Her look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:', 'answer': 'that he stopped, wandered, and began anew'}
{'question': 'Do you speak collectedly?', 'source': '``You speak collectedly, and you-- _ are _ collected.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his shoes and buckles trim?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she softly tend her with great skill and gentleness?', 'source': "There was an immediate dispersal for these restoratives, and she softly laid the patient on a sofa, and tended her with great skill and gentleness: calling her ``my precious!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who pleases, ?', 'source': "``If you please, sir.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Are you well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had been?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "'ll I let you know I will?", 'source': "I 'll let you know, if you do not bring smelling-salts, cold water, and vinegar, quick, I will.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he set very close to his head: which wig was made of hair?', 'source': 'He wore an odd little sleek crisp flaxen wig, setting very close to his head: which wig, it is to be presumed, was made of hair, but which looked far more as though it were spun from filaments of silk or glass.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was a face habitually quieted still lighted up under the quaint wig by a pair of moist bright eyes?', 'source': "A face habitually suppressed and quieted, was still lighted up under the quaint wig by a pair of moist bright eyes that it must have cost their owner, in years gone by, some pains to drill to the composed and reserved expression of Tellson's Bank.", 'answer': 'that it must have cost their owner'}
{'question': 'Was close her hold upon his arm?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I done my best to prepare myself?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was a face habitually suppressed still lighted up under the quaint wig by a pair of moist bright eyes?', 'source': "A face habitually suppressed and quieted, was still lighted up under the quaint wig by a pair of moist bright eyes that it must have cost their owner, in years gone by, some pains to drill to the composed and reserved expression of Tellson's Bank.", 'answer': 'that it must have cost their owner'}
{'question': 'Are my credentials entries, and memoranda?', 'source': "My credentials, entries, and memoranda, are all comprehended in the one line, ` Recalled to Life; ' which may mean anything.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I carry about me?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have no feelings?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I inform me that some intelligence-- or discovery--?', 'source': "``I received a letter from the Bank, sir, yesterday, informing me that some intelligence-- or discovery--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the expression deepen itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I going to see his Ghost!', 'source': '``I am going to see his Ghost!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he watch her as she mused?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall I be more happy to execute it?', 'source': "I shall be more happy to execute it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life?', 'source': "Your father has been taken to the house of an old servant in Paris, and we are going there: I, to identify him if I can: you, to restore him to life, love, duty, rest, comfort.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was its damp and dirty straw its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, ?', 'source': 'The mildewy inside of the coach, with its damp and dirty straw, its disagreeable smell, and its obscurity, was rather like a larger dog-kennel.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will we hope the best?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had?', 'source': '``You know that your parents had no great possession, and that what they had was secured to your mother and to you.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who had?', 'source': '``You know that your parents had no great possession, and that what they had was secured to your mother and to you.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did she curtsey to him?', 'source': 'She curtseyed to him (young ladies made curtseys in those days), with a pretty desire to convey to him that she felt how much older and wiser he was than she.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he a little vain of it?', 'source': 'He had a good leg, and was a little vain of it, for his brown stockings fitted sleek and close, and were of a fine texture; his shoes and buckles, too, though plain, were trim.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will you be soon at?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': 'at his dear side'}
{'question': 'Have I passed from one to another, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is this a secret service altogether?', 'source': 'This is a secret service altogether.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will it be-- not him!', 'source': "It will be his Ghost-- not him!''", 'answer': 'his Ghost'}
{'question': 'I will relate to you the story of one of our customers?', 'source': "I will, with your leave, relate to you, miss, the story of one of our customers.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he say the words?', 'source': 'As he said the words he looked down, with an admiring pity, on the flowing golden hair; as if he pictured to himself that it might have been already tinged with gray.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I pass my whole life?', 'source': "I pass my whole life, miss, in turning an immense pecuniary Mangle.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look down?', 'source': 'As he said the words he looked down, with an admiring pity, on the flowing golden hair; as if he pictured to himself that it might have been already tinged with gray.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was my time here sir?', 'source': 'That was before my time here, sir.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's right?", 'source': "``That's right, that's right.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it ever intended that I should go across salt water?', 'source': "``If it was ever intended that I should go across salt water, do you suppose Providence would have cast my lot in an island?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he feel his wrist held closer?', 'source': 'He felt his wrist held closer, and he stopped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it be dangerous?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to make any inquiries, because it would be dangerous.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are?', 'source': "I have done my best to prepare myself, and I naturally have a strong and eager interest to know what they are.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does she not notice a word!', 'source': 'She does not notice a word!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does a bottle of good claret after dinner do a digger in the red coals no harm, otherwise than as it has a tendency to throw him out of work?', 'source': 'A bottle of good claret after dinner does a digger in the red coals no harm, otherwise than as it has a tendency to throw him out of work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should I be so much more at my ease about your state of mind?', 'source': "I should be so much more at my ease about your state of mind.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I I am not so much to look at?', 'source': 'I am not so much to look at, am I?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is me a scrap of writing openly referring to it?', 'source': 'I carry about me, not a scrap of writing openly referring to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his linen as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea?', 'source': 'His linen, though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings, was as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you be soon at his dear side?', 'source': "You are well on your way to the poor wronged gentleman, and, with a fair sea voyage, and a fair land journey, you will be soon at his dear side.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stop?', 'source': 'He felt his wrist held closer, and he stopped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have no time for them?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Pray bring his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business''?", 'source': "``Pray,'' said Mr. Lorry, in a soothing tone, bringing his left hand from the back of the chair to lay it on the supplicatory fingers that clasped him in so violent a tremble: ``pray control your agitation-- a matter of business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I going to?', 'source': 'I am going to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I almost sure it was you?', 'source': "I am almost sure it was you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she raise her hand?', 'source': 'The young forehead lifted itself into that singular expression-- but it was pretty and characteristic, besides being singular-- and she raised her hand, as if with an involuntary action she caught at, or stayed some passing shadow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the time for them no chance of them?', 'source': 'I have no time for them, no chance of them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will it be his Ghost-- not him!', 'source': "It will be his Ghost-- not him!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she say?', 'source': 'She said, in a low, distinct, awe-stricken voice, as if she were saying it in a dream,', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do her look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:?', 'source': 'Her look so discomposed him that he stopped, wandered, and began anew:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you confuse me?', 'source': 'You confuse me, and how can I transact business if I am confused?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make her another bow?', 'source': 'He made her another bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not much in the habit of such travel yourself?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he set down his glass untouched?', 'source': 'He set down his glass untouched.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it too probable?', 'source': 'Greatly changed, it is too probable; almost a wreck, it is possible; though we will hope the best.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remain standing between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is me sir?', 'source': "``Are you quite a stranger to me, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's good!", 'source': "That's good!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his linen though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings?', 'source': 'His linen, though not of a fineness in accordance with his stockings, was as white as the tops of the waves that broke upon the neighbouring beach, or the specks of sail that glinted in the sunlight far at sea.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he awaited his breakfast?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he move his chair to it?', 'source': 'The arrival of his breakfast roused him, and he said to the drawer, as he moved his chair to it:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Sir, do I thank you indeed?', 'source': '``Sir, I thank you indeed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think?', 'source': "Not much in the habit of such traveling yourself, I think, sir?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she sit so still when he had very gently raised her?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit so still?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was its shining surface before?', 'source': 'After this odd description of his daily routine of employment, Mr. Lorry flattened his flaxen wig upon his head with both hands (which was most unnecessary, for nothing could be flatter than its shining surface was before), and resumed his former attitude.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she muse?', 'source': 'He watched her as she mused, and the moment she raised her eyes again, went on:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look?', 'source': 'Very orderly and methodical he looked, with a hand on each knee, and a loud watch ticking a sonorous sermon under his flapped waist-coat, as though it pitted its gravity and longevity against the levity and evanescence of the brisk fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did only one thing more lie stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own''?", 'source': "``Only one thing more,'' said Mr. Lorry, laying stress upon it as a wholesome means of enforcing her attention: ``he has been found under another name; his own, long forgotten or long concealed.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his custom?', 'source': 'When the mail got successfully to Dover, in the course of the forenoon, the head drawer at the Royal George Hotel opened the coach-door as his custom was.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you bear it?', 'source': "You can bear it?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will?', 'source': '``I will.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Was it possible to be?', 'source': 'Between the eyebrows and just over the little feminine nose, the line of which was as delicate and fine as it was possible to be, the expression deepened itself as she took her seat thoughtfully in the chair by which she had hitherto remained standing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Should he hurt her?', 'source': 'So close was her hold upon his arm, that he feared to detach himself lest he should hurt her; therefore he called out loudly for assistance without moving.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists so much more steady than they had been?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she do?', 'source': 'She did, indeed, start.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he alive?', 'source': 'He is alive.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit?', 'source': 'His breakfast-table was drawn before the fire, and as he sat, with its light shining on him, waiting for the meal, he sat so still, that he might have been sitting for his portrait.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they been?', 'source': 'Without directly answering to this appeal, she sat so still when he had very gently raised her, and the hands that had not ceased to clasp his wrists were so much more steady than they had been, that she communicated some reassurance to Mr. Jarvis Lorry.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I thank you very gratefully?', 'source': 'I thank you very gratefully.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it dark?', 'source': 'When it was dark, and he sat before the coffee-room fire, awaiting his dinner as he had awaited his breakfast, his mind was busily digging, digging, digging, in the live red coals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'I will?', 'source': '``I will.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you please?', 'source': "``If you please, sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they have?', 'source': '``You know that your parents had no great possession, and that what they had was secured to your mother and to you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner?', 'source': 'It would be worse than useless now to inquire which; worse than useless to seek to know whether he has been for years overlooked, or always designedly held prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day?', 'source': 'I have passed from one to another, in the course of my business life, just as I pass from one of our customers to another in the course of my business day; in short, I have no feelings; I am a mere machine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027?', 'source': 'After becoming a monk at the monastery at Winchester, he was appointed Abbot of Tavistock Abbey in around 1027.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he work to bring one of the king's relatives back to England from Hungary to secure an heir for the childless king?", 'source': "He worked to bring one of the king's relatives, Edward the Exile, back to England from Hungary to secure an heir for the childless king.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he named to the Bishopric of Worcester in 1046?', 'source': 'In 1046 he was named to the Bishopric of Worcester.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he related to a number of other ecclesiastics of the period?', 'source': 'He was related to a number of other ecclesiastics of the period.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five conduct their Greatnesses, and myriads of small creatures along the roads that lay before them?', 'source': 'Thus did the year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five conduct their Greatnesses, and myriads of small creatures-- the creatures of this chronicle among the rest-- along the roads that lay before them.', 'answer': 'thus'}
{'question': 'What did all these things, and a thousand like them, come to close upon the dear old year?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five'}
{'question': 'What was it the year of?', 'source': 'It was the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five'}
{'question': "Was Mrs. Southcott's five-and-twentieth blessed birthday of whom a prophetic private in the Life Guards had heralded the sublime appearance by announcing that arrangements were made for the swallowing up of London and Westminster?", 'source': 'Mrs. Southcott had recently attained her five-and-twentieth blessed birthday, of whom a prophetic private in the Life Guards had heralded the sublime appearance by announcing that arrangements were made for the swallowing up of London and Westminster.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did all these things, and a thousand like there, come to close upon the dear old year?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five'}
{'question': 'Were spiritual revelations conceded to England at that favored period?', 'source': 'Spiritual revelations were conceded to England at that favored period, as at this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it clearer than crystal to the lords of the State preserves of loaves and fishes in both countries?', 'source': 'In both countries it was clearer than crystal to the lords of the State preserves of loaves and fishes, that things in general were settled for ever.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'It was the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'When was it?', 'source': 'It was the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five'}
{'question': 'Did France roll with spending it?', 'source': 'France, less favored on the whole as to matters spiritual than her sister of the shield and trident, rolled with exceeding smoothness down hill, making paper money and spending it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did thus do the year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five conduct their Greatnesses, and myriads of small creatures along the roads that lay before them?', 'source': 'Thus did the year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five conduct their Greatnesses, and myriads of small creatures-- the creatures of this chronicle among the rest-- along the roads that lay before them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all these things, and a thousand like them, come to pass in?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was France less favored on the whole as to matters spiritual than her sister of the shield and trident?', 'source': 'France, less favored on the whole as to matters spiritual than her sister of the shield and trident, rolled with exceeding smoothness down hill, making paper money and spending it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all these things, and a thousand like there, come to pass in?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was her five-and-twentieth blessed birthday of whom a prophetic private in the Life Guards had heralded the sublime appearance by announcing that arrangements were made for the swallowing up of London and Westminster?', 'source': 'Mrs. Southcott had recently attained her five-and-twentieth blessed birthday, of whom a prophetic private in the Life Guards had heralded the sublime appearance by announcing that arrangements were made for the swallowing up of London and Westminster.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did all these things, and a thousand like them, come to close one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'upon the dear old year'}
{'question': 'When did all these things, and a thousand like there, come to close one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': 'upon the dear old year'}
{'question': 'Did all these things, and a thousand like them, come to close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'It was the year of Our Lord one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all these things, and a thousand like there, come to close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five?', 'source': 'All these things, and a thousand like them, came to pass in and close upon the dear old year one thousand seven hundred and seventy-five.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you know?', 'source': 'You know all the men of this part of the country.', 'answer': 'all the men of this part of the country'}
{'question': 'Who did he turn sideways to the carriage?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Do Monseigneur, hear my petition!', 'source': 'Monseigneur, hear my petition!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the carriage present herself at?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': 'at the carriage-door'}
{'question': 'Was the wonder of it Monseigneur?', 'source': '``With your gracious permission, that was the wonder of it, Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was its poor brewery?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': 'poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses'}
{'question': 'Who looked an old woman?', 'source': 'She looked an old woman, but was young.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "What was that the wonder of, ``With the chain of the shoe-- the drag's gracious permission''?", 'source': '``With your gracious permission, that was the wonder of it, Monseigneur.', 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'Does a person plunge into the river?', 'source': "``Monseigneur, he precipitated himself over the hill-side, head first, as a person plunges into the river.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Monseigneur, hear me!', 'source': '``Monseigneur, hear me!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had its one poor street?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': 'the village'}
{'question': 'Who saw him of all the days of my life?', 'source': "Of all the days of my life, I never saw him.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did she look?', 'source': 'She looked an old woman, but was young.', 'answer': 'an old woman'}
{'question': 'Were few children to be seen?', 'source': 'Few children were to be seen, and no dogs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he stoop?', 'source': 'He stooped a little, and with his tattered blue cap pointed under the carriage.', 'answer': 'a little'}
{'question': 'What was their choice on earth stated in the prospect-- Life on?', 'source': 'As to the men and women, their choice on earth was stated in the prospect-- Life on the lowest terms that could sustain it, down in the little village under the mill; or captivity and Death in the dominant prison on the crag.', 'answer': 'on the lowest terms that could sustain it'}
{'question': 'Who do that expect?', 'source': "``Monsieur Charles, whom I expect; is he arrived from England?''", 'answer': 'Charles'}
{'question': 'Who did that turn sideways to the carriage?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Was the hill-side head?', 'source': "``Monseigneur, he precipitated himself over the hill-side, head first, as a person plunges into the river.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did that turn himself sideways to?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'to the carriage'}
{'question': "Who said, ``Truly, you did well''?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': "Who was the Marquis felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle that, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'of yours'}
{'question': "Who was felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle that, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of yours?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'What was it hard by?', 'source': 'It was hard by the fountain, and the peasants suspended their operations to look at him.', 'answer': 'by the fountain'}
{'question': 'What had he held examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner?', 'source': 'Monsieur Gabelle was the Postmaster, and some other taxing functionary united; he had come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination, and had held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner.', 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': 'What was hard by the fountain?', 'source': 'It was hard by the fountain, and the peasants suspended their operations to look at him.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was the fellow brought?', 'source': 'The fellow was brought, cap in hand, and the other fellows closed round to look and listen, in the manner of the people at the Paris fountain.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she turn as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': 'her head'}
{'question': 'What did I have?', 'source': "I had the honor of being passed on the road.''", 'answer': 'the honor of being passed on the road'}
{'question': 'What does he lie?', 'source': "But he lies yonder, under a little heap of poor grass.''", 'answer': 'yonder'}
{'question': 'Who lies yonder?', 'source': "But he lies yonder, under a little heap of poor grass.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did I see of all the days of my life?', 'source': "Of all the days of my life, I never saw him.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What was he not of?', 'source': 'He was not of this part of the country.', 'answer': 'of this part of the country'}
{'question': 'What had he held the examined by the drapery of his arm in?', 'source': 'Monsieur Gabelle was the Postmaster, and some other taxing functionary united; he had come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination, and had held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner.', 'answer': 'in an official manner'}
{'question': "Who said, ``Truly, that did well''?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'Are again so many there is so much want?', 'source': 'Monseigneur, they are so many, they increase so fast, there is so much want.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who made a bow?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, is the road true?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, it is true.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the village have its poor people too?', 'source': 'It had its poor people too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Monseigneur, hear!', 'source': '``Monseigneur, hear me!', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did some half-dozen other particular friends present him breathless to Monsieur the Marquis?', 'source': 'Some half-dozen other particular friends promptly hauled him out, and presented him breathless to Monsieur the Marquis.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked at them?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who saw in them?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he make?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'a bow'}
{'question': 'What came up to her?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': 'the carriage'}
{'question': 'Did it subside to a foot pace among the many sweet scents of a summer night?', 'source': 'Gradually, it subsided to a foot pace, swinging and lumbering upward among the many sweet scents of a summer night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had Monsieur Gabelle come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination?', 'source': 'Monsieur Gabelle was the Postmaster, and some other taxing functionary united; he had come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination, and had held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does that lie?', 'source': "But he lies yonder, under a little heap of poor grass.''", 'answer': 'yonder'}
{'question': 'What are again so many?', 'source': 'Monseigneur, they are so many, they increase so fast, there is so much want.', 'answer': 'there is so much want'}
{'question': 'Was a blush on the countenance of Monsieur the Marquis no impeachment of his high breeding?', 'source': 'A blush on the countenance of Monsieur the Marquis was no impeachment of his high breeding; it was not from within; it was occasioned by an external circumstance beyond his control-- the setting sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do the man's husband forester?", 'source': "My husband, the forester.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who then recovered himself?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who does not ask it?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, the good God knows; but I do not ask it.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he turn himself sideways to?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'to the carriage'}
{'question': 'Did Monseigneur look out with his unchangeable face?', 'source': 'With an exclamation of impatience, but with his unchangeable face, Monseigneur looked out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are so many there is so much want?', 'source': 'Monseigneur, they are so many, they increase so fast, there is so much want.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'When did I see him?', 'source': "Of all the days of my life, I never saw him.''", 'answer': 'of all the days of my life'}
{'question': 'What had its poor people too?', 'source': 'It had its poor people too.', 'answer': 'the village'}
{'question': "Who was the Marquis felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'of yours'}
{'question': "Who was felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of yours?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'Did the wheels turn so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the carriage rise quickly?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did that make?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'a bow'}
{'question': 'Might the wheels not have been so fortunate?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May do the Devil carry away these idiots!', 'source': '``May the Devil carry away these idiots!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did the carriage come up to?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': 'to her'}
{'question': 'The wheels had very little else to save?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he see in?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'in them'}
{'question': 'Who did he look at?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'at them'}
{'question': 'What did he see in?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'in them'}
{'question': 'What did he look at?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': 'at them'}
{'question': 'Who did he then recover?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Who did he have?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': 'any spectre on his conscience'}
{'question': 'What do I not ask?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, the good God knows; but I do not ask it.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, was he whiter than the miller?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, he was whiter than the miller.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is the man's husband the?", 'source': "My husband, the forester.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who cannot pay something?', 'source': "He cannot pay something?''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What can he not pay?', 'source': "He cannot pay something?''", 'answer': 'something'}
{'question': 'Who did that then recover?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What is my husband?', 'source': "My husband, the forester.''", 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': 'Was its poor brewery poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, was that whiter than the miller?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, he was whiter than the miller.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all his fellows stoop to look under the carriage?', 'source': 'All his fellows stooped to look under the carriage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did that have?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': 'any spectre on his conscience'}
{'question': 'Had he come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination?', 'source': 'Monsieur Gabelle was the Postmaster, and some other taxing functionary united; he had come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination, and had held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I have the honor of being passed on the road?', 'source': "I had the honor of being passed on the road.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do Life know all the men of this part of the country?', 'source': 'You know all the men of this part of the country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do that not ask?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, the good God knows; but I do not ask it.', 'answer': 'again'}
{'question': 'Do I expect Charles?', 'source': "``Monsieur Charles, whom I expect; is he arrived from England?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do to observe whether that had any spectre on his conscience?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did some half-dozen other particular friends promptly haul him out?', 'source': 'Some half-dozen other particular friends promptly hauled him out, and presented him breathless to Monsieur the Marquis.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Round upon all these darkening objects as the night draw on with the air of one who was coming near home?', 'source': 'Round upon all these darkening objects as the night drew on, the Marquis looked, with the air of one who was coming near home.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Pardon not of this part of the country?', 'source': 'He was not of this part of the country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you know all the men of this part of the country?', 'source': 'You know all the men of this part of the country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it have too?', 'source': 'It had its poor people too.', 'answer': 'its poor people'}
{'question': 'Do that expect Charles?', 'source': "``Monsieur Charles, whom I expect; is he arrived from England?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was young?', 'source': 'She looked an old woman, but was young.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was their choice on earth stated in the prospect-- Life on the lowest terms that could sustain it?', 'source': 'As to the men and women, their choice on earth was stated in the prospect-- Life on the lowest terms that could sustain it, down in the little village under the mill; or captivity and Death in the dominant prison on the crag.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the carriage present herself at the carriage-door?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was its poor brewery poor tannery?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the village have its one poor street?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he lie yonder?', 'source': "But he lies yonder, under a little heap of poor grass.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it occasioned by an external circumstance beyond his control-- the setting sun?', 'source': 'A blush on the countenance of Monsieur the Marquis was no impeachment of his high breeding; it was not from within; it was occasioned by an external circumstance beyond his control-- the setting sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he not of this part of the country?', 'source': 'He was not of this part of the country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was its poor brewery poor tavern?', 'source': 'The village had its one poor street, with its poor brewery, poor tannery, poor tavern, poor stable-yard for relays of post-horses, poor fountain, all usual poor appointments.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was that the wonder of it, ``With the chain of the shoe-- the drag's gracious permission''?", 'source': '``With your gracious permission, that was the wonder of it, Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who leaned back?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did she look an old woman?', 'source': 'She looked an old woman, but was young.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner?', 'source': 'Monsieur Gabelle was the Postmaster, and some other taxing functionary united; he had come out with great obsequiousness to assist at this examination, and had held the examined by the drapery of his arm in an official manner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that have any spectre on his conscience?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stoop a little?', 'source': 'He stooped a little, and with his tattered blue cap pointed under the carriage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a woman kneeling to this distressful emblem of a great distress that had long been growing worse, and was not at its worst?', 'source': 'To this distressful emblem of a great distress that had long been growing worse, and was not at its worst, a woman was kneeling.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had very little else to save?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was it hard by the fountain?', 'source': 'It was hard by the fountain, and the peasants suspended their operations to look at him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that turn himself sideways to the carriage?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who might not have been so fortunate?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Did the Marquis say, ``Truly, you did well''?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does that lie yonder?', 'source': "But he lies yonder, under a little heap of poor grass.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she turn her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was that the wonder of it, ``With your gracious permission''?", 'source': '``With your gracious permission, that was the wonder of it, Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is dead?', 'source': "He is dead.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is quiet?', 'source': 'He is quiet.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the peasants suspend their operations to look at him?', 'source': 'It was hard by the fountain, and the peasants suspended their operations to look at him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make a bow?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Marquis say, ``Truly, that did well''?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did my husband die of want?', 'source': "My husband died of want; so many die of want; so many more will die of want.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I see him of all the days of my life?', 'source': "Of all the days of my life, I never saw him.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the carriage come up to her?', 'source': 'She turned her head as the carriage came up to her, rose quickly, and presented herself at the carriage-door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are they so many there is so much want?', 'source': 'Monseigneur, they are so many, they increase so fast, there is so much want.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have any spectre on his conscience?', 'source': 'Perhaps, to observe whether he had any spectre on his conscience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are they so many?', 'source': 'Monseigneur, they are so many, they increase so fast, there is so much want.', 'answer': 'there is so much want'}
{'question': 'Did that make a bow?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn himself sideways to the carriage?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do my husband forester?', 'source': "My husband, the forester.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did that's husband die of want?", 'source': "My husband died of want; so many die of want; so many more will die of want.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, is it true?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, it is true.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the Marquis felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle that, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of yours?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that then recover himself?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can he not pay something?', 'source': "He cannot pay something?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do that not ask again?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, the good God knows; but I do not ask it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not from within?', 'source': 'A blush on the countenance of Monsieur the Marquis was no impeachment of his high breeding; it was not from within; it was occasioned by an external circumstance beyond his control-- the setting sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lean back?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she young?', 'source': 'She looked an old woman, but was young.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he see in them?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look at them?', 'source': 'He looked at them, and saw in them, without knowing it, the slow sure filing down of misery-worn face and figure, that was to make the meagreness of Frenchmen an English superstition which should survive the truth through the best part of a hundred years.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is that's petition?", 'source': "My petition is, that a morsel of stone or wood, with my husband's name, may be placed over him to show where he lies.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my petition?', 'source': "My petition is, that a morsel of stone or wood, with my husband's name, may be placed over him to show where he lies.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my husband the?', 'source': "My husband, the forester.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the Marquis felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage'', and not open that great mouth of yours?", 'source': "``Truly, you did well,'' said the Marquis, felicitously sensible that such vermin were not to ruffle him, ``to see a thief accompanying my carriage, and not open that great mouth of yours.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he then recover himself?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not ask it?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, the good God knows; but I do not ask it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that lean back?', 'source': 'He turned himself sideways to the carriage, and leaned back, with his face thrown up to the sky, and his head hanging down; then recovered himself, fumbled with his cap, and made a bow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might they not have been so fortunate?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'They had very little else to save?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he dead?', 'source': "He is dead.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is he quiet?', 'source': 'He is quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it have its poor people too?', 'source': 'It had its poor people too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the wheels turn so suddenly?', 'source': 'The half-dozen who were peering at the chain were still among the wheels, like sheep; the wheels turned so suddenly that they were lucky to save their skins and bones; they had very little else to save, or they might not have been so fortunate.', 'answer': 'that they were lucky to save their skins and bones'}
{'question': "Was the nephew in the polished uncle's former tone?", 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were his finger the fine point of?', 'source': 'Once again he touched him on the breast, as though his finger were the fine point of a small sword, with which, in delicate finesse, he ran him through the body, and said,', 'answer': 'of a small sword'}
{'question': 'What did that fountain cry, ?', 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': 'Dead'}
{'question': 'Are the trees and the night all that are here?', 'source': "The trees and the night are all that are here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was me?', 'source': "``Seeking them from me, my nephew,'' said the Marquis, touching him on the breast with his forefinger-- they were now standing by the hearth-- ``you will for ever seek them in vain, be assured.''", 'answer': 'my nephew'}
{'question': 'What did his tone linger in?', 'source': 'His tone lingered in the air, almost like the tone of a musical instrument.', 'answer': 'in the air'}
{'question': 'What did it come up to?', 'source': 'It came on briskly, and came up to the front of the chateau.', 'answer': 'to the front of the chateau'}
{'question': "Is fear and slavery the Marquis's friend?", 'source': "The dark deference of fear and slavery, my friend,'' observed the Marquis, ``will keep the dogs obedient to the whip, as long as this roof,'' looking up to it, ``shuts out the sky.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could the Marquis becomingly be of a country still containing himself?', 'source': 'The Marquis took a gentle little pinch of snuff, and shook his head; as elegantly despondent as he could becomingly be of a country still containing himself, that great means of regeneration.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who added to himself?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': 'the imperturbable master'}
{'question': 'Do the ringing of the bell now shine brightly?', 'source': 'It now shone brightly, through the door of communication.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the posting-houses not shake hands?', 'source': 'Monseigneur received him in a courtly manner, but they did not shake hands.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the midst of a group of fifty particular friends portend that there was one stone face too many at the chateau?', 'source': 'It portended that there was one stone face too many, up at the chateau.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a fine mask make angry, and petrified?', 'source': 'It was like a fine mask, suddenly startled, made angry, and petrified.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he say to?', 'source': 'he said to Monseigneur, as he took his seat at table.', 'answer': 'to Monseigneur'}
{'question': 'Did the uncle sip his coffee?', 'source': "``I do not quite understand,'' returned the uncle, sipping his coffee.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the nephew ``a face the polished uncle can look at but the dark deference of fear and slavery''?", 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the stone face crimsoned?', 'source': 'In the glow, the water of the chateau fountain seemed to turn to blood, and the stone faces crimsoned.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the imperturbable master to be told that supper awaited him then and there?', 'source': 'He was to be told (said Monseigneur) that supper awaited him then and there, and that he was prayed to come to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If a conversation had carried the imperturbable master to death who hopes it would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'If a conversation had carried the imperturbable master to death do I hope it would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was his chair opposite to?', 'source': 'His chair was opposite to the window, and he had taken his soup, and was raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips, when he put it down.', 'answer': 'to the window'}
{'question': 'Was the fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis-- diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France?', 'source': 'The fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis-- was conspicuous in their rich furniture; but, it was diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who turned his calm face to his nephew with a smile?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What might a good opportunity for consideration influence to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': 'your destiny'}
{'question': 'Did the chateau awake later?', 'source': 'The chateau awoke later, as became its quality, but awoke gradually and surely.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was with its window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds?', 'source': 'A small lofty room, with its window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds closed, so that the dark night only showed in slight horizontal lines of black, alternating with their broad lines of stone color.', 'answer': 'the small lofty room'}
{'question': "What did the nephew ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France say ``We have so asserted''?", 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': 'our station'}
{'question': 'What did that fountain suggest up!', 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': 'the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, and the tall man with his arms'}
{'question': 'Who did he let his thin gauze curtains fall around?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'around him'}
{'question': 'Did the imperturbable master come on briskly?', 'source': 'It came on briskly, and came up to the front of the chateau.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he hear the sound of?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': 'of wheels'}
{'question': 'What is the night?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them'}
{'question': 'What did he turn his calm face to his nephew with?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'with a smile'}
{'question': 'Has a new philosophy become the mode?', 'source': 'We have lost many privileges; a new philosophy has become the mode; and the assertion of our station, in these days, might (I do not go so far as to say would, but might) cause us real inconvenience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it my Refuge for?', 'source': "For the rest, it is my Refuge.''", 'answer': 'for the rest'}
{'question': 'What is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he leave only one light burning on?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'on the large hearth'}
{'question': 'What had they picked up in their interrupted saunter?', 'source': 'The led cows, hastily brought in and tethered to anything that would hold them, were looking stupidly on, or lying down chewing the cud of nothing particularly repaying their trouble, which they had picked up in their interrupted saunter.', 'answer': 'their trouble'}
{'question': 'Did people come forth shivering-- chilled?', 'source': 'Casement windows opened, crazy doors were unbarred, and people came forth shivering-- chilled, as yet, by the new sweet air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might a good opportunity for consideration influence your destiny to than you influence it for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': 'to far greater advantage'}
{'question': "Who said, ``My friend, I told you so''?", 'source': "``My friend, I told you so,'' said the uncle, with a fine pulsation in the two marks.", 'answer': 'the uncle'}
{'question': 'Do the honor of the family look to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning?', 'source': '``I look to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the family honor sir?', 'source': 'The family honor, sir, is safe from me in this country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been known in England as Charles Darnay?', 'source': 'He had been known in England as Charles Darnay.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was one of the line that was never to break?', 'source': 'The fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis-- was conspicuous in their rich furniture; but, it was diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was to be told that he was prayed to come to it?', 'source': 'He was to be told (said Monseigneur) that supper awaited him then and there, and that he was prayed to come to it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is it not probable will arrive to-night; nevertheless?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What is it for the rest?', 'source': "For the rest, it is my Refuge.''", 'answer': 'my Refuge'}
{'question': 'Does a doctor with a daughter?', 'source': '``A Doctor with a daughter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the imperturbable master compose himself to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am the Marquis?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the small lofty room with a supper-table's window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds?", 'source': 'A small lofty room, with its window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds closed, so that the dark night only showed in slight horizontal lines of black, alternating with their broad lines of stone color.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did no other words pass between?', 'source': 'So long as a servant was present, no other words passed between them.', 'answer': 'between them'}
{'question': 'Was the intention in the words?', 'source': '``I had no intention, in the words I used, to claim it yet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, is the nothing?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, it is nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If it had carried me to death who hopes it would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he take?', 'source': 'And he took another gentle little pinch of snuff, and lightly crossed his legs.', 'answer': 'another gentle little pinch of snuff'}
{'question': 'Is the third of the rooms; a round room?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are the honor of the family fatigued?', 'source': '``You are fatigued.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would abandon it?', 'source': "''-- I would abandon it, and live otherwise and elsewhere.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was he half way through?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': 'through it'}
{'question': 'Is a conversation a sacred object?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Meanwhile will the Marquis preserve the honor and repose of the family?', 'source': "``Meanwhile,'' said the Marquis, ``I will preserve the honor and repose of the family, if you will not.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the imperturbable master anticipate?', 'source': '``I have come back, sir, as you anticipate, pursuing the object that took me away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do the Marquis believe effect to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, ``In effect''?", 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did we do?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': 'a world of wrong'}
{'question': 'What was our pleasure?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'If a conversation had carried the imperturbable master to death who do I hope it would have sustained?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What has my good fortune kept me out of a prison in here?', 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': 'in France'}
{'question': "What could I even resolve to incommode you to, ``For the honor of the family''?", 'source': '``For the honor of the family, I could even resolve to incommode you to that extent.', 'answer': 'to that extent'}
{'question': 'Do the Marquis say?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was in his former tone?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': 'the nephew'}
{'question': 'Had coffee been served?', 'source': 'When coffee had been served and they were alone together, the nephew, looking at the uncle and meeting the eyes of the face that was like a fine mask, opened a conversation.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it portend that there was at the chateau?', 'source': 'It portended that there was one stone face too many, up at the chateau.', 'answer': 'one stone face too many'}
{'question': 'Did dead darkness add its own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads Dead darkness lay on all the landscape?', 'source': 'Dead darkness lay on all the landscape, dead darkness added its own hush to the hushing dust on all the roads.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did the nephew look at?', 'source': 'The nephew looked at him, in vain, in passing on to the door.', 'answer': 'at him'}
{'question': 'What had they their trouble picked up in?', 'source': 'The led cows, hastily brought in and tethered to anything that would hold them, were looking stupidly on, or lying down chewing the cud of nothing particularly repaying their trouble, which they had picked up in their interrupted saunter.', 'answer': 'in their interrupted saunter'}
{'question': 'Is the stony business altogether with heavy stone balustrades, and stone urns, and stone flowers, and stone?', 'source': 'A stony business altogether, with heavy stone balustrades, and stone urns, and stone flowers, and stone faces of men, and stone heads of lions, in all directions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did he observe then ``is very attractive to you''?", 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'England'}
{'question': 'Is repression the only lasting philosophy?', 'source': '``Repression is the only lasting philosophy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would the imperturbable master have cared to stop me there?', 'source': "``I doubt, sir,'' returned the nephew, ``whether, if it had carried me to the utmost brink of death, you would have cared to stop me there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he turn his calm face to with a smile?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'to his nephew'}
{'question': 'Who is it the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say for?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'what is set down for them'}
{'question': 'What did he leave on the large hearth?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'only one light burning'}
{'question': 'What is that supposition?', 'source': "What is it but a wilderness of misery and ruin!''", 'answer': 'what'}
{'question': 'Who sow chance seeds?', 'source': 'Had the birds, carrying some grains of it to a distance, dropped one over him as they sow chance seeds?', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who would have cared to stop me there?', 'source': "``I doubt, sir,'' returned the nephew, ``whether, if it had carried me to the utmost brink of death, you would have cared to stop me there.''", 'answer': 'the imperturbable master'}
{'question': 'Who did the imperturbable master add to?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': 'When did then begin?', 'source': 'Then began the rarely lightened toil of the day among the village population.', 'answer': 'the rarely lightened toil of the day among the village population'}
{'question': 'Was the nephew sadly?', 'source': "``This property and France are lost to me,'' said the nephew, sadly; ``I renounce them.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If a conversation had carried the imperturbable master to death what do I hope would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the valet gone Monsieur the Marquis walk to and fro in his loose chamber-robe?', 'source': 'The valet come and gone, Monsieur the Marquis walked to and fro in his loose chamber-robe, to prepare himself gently for sleep, that hot still night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said, ``You do me too much honor'', ``still, I prefer that supposition''?", 'source': "``You do me too much honor,'' said the Marquis; ``still, I prefer that supposition.''", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'Who have lost many privileges?', 'source': 'We have lost many privileges; a new philosophy has become the mode; and the assertion of our station, in these days, might (I do not go so far as to say would, but might) cause us real inconvenience.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Did it lie back on the pillow of Monsieur the Marquis?', 'source': 'It lay back on the pillow of Monsieur the Marquis.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say for?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'what is set down for them'}
{'question': 'Did the valet come Monsieur the Marquis walk to and fro in his loose chamber-robe?', 'source': 'The valet come and gone, Monsieur the Marquis walked to and fro in his loose chamber-robe, to prepare himself gently for sleep, that hot still night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If it had carried me to death who do I hope it would have sustained?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What was a heavy mass of building with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door?', 'source': 'It was a heavy mass of building, that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis, with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What would it have been of to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of his?', 'source': 'It would have been of as much avail to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of his.', 'answer': 'of as much avail'}
{'question': 'What is it the obstinate custom of to say what is set down for them?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'of such creatures hardly ever'}
{'question': 'Who composed himself to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'the imperturbable master'}
{'question': 'When did he come?', 'source': 'In a little while he came.', 'answer': 'in a little while'}
{'question': 'What looks at me with any deference on it?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': 'all the country round about us'}
{'question': 'What did they not shake?', 'source': 'Monseigneur received him in a courtly manner, but they did not shake hands.', 'answer': 'hands'}
{'question': 'What is Monseigneur, it?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, it is nothing.', 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': 'Who is the night the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say for?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'what is set down for them'}
{'question': 'What did he take at table?', 'source': 'he said to Monseigneur, as he took his seat at table.', 'answer': 'his seat'}
{'question': 'What did he hear?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': 'the sound of wheels'}
{'question': 'Who did not shake hands?', 'source': 'Monseigneur received him in a courtly manner, but they did not shake hands.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was the sun full up?', 'source': 'Now, the sun was full up, and movement began in the village.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would I abandon?', 'source': "''-- I would abandon it, and live otherwise and elsewhere.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did it carry me into?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'into great and unexpected peril'}
{'question': 'What is the night the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say for?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': 'what is set down for them'}
{'question': "Who believes it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, ``In effect''?", 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Meanwhile what will I preserve the honor and repose of?', 'source': "``Meanwhile,'' said the Marquis, ``I will preserve the honor and repose of the family, if you will not.", 'answer': 'of the family'}
{'question': 'What did he turn to his nephew with a smile?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'his calm face'}
{'question': "Who said, ``they said he was not arrived''?", 'source': "``My nephew,'' said the Marquis, glancing at the supper preparation; ``they said he was not arrived.''", 'answer': 'the Marquis'}
{'question': 'Who has the vanity to hope?', 'source': "``Which I have the vanity to hope is not probable.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who is to our knowledge?', 'source': 'From this room, many such dogs have been taken out to be hanged; in the next room (my bedroom), one fellow, to our knowledge, was poniarded on the spot for professing some insolent delicacy respecting his daughter-- _ his _ daughter?', 'answer': 'one fellow'}
{'question': 'If it had carried me to death what do I hope would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Outside does the blind?', 'source': '``Outside the blinds.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were his finger?', 'source': 'Once again he touched him on the breast, as though his finger were the fine point of a small sword, with which, in delicate finesse, he ran him through the body, and said,', 'answer': 'the fine point of a small sword'}
{'question': 'Is effect sir?', 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did this thrown open, admit the Marquis to?', 'source': 'This thrown open, admitted him to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others.', 'answer': 'to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others'}
{'question': 'What is it not probable he will arrive; nevertheless?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': 'to-night'}
{'question': 'Did that fountain suggest the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, and the tall man with his arms up!', 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do they sow?', 'source': 'Had the birds, carrying some grains of it to a distance, dropped one over him as they sow chance seeds?', 'answer': 'chance seeds'}
{'question': 'What have we lost?', 'source': 'We have lost many privileges; a new philosophy has become the mode; and the assertion of our station, in these days, might (I do not go so far as to say would, but might) cause us real inconvenience.', 'answer': 'many privileges'}
{'question': 'Was it diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France?', 'source': 'The fashion of the last Louis but one, of the line that was never to break-- the fourteenth Louis-- was conspicuous in their rich furniture; but, it was diversified by many objects that were illustrations of old pages in the history of France.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do they say that it is?', 'source': '``They say, those boastful English, that it is the Refuge of many.', 'answer': 'the Refuge of many'}
{'question': 'Who did he add to?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': 'to himself'}
{'question': 'What was it a heavy mass of building with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before?', 'source': 'It was a heavy mass of building, that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis, with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door.', 'answer': 'before the principal door'}
{'question': 'What did he get to?', 'source': 'Whether or no, the mender of roads ran, on the sultry morning, as if for his life, down the hill, knee-high in dust, and never stopped till he got to the fountain.', 'answer': 'to the fountain'}
{'question': 'What does all the country round about us look at me with?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': 'with any deference on it'}
{'question': 'What was he through it?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': 'half way'}
{'question': 'What We _ have done wrong?', 'source': "'' _ We _ have done wrong?''", 'answer': '_'}
{'question': 'Did Monseigneur receive him in a courtly manner?', 'source': 'Monseigneur received him in a courtly manner, but they did not shake hands.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he take his seat at?', 'source': 'he said to Monseigneur, as he took his seat at table.', 'answer': 'at table'}
{'question': 'What do I have?', 'source': "``Which I have the vanity to hope is not probable.''", 'answer': 'the vanity to hope'}
{'question': 'What was he?', 'source': 'Nor was he; but, he had been expected with Monseigneur.', 'answer': 'nor'}
{'question': 'Who does all the country round about us look at with any deference on it?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': 'at me'}
{'question': 'What had he taken?', 'source': 'His chair was opposite to the window, and he had taken his soup, and was raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips, when he put it down.', 'answer': 'his soup'}
{'question': 'Was Round its hilt a frill of paper:?', 'source': 'Round its hilt was a frill of paper, on which was scrawled:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do the imperturbable master compose to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What is my friend?', 'source': "The dark deference of fear and slavery, my friend,'' observed the Marquis, ``will keep the dogs obedient to the whip, as long as this roof,'' looking up to it, ``shuts out the sky.''", 'answer': 'fear and slavery'}
{'question': 'Did the servant who spoke stand with that blank behind Monseigneur, looking round for instructions?', 'source': 'The servant who spoke, had thrown the blinds wide, had looked out into the vacant darkness, and stood with that blank behind him, looking round for instructions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he stand looking quietly at?', 'source': 'Every fine straight line in the clear whiteness of his face, was cruelly, craftily, and closely compressed, while he stood looking quietly at his nephew, with his snuff-box in his hand.', 'answer': 'at his nephew'}
{'question': "What did the Marquis say, ``they said''?", 'source': "``My nephew,'' said the Marquis, glancing at the supper preparation; ``they said he was not arrived.''", 'answer': 'he was not arrived'}
{'question': 'Who believes our name to be more?', 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What shall I be ready in?', 'source': "I shall be ready in a quarter of an hour.''", 'answer': 'in a quarter of an hour'}
{'question': 'Was building that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis?', 'source': 'It was a heavy mass of building, that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis, with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he lightly cross?', 'source': 'And he took another gentle little pinch of snuff, and lightly crossed his legs.', 'answer': 'his legs'}
{'question': 'Would Good have been of as much avail to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of the honor of the family?', 'source': 'It would have been of as much avail to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of his.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Marquis say, ``You have been a long time coming''?", 'source': "``You have been a long time coming,'' said the Marquis, with a smile.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the Marquis say that those is the Refuge of many?', 'source': '``They say, those boastful English, that it is the Refuge of many.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he put in his pocket?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': 'his box'}
{'question': 'What did this thrown open, admit him to?', 'source': 'This thrown open, admitted him to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others.', 'answer': 'to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others'}
{'question': 'What did he put his box in?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': 'in his pocket'}
{'question': 'Who rang his little bell again?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who was it?', 'source': 'It was the nephew of Monseigneur.', 'answer': 'the nephew of Monseigneur'}
{'question': 'Had the Gorgon added the one stone face wanting; the stone face for which it had waited through about two hundred years?', 'source': 'The Gorgon had surveyed the building again in the night, and had added the one stone face wanting; the stone face for which it had waited through about two hundred years.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it a heavy mass of with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door?', 'source': 'It was a heavy mass of building, that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis, with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door.', 'answer': 'of building'}
{'question': "What do I believe to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, ``In effect''?", 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the birds carry some grains of that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis to a distance?', 'source': 'Had the birds, carrying some grains of it to a distance, dropped one over him as they sow chance seeds?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would the imperturbable master have cared to stop there?', 'source': "``I doubt, sir,'' returned the nephew, ``whether, if it had carried me to the utmost brink of death, you would have cared to stop me there.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did he take another gentle little pinch of snuff?', 'source': 'And he took another gentle little pinch of snuff, and lightly crossed his legs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Marquis listen for the retreating step of his valet?', 'source': 'The Marquis looked that way, and listened for the retreating step of his valet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the servant who spoke stand with that blank behind him, looking round for instructions?', 'source': 'The servant who spoke, had thrown the blinds wide, had looked out into the vacant darkness, and stood with that blank behind him, looking round for instructions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who influences it for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Does a doctor?', 'source': "A Doctor?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been some few leagues behind Monseigneur, early in the afternoon?', 'source': 'He had been some few leagues behind Monseigneur, early in the afternoon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had said it?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Had he been expected with Monseigneur?', 'source': 'Nor was he; but, he had been expected with Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who are granted to so few?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who was my nephew?', 'source': "``Seeking them from me, my nephew,'' said the Marquis, touching him on the breast with his forefinger-- they were now standing by the hearth-- ``you will for ever seek them in vain, be assured.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did he take a culminating pinch of snuff?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would you have cared to stop there?', 'source': "``I doubt, sir,'' returned the nephew, ``whether, if it had carried me to the utmost brink of death, you would have cared to stop me there.''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': "Did the nephew ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France say ``We have so asserted our station''?", 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you know?', 'source': 'You know a compatriot who has found a Refuge there?', 'answer': 'a compatriot who has found a Refuge there'}
{'question': 'Do you know a compatriot who has found a Refuge there?', 'source': 'You know a compatriot who has found a Refuge there?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What are granted to so few?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': 'our pleasure'}
{'question': 'Shall I be ready in a quarter of an hour?', 'source': "I shall be ready in a quarter of an hour.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the family honor safe from the Marquis in this country?', 'source': 'The family honor, sir, is safe from me in this country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do he compose to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Did England seed how indifferently you have prospered there?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it come up to the front of the chateau?', 'source': 'It came on briskly, and came up to the front of the chateau.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I believe?', 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': 'our name to be more'}
{'question': 'Who are sought by so many?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Were no other words alone together?', 'source': 'When coffee had been served and they were alone together, the nephew, looking at the uncle and meeting the eyes of the face that was like a fine mask, opened a conversation.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did the honor of the family observe then ``to''?", 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'England is very attractive to you'}
{'question': 'Had he heard of Monseigneur?', 'source': 'He had heard of Monseigneur, at the posting-houses, as being before him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Meanwhile what will I preserve?', 'source': "``Meanwhile,'' said the Marquis, ``I will preserve the honor and repose of the family, if you will not.", 'answer': 'the honor and repose of the family'}
{'question': 'Would the Marquis abandon that supposition?', 'source': "''-- I would abandon it, and live otherwise and elsewhere.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did all these trivial incidents belong to the routine of life, and the return of morning?', 'source': 'All these trivial incidents belonged to the routine of life, and the return of morning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it like a fine mask made angry, and petrified?', 'source': 'It was like a fine mask, suddenly startled, made angry, and petrified.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What came on briskly?', 'source': 'It came on briskly, and came up to the front of the chateau.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What are sought by so many?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was the done?', 'source': 'It was done.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was one fellow poniarded on the spot for professing some insolent delicacy respecting his daughter-- _ his _ daughter in the next room?', 'source': 'From this room, many such dogs have been taken out to be hanged; in the next room (my bedroom), one fellow, to our knowledge, was poniarded on the spot for professing some insolent delicacy respecting his daughter-- _ his _ daughter?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'a sacred object'}
{'question': 'Was every fine straight line in the clear whiteness of his face, cruelly?', 'source': 'Every fine straight line in the clear whiteness of his face, was cruelly, craftily, and closely compressed, while he stood looking quietly at his nephew, with his snuff-box in his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you pursue?', 'source': '``I have come back, sir, as you anticipate, pursuing the object that took me away.', 'answer': 'the object that took me away'}
{'question': 'Did the Marquis go on with his supper?', 'source': 'That was done too, and the Marquis went on with his supper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the words strike the eyes and ears of his nephew forcibly?', 'source': 'As he bent his head in his most courtly manner, there was a secrecy in his smiling face, and he conveyed an air of mystery to those words, which struck the eyes and ears of his nephew forcibly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was me my nephew?', 'source': "``Seeking them from me, my nephew,'' said the Marquis, touching him on the breast with his forefinger-- they were now standing by the hearth-- ``you will for ever seek them in vain, be assured.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he said?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did he say to Monseigneur?', 'source': 'he said to Monseigneur, as he took his seat at table.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have many such dogs been taken out to be hanged from this room?', 'source': 'From this room, many such dogs have been taken out to be hanged; in the next room (my bedroom), one fellow, to our knowledge, was poniarded on the spot for professing some insolent delicacy respecting his daughter-- _ his _ daughter?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are families these slight favors that might so incommode the Marquis?', 'source': 'These little instruments of correction, these gentle aids to the power and honor of families, these slight favors that might so incommode you, are only to be obtained now by interest and importunity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is correction these gentle aids to the power and honor of families?', 'source': 'These little instruments of correction, these gentle aids to the power and honor of families, these slight favors that might so incommode you, are only to be obtained now by interest and importunity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the uncle say, ``It is possible''?", 'source': "``It is possible,'' said the uncle, with great calmness.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did that fountain cry, ``Dead''?", 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did our not remote ancestors hold the right of life and death over the surrounding vulgar?', 'source': 'Our not remote ancestors held the right of life and death over the surrounding vulgar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I look to?', 'source': '``I look to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning.', 'answer': 'to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning'}
{'question': 'Did he convey an air of mystery to those words?', 'source': 'As he bent his head in his most courtly manner, there was a secrecy in his smiling face, and he conveyed an air of mystery to those words, which struck the eyes and ears of his nephew forcibly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you influence it for?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': 'for yourself'}
{'question': 'Is the family honor safe from me in this country?', 'source': 'The family honor, sir, is safe from me in this country.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the nephew observe ``I perceive that the Reception of the day before yesterday was''?", 'source': "``I perceive that, happily for me, the Reception of the day before yesterday was, as usual, a cold one,'' observed the nephew.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hear the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do you influence for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Can the family name suffer from me in no other?', 'source': "The family name can suffer from me in no other, for I bear it in no other.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does the nephew glance at him with deep distrust?', 'source': "``But, however that may be,'' resumed the nephew, glancing at him with deep distrust, ``I know that your diplomacy would stop me by any means, and would know no scruple as to means.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are these little instruments of correction only to be obtained now by interest and importunity?', 'source': 'These little instruments of correction, these gentle aids to the power and honor of families, these slight favors that might so incommode you, are only to be obtained now by interest and importunity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "As if the Gorgon's head had surveyed it was it finished?", 'source': "As if the Gorgon's head had surveyed it, when it was finished, two centuries ago.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who sees?', 'source': "But you are lost, Monsieur Charles, I see.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he ring again?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': 'his little bell'}
{'question': 'Did no other words pass between them?', 'source': 'So long as a servant was present, no other words passed between them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look with attention at the horizontal lines of black and stone color?', 'source': 'he calmly asked, looking with attention at the horizontal lines of black and stone color.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would it have been of as much avail to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of his?', 'source': 'It would have been of as much avail to interrogate any stone face outside the chateau as to interrogate that face of his.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the birds carry some grains of it to a distance?', 'source': 'Had the birds, carrying some grains of it to a distance, dropped one over him as they sow chance seeds?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did he observe then ``to''?", 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': 'England is very attractive to you'}
{'question': 'Was it the nephew of Monseigneur?', 'source': 'It was the nephew of Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are families these slight favors that might so incommode you?', 'source': 'These little instruments of correction, these gentle aids to the power and honor of families, these slight favors that might so incommode you, are only to be obtained now by interest and importunity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might that not be so long as the Marquis supposed?', 'source': 'That might not be so long as the Marquis supposed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn his calm face to his nephew with a smile?', 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did we do a world of wrong?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who anticipates?', 'source': '``I have come back, sir, as you anticipate, pursuing the object that took me away.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'If a conversation had carried the imperturbable master to death what do I hope?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'it would have sustained me'}
{'question': "Could the Marquis even resolve to incommode you to that extent, ``For the honor of the family''?", 'source': '``For the honor of the family, I could even resolve to incommode you to that extent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they their trouble picked up in their interrupted saunter?', 'source': 'The led cows, hastily brought in and tethered to anything that would hold them, were looking stupidly on, or lying down chewing the cud of nothing particularly repaying their trouble, which they had picked up in their interrupted saunter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the led cows looking stupidly on, or lying down chewing the cud of nothing particularly repaying their trouble?', 'source': 'The led cows, hastily brought in and tethered to anything that would hold them, were looking stupidly on, or lying down chewing the cud of nothing particularly repaying their trouble, which they had picked up in their interrupted saunter.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his tone linger in the air?', 'source': 'His tone lingered in the air, almost like the tone of a musical instrument.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips?', 'source': 'His chair was opposite to the window, and he had taken his soup, and was raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips, when he put it down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might a good opportunity for consideration influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Light monsieur my nephew to his chamber there!', 'source': 'Light Monsieur my nephew to his chamber there!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do they say?', 'source': '``They say, those boastful English, that it is the Refuge of many.', 'answer': 'that it is the Refuge of many'}
{'question': "Did the uncle say ``it is not necessary to say''?", 'source': "``Not to death,'' said the uncle; ``it is not necessary to say, to death.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is lost?', 'source': "But you are lost, Monsieur Charles, I see.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the honor of the family convey an air of mystery to those words?', 'source': 'As he bent his head in his most courtly manner, there was a secrecy in his smiling face, and he conveyed an air of mystery to those words, which struck the eyes and ears of his nephew forcibly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his chair opposite to the window?', 'source': 'His chair was opposite to the window, and he had taken his soup, and was raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips, when he put it down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might the assertion cause us real inconvenience?', 'source': 'We have lost many privileges; a new philosophy has become the mode; and the assertion of our station, in these days, might (I do not go so far as to say would, but might) cause us real inconvenience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the step the women bending over it?', 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Could I even resolve to incommode you to that extent, ``For the honor of the family''?", 'source': '``For the honor of the family, I could even resolve to incommode you to that extent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is fatigued?', 'source': '``You are fatigued.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the nephew look at him?', 'source': 'The nephew looked at him, in vain, in passing on to the door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the step the women bending over that fountain?', 'source': "That fountain suggested the Paris fountain, the little bundle lying on the step, the women bending over it, and the tall man with his arms up, crying, ``Dead!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the nephew say, ``This property and France are lost to me'', ``I renounce them''?", 'source': "``This property and France are lost to me,'' said the nephew, sadly; ``I renounce them.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Marquis look that way?', 'source': 'The Marquis looked that way, and listened for the retreating step of his valet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this thrown open, admit the Marquis to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others?', 'source': 'This thrown open, admitted him to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his finger the fine point of a small sword?', 'source': 'Once again he touched him on the breast, as though his finger were the fine point of a small sword, with which, in delicate finesse, he ran him through the body, and said,', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the nephew ``a face I can look at but the dark deference of fear and slavery''?", 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did one little bird sing its sweetest song with all its might?', 'source': 'The carol of the birds was loud and high, and, on the weather-beaten sill of the great window of the bed-chamber of Monsieur the Marquis, one little bird sang its sweetest song with all its might.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did we injure every human creature who came between us and our pleasure?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do they say that it is the Refuge of many?', 'source': '``They say, those boastful English, that it is the Refuge of many.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it portend that there was one stone face too many at the chateau?', 'source': 'It portended that there was one stone face too many, up at the chateau.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he diminished the distance rapidly?', 'source': 'He had diminished the distance rapidly, but not so rapidly as to come up with Monseigneur on the road.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he leave only one light burning on the large hearth?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hear the sound of wheels?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What used not to be so?', 'source': 'It used not to be so, but France in all such things is changed for the worse.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Is it useless to discuss the question?', 'source': 'But it is useless to discuss the question.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the uncle say, ``My friend, I told you so''?", 'source': "``My friend, I told you so,'' said the uncle, with a fine pulsation in the two marks.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this thrown open, admit him to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others?', 'source': 'This thrown open, admitted him to his own private apartment of three rooms: his bed-chamber and two others.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they not shake hands?', 'source': 'Monseigneur received him in a courtly manner, but they did not shake hands.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he observe then ``England is very attractive to you''?", 'source': "``England is very attractive to you, seeing how indifferently you have prospered there,'' he observed then, turning his calm face to his nephew with a smile.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Monseigneur, is it nothing?', 'source': '``Monseigneur, it is nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have we lost many privileges?', 'source': 'We have lost many privileges; a new philosophy has become the mode; and the assertion of our station, in these days, might (I do not go so far as to say would, but might) cause us real inconvenience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Is it my Refuge for the rest?', 'source': "For the rest, it is my Refuge.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do they sow chance seeds?', 'source': 'Had the birds, carrying some grains of it to a distance, dropped one over him as they sow chance seeds?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them?', 'source': 'But it is the obstinate custom of such creatures hardly ever to say what is set down for them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do _ We _ have done wrong?', 'source': "'' _ We _ have done wrong?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it carry me into great and unexpected peril?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he to be told that he was prayed to come to it?', 'source': 'He was to be told (said Monseigneur) that supper awaited him then and there, and that he was prayed to come to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has my good fortune kept me out of a prison in France here?', 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were alone together?', 'source': 'When coffee had been served and they were alone together, the nephew, looking at the uncle and meeting the eyes of the face that was like a fine mask, opened a conversation.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he put his box in his pocket?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the small lofty room with its window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds?', 'source': 'A small lofty room, with its window wide open, and the wooden jalousie-blinds closed, so that the dark night only showed in slight horizontal lines of black, alternating with their broad lines of stone color.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who says?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did he come in a little while?', 'source': 'In a little while he came.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it scarcely worth mentioning?', 'source': "It is scarcely worth mentioning; but, is it yet?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it a sacred object?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have the vanity to hope?', 'source': "``Which I have the vanity to hope is not probable.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What do I believe it to be at, ``In effect''?", 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': 'at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune'}
{'question': 'If it had carried me to death do I hope it would have sustained me?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he get to the fountain?', 'source': 'Whether or no, the mender of roads ran, on the sultry morning, as if for his life, down the hill, knee-high in dust, and never stopped till he got to the fountain.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you pursue the object that took me away?', 'source': '``I have come back, sir, as you anticipate, pursuing the object that took me away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the nephew in his former tone?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are they granted to so few?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he calmly ask?', 'source': 'he calmly asked, looking with attention at the horizontal lines of black and stone color.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did we injure?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': 'every human creature who came between us and our pleasure'}
{'question': 'Did it come on briskly?', 'source': 'It came on briskly, and came up to the front of the chateau.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is what that supposition?', 'source': "What is it but a wilderness of misery and ruin!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it portend at?', 'source': 'It portended that there was one stone face too many, up at the chateau.', 'answer': 'that there was one stone face too many at the chateau'}
{'question': 'Are they sought by so many?', 'source': 'They are sought by so many, and they are granted to so few!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must you be fatigued?', 'source': 'But you must be fatigued.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Marquis say, ``they said he was not arrived''?", 'source': "``My nephew,'' said the Marquis, glancing at the supper preparation; ``they said he was not arrived.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it our pleasure?', 'source': "Even in my father's time, we did a world of wrong, injuring every human creature who came between us and our pleasure, whatever it was.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If it had carried me to death what do I hope?', 'source': "It carried me into great and unexpected peril; but it is a sacred object, and if it had carried me to death I hope it would have sustained me.''", 'answer': 'it would have sustained me'}
{'question': 'Would I abandon it?', 'source': "''-- I would abandon it, and live otherwise and elsewhere.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is fear and slavery my friend?', 'source': "The dark deference of fear and slavery, my friend,'' observed the Marquis, ``will keep the dogs obedient to the whip, as long as this roof,'' looking up to it, ``shuts out the sky.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does all the country round about us look at me with any deference on it?', 'source': "``There is not,'' pursued the nephew, in his former tone, ``a face I can look at, in all this country round about us, which looks at me with any deference on it but the dark deference of fear and slavery.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand looking quietly at his nephew?', 'source': 'Every fine straight line in the clear whiteness of his face, was cruelly, craftily, and closely compressed, while he stood looking quietly at his nephew, with his snuff-box in his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he taken his soup?', 'source': 'His chair was opposite to the window, and he had taken his soup, and was raising his glass of Bordeaux to his lips, when he put it down.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was nor he?', 'source': 'Nor was he; but, he had been expected with Monseigneur.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he half way through it?', 'source': 'He was half way through it, when he again stopped with his glass in his hand, hearing the sound of wheels.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did the Marquis say, ``You do'', ``still, I prefer that supposition''?", 'source': "``You do me too much honor,'' said the Marquis; ``still, I prefer that supposition.''", 'answer': 'me too much honor'}
{'question': "Did the Marquis say, ``You do me too much honor'', ``still, I prefer that supposition''?", 'source': "``You do me too much honor,'' said the Marquis; ``still, I prefer that supposition.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Meanwhile will I preserve the honor and repose of the family?', 'source': "``Meanwhile,'' said the Marquis, ``I will preserve the honor and repose of the family, if you will not.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I look to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning?', 'source': '``I look to the pleasure of seeing you again in the morning.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is one fellow to our knowledge?', 'source': 'From this room, many such dogs have been taken out to be hanged; in the next room (my bedroom), one fellow, to our knowledge, was poniarded on the spot for professing some insolent delicacy respecting his daughter-- _ his _ daughter?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, ``In effect''?", 'source': "``In effect, sir,'' pursued the nephew, ``I believe it to be at once your bad fortune, and my good fortune, that has kept me out of a prison in France here.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take his seat at table?', 'source': 'he said to Monseigneur, as he took his seat at table.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said ``We have so asserted our station''?", 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': 'the nephew ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France'}
{'question': 'Did he add to himself?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lightly cross his legs?', 'source': 'And he took another gentle little pinch of snuff, and lightly crossed his legs.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is that supposition little to relinquish?', 'source': 'It is little to relinquish.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that done too?', 'source': 'That was done too, and the Marquis went on with his supper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do it now shine brightly?', 'source': 'It now shone brightly, through the door of communication.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he to be told that supper awaited him then and there?', 'source': 'He was to be told (said Monseigneur) that supper awaited him then and there, and that he was prayed to come to it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it little to relinquish?', 'source': 'It is little to relinquish.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it not probable?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': 'he will arrive to-night; nevertheless'}
{'question': 'Could he becomingly be of a country still containing himself?', 'source': 'The Marquis took a gentle little pinch of snuff, and shook his head; as elegantly despondent as he could becomingly be of a country still containing himself, that great means of regeneration.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I believe our name to be more?', 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I see?', 'source': "But you are lost, Monsieur Charles, I see.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you lost?', 'source': "But you are lost, Monsieur Charles, I see.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it use not to be so?', 'source': 'It used not to be so, but France in all such things is changed for the worse.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you fatigued?', 'source': '``You are fatigued.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you anticipate?', 'source': '``I have come back, sir, as you anticipate, pursuing the object that took me away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a heavy mass of building with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door?', 'source': 'It was a heavy mass of building, that chateau of Monsieur the Marquis, with a large stone courtyard before it, and two stone sweeps of staircase meeting in a stone terrace before the principal door.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is what it?', 'source': "What is it but a wilderness of misery and ruin!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you influence it for yourself?', 'source': 'A good opportunity for consideration, surrounded by the advantages of solitude, might influence your destiny to far greater advantage than you influence it for yourself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it done?', 'source': 'It was done.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would you have cared to stop me there?', 'source': "``I doubt, sir,'' returned the nephew, ``whether, if it had carried me to the utmost brink of death, you would have cared to stop me there.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he compose himself to sleep?', 'source': 'So, leaving only one light burning on the large hearth, he let his thin gauze curtains fall around him, and heard the night break its silence with a long sigh as he composed himself to sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the nephew ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France say ?', 'source': "``We have so asserted our station, both in the old time and in the modern time also,'' said the nephew, gloomily, ``that I believe our name to be more detested than any name in France.''", 'answer': 'We have so asserted our station'}
{'question': 'Did he ring his little bell again?', 'source': "-- And burn Monsieur my nephew in his bed, if you will,'' he added to himself, before he rang his little bell again, and summoned his valet to his own bedroom.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they alone together?', 'source': 'When coffee had been served and they were alone together, the nephew, looking at the uncle and meeting the eyes of the face that was like a fine mask, opened a conversation.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he said it?', 'source': 'When he had said it, he took a culminating pinch of snuff, and put his box in his pocket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you say?', 'source': 'I am, as you say, at a disadvantage.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it?', 'source': 'It is not probable he will arrive to-night; nevertheless, leave the table as it is.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did her golden hair fall down over?', 'source': 'Her golden hair, which she wore in long curls, had been hurriedly pushed aside, and fell down over her neck.', 'answer': 'over her neck'}
{'question': 'Who stayed them with a motion of her hand?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did the captive of many years sit looking fixedly in the middle of the forehead?', 'source': 'As the captive of many years sat looking fixedly, by turns, at Mr. Lorry and at Defarge, some long obliterated marks of an actively intent intelligence in the middle of the forehead, gradually forced themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who taught myself?', 'source': 'I taught myself.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What did the spirit of a fast-dying man say those were?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': 'the words'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry ask me, ``I forget what there was''?", 'source': '``I forget what it was you asked me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What found these upon my sleeve?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was Monsieur Defarge so confused, and so very slow to answer?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he sit looking fixedly at?', 'source': 'The shoe dropped to the ground, and he sat looking fixedly at the questioner.', 'answer': 'at the questioner'}
{'question': 'Did the shoemaker look up?', 'source': 'When he had stood, for a minute or two, by the side of Defarge, the shoemaker looked up.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is well?', 'source': '``It is well.', 'answer': 'these'}
{'question': 'What did he and Mr. Lorry assist him to?', 'source': "Monsieur Defarge put this provender, and the lamp he carried, on the shoemaker's bench (there was nothing else in the garret but a pallet bed), and he and Mr. Lorry roused the captive, and assisted him to his feet.", 'answer': 'to his feet'}
{'question': 'Who rocked him on her breast like a child?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did his eyes in gloomy abstraction look about him in?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': 'in the old way'}
{'question': 'When was he ago?', 'source': 'She was-- and He was-- before the slow years of the North Tower-- ages ago.', 'answer': 'ages'}
{'question': 'Did the shoemaker stop his work?', 'source': 'The shoemaker stopped his work; looked with a vacant air of listening, at the floor on one side of him; then similarly, at the floor on the other side of him; then, upward at the speaker.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who sat looking fixedly at the questioner?', 'source': 'The shoe dropped to the ground, and he sat looking fixedly at the questioner.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Who can never help me to escape in the body? '", 'source': "They can never help me to escape in the body, though they may in the spirit. '", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did his cold white head mingle with?', 'source': 'His cold white head mingled with her radiant hair, which warmed and lighted it as though it were the light of Freedom shining on him.', 'answer': 'with her radiant hair'}
{'question': 'Who said those were the words?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': 'the spirit of a fast-dying man'}
{'question': 'If Manette will lock the door to secure post-horses from interruption, do I not doubt that you will find him?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is all that the maker's name may tell you?", 'source': 'All that I may tell you, here and now, is, that I pray to you to touch me and to bless me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If Manette will lock the door to secure post-horses from interruption, who does not doubt that you will find him?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What had darkness fallen on him in?', 'source': 'Darkness had fallen on him in its place.', 'answer': 'in its place'}
{'question': 'What struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': 'a strange thrill'}
{'question': 'Who not yet trusted the tones of her voice?', 'source': 'Not yet trusting the tones of her voice, she sat down on the bench beside him.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who took it in his hand?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took it in his hand.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who is not a shoemaker by trade?', 'source': '``I am not a shoemaker by trade?', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did they tear his white hair in?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': 'in a frenzy'}
{'question': 'What fell down over her neck?', 'source': 'Her golden hair, which she wore in long curls, had been hurriedly pushed aside, and fell down over her neck.', 'answer': 'her golden hair'}
{'question': 'What was like the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago?', 'source': 'It was like the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did I get it with after a long while?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': 'with much difficulty'}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man have none?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What can never help me to escape in the body? '", 'source': "They can never help me to escape in the body, though they may in the spirit. '", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Are lanterns at the?', 'source': 'Soldiers with lanterns, at the guard-house there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did immediately see nothing?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who held him closer round the neck?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did die out of him?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': "the spirit of a fast-dying man's shoemaking"}
{'question': 'What came to him coherently?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'those'}
{'question': "Who readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his?", 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they tear in a frenzy?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': 'his white hair'}
{'question': 'Who went up to his white hair?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': 'the spirit of a fast-dying man'}
{'question': 'What died out?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'a very faint voice'}
{'question': 'Who did find spoken words for it?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did she hold closer round the neck?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who did he turn to the light?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': 'her full'}
{'question': 'Who had followed him?', 'source': "The prisoner had got into a coach, and his daughter had followed him, when Mr. Lorry's feet were arrested on the step by his asking, miserably, for his shoemaking tools and the unfinished shoes.", 'answer': "the prisoner's daughter"}
{'question': 'Who sees how composed he has become?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who can I not tell at this time?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Who is this time's mind?", 'source': "Is there no old banker, no old business, no old servant, no old time, rising in your mind, Monsieur Manette?''", 'answer': 'Monsieur Manette'}
{'question': 'Who readily responded to his daughter took her hand in both his own?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What cannot be?', 'source': 'It cannot be.', 'answer': 'a very faint voice'}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man have more than one or two long golden hairs?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who can they never help to escape in the body? '", 'source': "They can never help me to escape in the body, though they may in the spirit. '", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Whose walking-shoe is it?', 'source': "It is a young lady's walking-shoe.", 'answer': "a young lady's walking-shoe"}
{'question': "Who can the maker's name not tell at this time?", 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Had the prisoner's daughter followed him?", 'source': "The prisoner had got into a coach, and his daughter had followed him, when Mr. Lorry's feet were arrested on the step by his asking, miserably, for his shoemaking tools and the unfinished shoes.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did haggard eyes rest on the face?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What returned to his forehead?', 'source': 'As the concentrated expression returned to his forehead, he seemed to become conscious that it was in hers too.', 'answer': 'the concentrated expression'}
{'question': 'Do O, see!', 'source': 'O, see!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the two spectators start forward?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What showed his body to be withered?', 'source': 'His yellow rags of shirt lay open at the throat, and showed his body to be withered and worn.', 'answer': "the workman's yellow rags of shirt"}
{'question': 'Was that Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting?', 'source': 'Only one soul was to be seen, and that was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'How many long golden hairs did he have?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': 'more than one or two long golden hairs'}
{'question': 'Did no sound proceed from some words?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did his daughter fall upon her knees before?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': 'before him'}
{'question': 'When was it raised?', 'source': 'It was raised for a moment, and a very faint voice responded to the salutation, as if it were at a distance:', 'answer': 'for a moment'}
{'question': 'What forced themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him?', 'source': 'As the captive of many years sat looking fixedly, by turns, at Mr. Lorry and at Defarge, some long obliterated marks of an actively intent intelligence in the middle of the forehead, gradually forced themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him.', 'answer': 'gradually'}
{'question': 'Did the shoemaker reply?', 'source': 'There was a longer pause than usual, before the shoemaker replied:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again?', 'source': 'But, the question reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again.', 'answer': 'the question'}
{'question': 'Who resumed his work?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who had sunk in her arms?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who had no fear of his striking at her with the knife?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "Do the maker's name feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart?", 'source': 'I feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the lethargy worn out?', 'source': 'He had gradually dropped to the floor, and lay there in a lethargy, worn out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who watched him?', 'source': "Then, as the darkness closed in, the daughter laid her head down on the hard ground close at the father's side, and watched him.", 'answer': 'the daughter'}
{'question': 'Did the shoemaker look up as before?', 'source': 'The shoemaker looked up as before, but without removing a hand from his work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What showed his body to be worn?', 'source': 'His yellow rags of shirt lay open at the throat, and showed his body to be withered and worn.', 'answer': "the workman's yellow rags of shirt"}
{'question': 'What did she have no fear of his striking at her with?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'with the knife'}
{'question': 'Do Manette see how you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who took the shoe up?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who fell upon her knees before him?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': 'his daughter'}
{'question': 'Whose shoe is it?', 'source': "``It is a lady's shoe.", 'answer': "a lady's shoe"}
{'question': 'What did he seem to become conscious that it was in too?', 'source': 'As the concentrated expression returned to his forehead, he seemed to become conscious that it was in hers too.', 'answer': 'in hers'}
{'question': 'If Manette will lock the door to secure post-horses from interruption, who do I not doubt that you will find?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who had laid her head upon my shoulder?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who will Manette take care of until you return in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'Did the two spectators start?', 'source': 'Once more, the two spectators started, as he turned upon her with a frightful suddenness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he gradually dropped to?', 'source': 'He had gradually dropped to the floor, and lay there in a lethargy, worn out.', 'answer': 'to the floor'}
{'question': 'Who opened this?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': 'the spirit of a fast-dying man'}
{'question': 'Who did she rock on her breast like a child?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who did she stay with a motion of her hand?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who laid her hand upon his arm?', 'source': 'He recoiled, but she laid her hand upon his arm.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did he take up?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': 'the shoe'}
{'question': 'Who will take care of him until you return in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'Manette'}
{'question': 'Who looked at it?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they find these upon?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'upon my sleeve'}
{'question': 'Who looked at her?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who had nestled down with him?', 'source': 'She had nestled down with him, that his head might lie upon her arm; and her hair drooping over him curtained him from the light.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': "Who did he readily respond to's drawing her arm through his?", 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'to his daughter'}
{'question': 'Who laid her hand upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did a strange thrill strike when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What would have caused them to look large?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'the hollowness and thinness of his face'}
{'question': 'What did he look at?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': 'at the two'}
{'question': 'Were both Mr. Lorry and Defarge rather disinclined to this course?', 'source': 'Both Mr. Lorry and Defarge were rather disinclined to this course, and in favor of one of them remaining.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she stay with a motion of her hand?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who saw her face?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who had his hands not been seen in before?', 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': 'in him'}
{'question': 'Do Manette return?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he readily respond to took her hand in both his own?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'to his daughter'}
{'question': 'What did that see?', 'source': 'Only one soul was to be seen, and that was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': 'What proceeded from them?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': 'no sound'}
{'question': 'Who tried speaking to him?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who handed them in?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did he turn her full to?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': 'to the light'}
{'question': "If the maker's name touch, in touching my hair, does anything that recall a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free!", 'source': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, anything that recalls a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free, weep for it, weep for it!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who is these's name?", 'source': "What is your name, my gentle angel?''", 'answer': "the spirit of a fast-dying man's gentle angel"}
{'question': "Can the maker's name not tell you here?", 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who drank what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings?', 'source': 'In the submissive way of one long accustomed to obey under coercion, he ate and drank what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings, that they gave him to wear.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did she have at her with the knife?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'no fear of his striking'}
{'question': 'Who did she have no fear of his striking at with the knife?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'at her'}
{'question': 'Who had taken it up?', 'source': 'He had taken it up, and was stooping to work again, when his eyes caught the skirt of her dress.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the darkness close in?', 'source': "Then, as the darkness closed in, the daughter laid her head down on the hard ground close at the father's side, and watched him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose hand did he drop?', 'source': "On their reaching the courtyard he instinctively altered his tread, as being in expectation of a drawbridge; and when there was no drawbridge, and he saw the carriage waiting in the open street, he dropped his daughter's hand and clasped his head again.", 'answer': "his daughter's hand"}
{'question': 'What came from that quarter?', 'source': 'His haggard eyes turned to Defarge as if he would have transferred the question to him: but as no help came from that quarter, they turned back on the questioner when they had sought the ground.', 'answer': 'no help'}
{'question': 'Who took her hair into his hand again?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who looked at the two?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "What did he readily respond to his daughter's drawing her arm through?", 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'through his'}
{'question': 'What tried speaking to him?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did his daughter fall upon before him?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': 'upon her knees'}
{'question': 'Who did I ask leave to teach?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'What did he find spoken words for?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'for it'}
{'question': 'Who looked closely at it?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they find upon my sleeve?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'these'}
{'question': 'What did he advance by little and little?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': 'his hand'}
{'question': 'What is my father?', 'source': '``You remember the place, my father?', 'answer': 'the place'}
{'question': 'Who recollected what they had said to him?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, who does not doubt that you will find him?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who tried to secure it in his breast?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who put her two hands to her lips?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did his shoemaking die out of?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'Who sees how you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Were gradually fainter?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did one begin to descend?', 'source': 'They began to descend; Monsieur Defarge going first with the lamp, Mr. Lorry closing the little procession.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who came to him coherently?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did a sound happen?', 'source': "It happened, at length, that he had occasion to change the instrument in his hand, for his shoemaker's knife.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago?', 'source': 'It was like the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has made shoes ever since?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did she rock him on like a child?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'on her breast'}
{'question': 'What were it the light of shining on him?', 'source': 'His cold white head mingled with her radiant hair, which warmed and lighted it as though it were the light of Freedom shining on him.', 'answer': 'of Freedom'}
{'question': 'What were at his feet and on his bench?', 'source': 'His few common tools and various scraps of leather were at his feet and on his bench.', 'answer': "the workman's few common tools and various scraps of leather"}
{'question': 'Who did they try speaking to?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What were it shining on him?', 'source': 'His cold white head mingled with her radiant hair, which warmed and lighted it as though it were the light of Freedom shining on him.', 'answer': 'the light of Freedom'}
{'question': "What did he readily respond to his daughter's drawing through his?", 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'her arm'}
{'question': 'What learned it here?', 'source': 'I-I learned it here.', 'answer': 'I-I'}
{'question': 'Is here monsieur?', 'source': '``Here is monsieur, who knows a well-made shoe when he sees one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who sat staring at her?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who took it up?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who will Manette take care of until then post-horses will remove him straight in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'What did she not yet trust the tones of?', 'source': 'Not yet trusting the tones of her voice, she sat down on the bench beside him.', 'answer': 'of her voice'}
{'question': "Did Monsieur Defarge say ``You have a visitor''?", 'source': "``You have a visitor, you see,'' said Monsieur Defarge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who murmured an answer as if she had repeated it?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did I say those were?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': 'the words'}
{'question': 'What did he stare at her with?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': 'with a fearful look'}
{'question': 'Who had she nestled down with?', 'source': 'She had nestled down with him, that his head might lie upon her arm; and her hair drooping over him curtained him from the light.', 'answer': 'with him'}
{'question': 'What did he open?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'What was I brought to?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'to the North Tower'}
{'question': "What can they never help me to escape in? '", 'source': "They can never help me to escape in the body, though they may in the spirit. '", 'answer': 'in the body'}
{'question': 'Does monsieur know a well-made shoe when he sees one?', 'source': '``Here is monsieur, who knows a well-made shoe when he sees one.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who sighed ``No.''?", 'source': "She sighed ``No.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did I say were the words?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': 'those'}
{'question': 'What have I made ever since?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': 'shoes'}
{'question': 'What did he hold out for the shoe that had been taken from him?', 'source': 'As he held out his hand for the shoe that had been taken from him, Mr. Lorry said, still looking steadfastly in his face:', 'answer': 'his hand'}
{'question': 'Who did he look at?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': 'at her'}
{'question': 'How many her hands did she put to her lips?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'her two hands'}
{'question': "Did the daughter lay her head down on the hard ground close at the father's side?", 'source': "Then, as the darkness closed in, the daughter laid her head down on the hard ground close at the father's side, and watched him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were gradually overclouded again?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had she moved from the wall of the garret, very near to on which he sat?', 'source': 'She had moved from the wall of the garret, very near to the bench on which he sat.', 'answer': 'to the bench'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Lorry and Monsieur Defarge brought with them?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry and Monsieur Defarge had made all ready for the journey, and had brought with them, besides traveling cloaks and wrappers, bread and meat, wine, and hot coffee.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he murmur as if she had repeated it?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': 'an answer'}
{'question': 'What had she moved very near from to the bench on which he sat?', 'source': 'She had moved from the wall of the garret, very near to the bench on which he sat.', 'answer': 'from the wall of the garret, very near'}
{'question': 'What turned to it when she spoke?', 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': 'invariably'}
{'question': 'Who released his arm?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What was it not?', 'source': 'It was not the faintness of physical weakness, though confinement and hard fare no doubt had their part in it.', 'answer': 'the faintness of physical weakness'}
{'question': 'Who did the question remind of his work, and he bent over it again?', 'source': 'But, the question reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did he resume?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': 'his work'}
{'question': 'What did he turn upon her with?', 'source': 'Once more, the two spectators started, as he turned upon her with a frightful suddenness.', 'answer': 'with a frightful suddenness'}
{'question': 'What do Manette see?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'how composed he has become'}
{'question': 'Who had Defarge not removed his from?', 'source': "``I want,'' said Defarge, who had not removed his gaze from the shoemaker, ``to let in a little more light here.", 'answer': "gaze from the shoemaker, ``to let in a little more light'' here"}
{'question': 'What is my gentle angel?', 'source': "What is your name, my gentle angel?''", 'answer': 'your name'}
{'question': "What do the maker's name feel?", 'source': 'I feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart.', 'answer': 'his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart'}
{'question': 'What had he put up?', 'source': 'He had put up a hand between his eyes and the light, and the very bones of it seemed transparent.', 'answer': 'a hand between his eyes and the light'}
{'question': 'What had he sunk in?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': 'in her arms'}
{'question': 'What did she have no fear of at her with the knife?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'of his striking'}
{'question': 'Who is good gentlemen?', 'source': "But she sat perfectly still in his grasp, and only said, in a low voice, ``I entreat you, good gentlemen, do not come near us, do not speak, do not move!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who knew she knew she ever heard these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who had his daughter followed?', 'source': "The prisoner had got into a coach, and his daughter had followed him, when Mr. Lorry's feet were arrested on the step by his asking, miserably, for his shoemaking tools and the unfinished shoes.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did he utter?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': 'this cry'}
{'question': 'Who remember those very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': 'the spirit of a fast-dying man'}
{'question': 'Who kissed them to him?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, who do I not doubt that you will find?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did she know she knew she ever heard these are not?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'the hands'}
{'question': 'What did she know she knew she ever heard are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'these'}
{'question': 'What did he lay down softly?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': 'the knife'}
{'question': 'What did she stay them with?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': 'with a motion of her hand'}
{'question': 'What had their part in it?', 'source': 'It was not the faintness of physical weakness, though confinement and hard fare no doubt had their part in it.', 'answer': 'confinement and hard fare no doubt'}
{'question': "Did Monsieur Defarge put this provender, and the lamp he carried, on the shoemaker's bench?", 'source': "Monsieur Defarge put this provender, and the lamp he carried, on the shoemaker's bench (there was nothing else in the garret but a pallet bed), and he and Mr. Lorry roused the captive, and assisted him to his feet.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he taken up?', 'source': 'He had taken it up, and was stooping to work again, when his eyes caught the skirt of her dress.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Do the workman suppose so?', 'source': 'I suppose so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she sigh ?', 'source': "She sighed ``No.''", 'answer': 'No.'}
{'question': "Who said, ``That's business'', ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it'', ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it''?", 'source': "``That's business,'' said Mr. Lorry, resuming on the shortest notice his methodical manners; ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it.''", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who then clasped them on her breast?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Had gradually been there?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who quickly brought them down?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did she hold him closer round?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': 'the neck'}
{'question': 'Do the old answer?', 'source': 'And the old answer:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the question remind him of his work, and he bent over again?', 'source': 'But, the question reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again.', 'answer': 'over it'}
{'question': 'Who did he sit staring at?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': 'at her'}
{'question': 'What did he refolded?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'his little packet'}
{'question': 'What can I not tell you at?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'at this time'}
{'question': 'What did his lips begin to form?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': 'some words'}
{'question': 'Do the workman not know?', 'source': "I do not know.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she lay her hand upon?', 'source': 'He recoiled, but she laid her hand upon his arm.', 'answer': 'upon his arm'}
{'question': 'Was only one soul to be seen?', 'source': 'Only one soul was to be seen, and that was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a very faint voice die out?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she hand in?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he find spoken for it?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'words'}
{'question': 'What did she lay upon his arm?', 'source': 'He recoiled, but she laid her hand upon his arm.', 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'What could she repeat?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': 'the question'}
{'question': "Who had the prisoner's daughter followed?", 'source': "The prisoner had got into a coach, and his daughter had followed him, when Mr. Lorry's feet were arrested on the step by his asking, miserably, for his shoemaking tools and the unfinished shoes.", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did she lay upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'Who still looked at her?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did she hand in?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who did he raise?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who could repeat the question?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did no sound proceed from?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': 'from them'}
{'question': 'What did he take her hair into again?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': 'into his hand'}
{'question': 'Had the face dropped again?', 'source': 'This time, a pair of haggard eyes had looked at the questioner, before the face had dropped again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I had?', 'source': "I have had a pattern in my hand.''", 'answer': 'a pattern in my hand'}
{'question': 'What did he take into his hand again?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': 'her hair'}
{'question': 'What did he try to secure in his breast?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he raise?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he look closely at?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': 'at it'}
{'question': 'What did his daughter hail?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': 'his softened tone and manner'}
{'question': 'What did gradually force themselves through?', 'source': 'As the captive of many years sat looking fixedly, by turns, at Mr. Lorry and at Defarge, some long obliterated marks of an actively intent intelligence in the middle of the forehead, gradually forced themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him.', 'answer': 'through the black mist that had fallen on him'}
{'question': 'Were gradually gone?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she then clasp on her breast?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he stoop over?', 'source': 'There was something awful in his unconsciousness of the figure that could have put out its hand and touched him as he stooped over his labor.', 'answer': 'over his labor'}
{'question': 'Who will take care of him until then we will remove him straight in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': 'his face'}
{'question': 'What did he see?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': 'her face'}
{'question': 'What is it in?', 'source': 'It is in the present mode.', 'answer': 'in the present mode'}
{'question': 'Was the task of recalling Monsieur Defarge from the vagrancy into which he always sank when he had spoken, like recalling some very weak person from a swoon, or endeavoring?', 'source': 'The task of recalling him from the vagrancy into which he always sank when he had spoken, was like recalling some very weak person from a swoon, or endeavoring, in the hope of some disclosure, to stay the spirit of a fast-dying man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did I teach?', 'source': 'I taught myself.', 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': "Did Defarge say, ``It is true''?", 'source': "``It is true,'' said Defarge, who was kneeling to look on and hear.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who raised them?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is monsieur?', 'source': "``Have you recognized him, monsieur?''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What had she laid upon my shoulder?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'her head'}
{'question': 'What did I never see?', 'source': 'I never saw the mode.', 'answer': 'the mode'}
{'question': 'What did he try to secure it in?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'in his breast'}
{'question': 'Who rested on it?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did he gloomily shake?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'his head'}
{'question': 'What lay on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood?', 'source': 'It lay on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What will I take care of him until then we will remove him straight in?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'in any case'}
{'question': 'What did she then clasp on her breast?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did he and Mr. Lorry rouse the captive?', 'source': "Monsieur Defarge put this provender, and the lamp he carried, on the shoemaker's bench (there was nothing else in the garret but a pallet bed), and he and Mr. Lorry roused the captive, and assisted him to his feet.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they clatter away under the feeble over-swinging lamps?', 'source': 'The postilion cracked his whip, and they clattered away under the feeble over-swinging lamps.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she know she knew ever heard these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did she know knew she ever heard these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did he look about?', 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': 'about him'}
{'question': 'Who is your name?', 'source': "What is your name, my gentle angel?''", 'answer': 'my gentle angel'}
{'question': 'Did his yellow rags of shirt lie open at the throat?', 'source': 'His yellow rags of shirt lay open at the throat, and showed his body to be withered and worn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who asked me, ``I forget what it was''?", 'source': '``I forget what it was you asked me.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What is?', 'source': 'All that I may tell you, here and now, is, that I pray to you to touch me and to bless me.', 'answer': "all that the maker's name may tell you"}
{'question': 'What is the same?', 'source': '``It is the same.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What rested on it?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had she laid her head upon?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'upon my shoulder'}
{'question': 'What did she put her two hands to?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'to her lips'}
{'question': 'What was he bent to work again again broken with?', 'source': 'With a weary sound that was not a sigh, nor a groan, he bent to work again, until the silence was again broken.', 'answer': 'with a weary sound that was not a sigh, nor a groan'}
{'question': 'Who did she kiss them to?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What face that I once knew so well at first I have unquestionably seen?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': 'Who can bear a little more?', 'source': "You can bear a little more?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did immediately knit?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What face that I once knew so well at first I thought it quite hopeless?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': "What shall the maker's name know at another time?", 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': "my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew these's hard, hard history"}
{'question': 'What will I take care of him until you return in?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'in any case'}
{'question': "Who can the maker's name not tell here?", 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he drop?', 'source': "On their reaching the courtyard he instinctively altered his tread, as being in expectation of a drawbridge; and when there was no drawbridge, and he saw the carriage waiting in the open street, he dropped his daughter's hand and clasped his head again.", 'answer': "his daughter's hand"}
{'question': 'Who cannot tell you here?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did the two spectators have?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she quickly bring down?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who did he still look at?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': 'at her'}
{'question': 'Where did it lie on which she stood?', 'source': 'It lay on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood.', 'answer': 'on that side of him which was not the side'}
{'question': 'Can a very faint voice not be?', 'source': 'It cannot be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his eyes in gloomy abstraction seek the ground?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did she kiss to him?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did she quickly bring down?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who is him?', 'source': "``Have you recognized him, monsieur?''", 'answer': 'monsieur'}
{'question': 'Who will I take care of until then we will remove him straight in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'Is your mind Monsieur Manette?', 'source': "Is there no old banker, no old business, no old servant, no old time, rising in your mind, Monsieur Manette?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she release?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': 'his arm'}
{'question': "Who did you ask, ``I forget what it was''?", 'source': '``I forget what it was you asked me.', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'What did she put to her lips?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'her two hands'}
{'question': 'What did he clasp again?', 'source': "On their reaching the courtyard he instinctively altered his tread, as being in expectation of a drawbridge; and when there was no drawbridge, and he saw the carriage waiting in the open street, he dropped his daughter's hand and clasped his head again.", 'answer': 'his head'}
{'question': 'What did she kiss to him?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Was the opened half-door secured at that angle for the time?', 'source': 'The opened half-door was opened a little further, and secured at that angle for the time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he glance at the shoe with some little passing touch of pride?', 'source': 'He glanced at the shoe with some little passing touch of pride.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who began to descend?', 'source': 'They began to descend; Monsieur Defarge going first with the lamp, Mr. Lorry closing the little procession.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who remembers them very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Did Defarge say, ``I want''?", 'source': "``I want,'' said Defarge, who had not removed his gaze from the shoemaker, ``to let in a little more light here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she then clasp them on?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': 'on her breast'}
{'question': 'Who were fainter?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did he go up to?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': 'to his white hair'}
{'question': 'What did they rest on?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': 'on it'}
{'question': 'Who will I take care of until you return in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'of him'}
{'question': 'Could no human intelligence have read the mysteries of his mind?', 'source': 'No human intelligence could have read the mysteries of his mind, in the scared blank wonder of his face.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I have?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': 'none'}
{'question': 'Who can I not tell here?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did she not yet trust?', 'source': 'Not yet trusting the tones of her voice, she sat down on the bench beside him.', 'answer': 'the tones of her voice'}
{'question': 'Did the very bones of it seem transparent?', 'source': 'He had put up a hand between his eyes and the light, and the very bones of it seemed transparent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, does anything that recall a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free!', 'source': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, anything that recalls a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free, weep for it, weep for it!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were overclouded again?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did Monsieur Defarge have no recollection whatever of his having been brought from his prison to that house, was apparent to one?', 'source': 'That he had no recollection whatever of his having been brought from his prison to that house, was apparent to them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is you?', 'source': "But she sat perfectly still in his grasp, and only said, in a low voice, ``I entreat you, good gentlemen, do not come near us, do not speak, do not move!''", 'answer': 'good gentlemen'}
{'question': 'What will I take until then we will remove him straight in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'care of him'}
{'question': 'What did he know?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': 'what had happened'}
{'question': 'What will I take until you return in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'care of him'}
{'question': 'What did he hold out his hand for?', 'source': 'As he held out his hand for the shoe that had been taken from him, Mr. Lorry said, still looking steadfastly in his face:', 'answer': 'for the shoe that had been taken from him'}
{'question': 'What did they come to?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'to him coherently'}
{'question': "What did you ask me, ``I forget''?", 'source': '``I forget what it was you asked me.', 'answer': 'what it was'}
{'question': 'Was an answer so very long ago?', 'source': "It was so very long ago.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he form this speech with his lips many times before he could utter it?', 'source': 'He formed this speech with his lips many times before he could utter it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had Defarge not removed his gaze from the shoemaker, ``to let in a little more light'' here?", 'source': "``I want,'' said Defarge, who had not removed his gaze from the shoemaker, ``to let in a little more light here.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they not traversed many steps of the long main staircase when he stopped, and stared at the roof and round at the walls?', 'source': 'They had not traversed many steps of the long main staircase when he stopped, and stared at the roof and round at the walls.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his face drop on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': 'in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it'}
{'question': 'What did those come to?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': 'to him coherently'}
{'question': "Is this time's mind Monsieur Manette?", 'source': "Is there no old banker, no old business, no old servant, no old time, rising in your mind, Monsieur Manette?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were naturally large?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What do you see?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'how composed he has become'}
{'question': 'What is it?', 'source': "``It is a lady's shoe.", 'answer': "a lady's shoe"}
{'question': 'What were naturally large?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was it not the faintness of physical weakness?', 'source': 'It was not the faintness of physical weakness, though confinement and hard fare no doubt had their part in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "If the maker's name touch, in touching my hair, what does anything that recall!", 'source': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, anything that recalls a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free, weep for it, weep for it!', 'answer': 'a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free'}
{'question': 'Will I take care of him until you return in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit looking fixedly at the questioner?', 'source': 'The shoe dropped to the ground, and he sat looking fixedly at the questioner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I get it with much difficulty after a long while?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge immediately call to her husband that she would get them?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge immediately called to her husband that she would get them, and went, knitting, out of the lamplight, through the courtyard.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lie there in a lethargy?', 'source': 'He had gradually dropped to the floor, and lay there in a lethargy, worn out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can the workman not say?', 'source': '``I cannot say that I mean to.', 'answer': 'that I mean to'}
{'question': 'Who had been there?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who stood?', 'source': 'She stood, like a spirit, beside him, and he bent over his work.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was he heard to say by degrees?', 'source': 'By degrees, in the pauses of his quick and labored breathing, he was heard to say:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she wear her golden hair in long curls?', 'source': 'Her golden hair, which she wore in long curls, had been hurriedly pushed aside, and fell down over her neck.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked unnaturally so?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who were gone?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Did they hear him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;''?", 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I remember very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did he and Mr. Lorry assist him to his feet?', 'source': "Monsieur Defarge put this provender, and the lamp he carried, on the shoemaker's bench (there was nothing else in the garret but a pallet bed), and he and Mr. Lorry roused the captive, and assisted him to his feet.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his hands release her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did Madame Defarge immediately call to her husband?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge immediately called to her husband that she would get them, and went, knitting, out of the lamplight, through the courtyard.', 'answer': 'that she would get them'}
{'question': 'What looked unnaturally so?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he have a white beard, raggedly cut, but not very long, a hollow face, and exceedingly bright eyes?', 'source': 'He had a white beard, raggedly cut, but not very long, a hollow face, and exceedingly bright eyes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What can I not say?', 'source': '``I cannot say that I mean to.', 'answer': 'that I mean to'}
{'question': 'What do I remember very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': "Is these's name the spirit of a fast-dying man's gentle angel?", 'source': "What is your name, my gentle angel?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man open this?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it lie on on which she stood?', 'source': 'It lay on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood.', 'answer': 'on that side of him which was not the side'}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man find spoken words for this speech?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she rock him on her breast like a child?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his yellow rags of shirt show his body to be withered?', 'source': 'His yellow rags of shirt lay open at the throat, and showed his body to be withered and worn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry take it in his hand?', 'source': 'Mr. Lorry took it in his hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was no I not a shoemaker by trade?', 'source': 'No, I was not a shoemaker by trade.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he readily respond to his daughter's drawing her arm through his?", 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who remembers coming up here?', 'source': "You remember coming up here?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did his yellow rags of shirt show his body to be worn?', 'source': 'His yellow rags of shirt lay open at the throat, and showed his body to be withered and worn.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the concentrated expression return to his forehead?', 'source': 'As the concentrated expression returned to his forehead, he seemed to become conscious that it was in hers too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she know she knew these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'she ever heard'}
{'question': 'Did she have no fear of his striking at her with the knife?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he bent to work again again broken with a weary sound that was not a sigh, nor a groan?', 'source': 'With a weary sound that was not a sigh, nor a groan, he bent to work again, until the silence was again broken.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who does not know?', 'source': "I do not know.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who no does not remember?', 'source': 'No, I do not remember.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was?', 'source': 'She was-- and He was-- before the slow years of the North Tower-- ages ago.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did his cold white head mingle with her radiant hair?', 'source': 'His cold white head mingled with her radiant hair, which warmed and lighted it as though it were the light of Freedom shining on him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he have?', 'source': 'He had a white beard, raggedly cut, but not very long, a hollow face, and exceedingly bright eyes.', 'answer': 'a white beard, raggedly cut, but not very long, a hollow face, and exceedingly bright eyes'}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man form this speech with his lips many times before he could utter it?', 'source': 'He formed this speech with his lips many times before he could utter it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he readily respond to his daughter took?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'her hand in both his own'}
{'question': 'Did he have no recollection whatever of his having been brought from his prison to that house, was apparent to them?', 'source': 'That he had no recollection whatever of his having been brought from his prison to that house, was apparent to them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her golden hair fall down over her neck?', 'source': 'Her golden hair, which she wore in long curls, had been hurriedly pushed aside, and fell down over her neck.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man utter this cry?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he ages ago?', 'source': 'She was-- and He was-- before the slow years of the North Tower-- ages ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she sit down on the bench beside him?', 'source': 'Not yet trusting the tones of her voice, she sat down on the bench beside him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he drink on?', 'source': 'In the submissive way of one long accustomed to obey under coercion, he ate and drank what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings, that they gave him to wear.', 'answer': 'what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings'}
{'question': 'If Manette will lock the door to secure post-horses from interruption, what do I not doubt?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'that you will find him'}
{'question': 'What did his face drop on in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': 'on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible'}
{'question': 'Was its deplorable peculiarity?', 'source': 'Its deplorable peculiarity was, that it was the faintness of solitude and disuse.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who supposes so?', 'source': 'I suppose so.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Will I take care of him until then we will remove him straight in any case?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I not a shoemaker by trade?', 'source': '``I am not a shoemaker by trade?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take the shoe up?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he seem to become conscious in?', 'source': 'As the concentrated expression returned to his forehead, he seemed to become conscious that it was in hers too.', 'answer': 'that it was in hers too'}
{'question': 'Did I-I learn it here?', 'source': 'I-I learned it here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the daughter watch him?', 'source': "Then, as the darkness closed in, the daughter laid her head down on the hard ground close at the father's side, and watched him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was I brought to the North Tower?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart?', 'source': 'I feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did that see nothing?', 'source': 'Only one soul was to be seen, and that was Madame Defarge-- who leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a strange thrill strike him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Can the maker's name not tell you at this time?", 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he gradually dropped to the floor?', 'source': 'He had gradually dropped to the floor, and lay there in a lethargy, worn out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will remove him straight?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Was it like the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago?', 'source': 'It was like the last feeble echo of a sound made long and long ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the spirit of a fast-dying man say those were the words?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the question remind him of over it again?', 'source': 'But, the question reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again.', 'answer': 'of his work, and he bent'}
{'question': 'What was it evidently for?', 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': 'for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him'}
{'question': 'Did they tear his white hair in a frenzy?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the question remind him of his work, and he bent over it again?', 'source': 'But, the question reminded him of his work, and he bent over it again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his daughter fall upon her knees before him?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had her golden hair been hurriedly pushed aside?', 'source': 'Her golden hair, which she wore in long curls, had been hurriedly pushed aside, and fell down over her neck.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his eyes in gloomy abstraction look about him in the old way?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had darkness fallen on him in its place?', 'source': 'Darkness had fallen on him in its place.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who returns?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Was it raised for a moment?', 'source': 'It was raised for a moment, and a very faint voice responded to the salutation, as if it were at a distance:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn upon her with a frightful suddenness?', 'source': 'Once more, the two spectators started, as he turned upon her with a frightful suddenness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she stay them with a motion of her hand?', 'source': 'The two spectators started forward, but she stayed them with a motion of her hand.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he?', 'source': 'She was-- and He was-- before the slow years of the North Tower-- ages ago.', 'answer': 'ages ago'}
{'question': 'Had he put up a hand between his eyes and the light?', 'source': 'He had put up a hand between his eyes and the light, and the very bones of it seemed transparent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both lie quiet?', 'source': 'The darkness deepened and deepened, and they both lay quiet, until a light gleamed through the chinks in the wall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she moved from the wall of the garret, very near to the bench on which he sat?', 'source': 'She had moved from the wall of the garret, very near to the bench on which he sat.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had been really otherwise?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did she lay her hand upon his arm?', 'source': 'He recoiled, but she laid her hand upon his arm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would the hollowness and thinness of his face have caused them to look large?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you see how you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stare at her with a fearful look?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she lay her hand upon his shoulder?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had been really otherwise?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he seem to become conscious that it was in hers too?', 'source': 'As the concentrated expression returned to his forehead, he seemed to become conscious that it was in hers too.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look at the two?', 'source': 'He looked at the two, less and less attentively, and his eyes in gloomy abstraction sought the ground and looked about him in the old way.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn her full to the light?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his lips begin to form some words?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did those come to him coherently?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I made shoes ever since?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did gradually force themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him?', 'source': 'As the captive of many years sat looking fixedly, by turns, at Mr. Lorry and at Defarge, some long obliterated marks of an actively intent intelligence in the middle of the forehead, gradually forced themselves through the black mist that had fallen on him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he have some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice?", 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he murmur an answer as if she had repeated it?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hold out his hand for the shoe that had been taken from him?', 'source': 'As he held out his hand for the shoe that had been taken from him, Mr. Lorry said, still looking steadfastly in his face:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did no sound proceed from them?', 'source': 'He stared at her with a fearful look, and after a while his lips began to form some words, though no sound proceeded from them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will we remove straight?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did he readily respond to his daughter took her hand in both his own?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did no help come from that quarter?', 'source': 'His haggard eyes turned to Defarge as if he would have transferred the question to him: but as no help came from that quarter, they turned back on the questioner when they had sought the ground.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it lie on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood?', 'source': 'It lay on that side of him which was not the side on which she stood.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he drink what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings?', 'source': 'In the submissive way of one long accustomed to obey under coercion, he ate and drank what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings, that they gave him to wear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he open this?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have more than one or two long golden hairs?', 'source': 'He opened this, carefully, on his knee, and it contained a very little quantity of hair: not more than one or two long golden hairs, which he had, in some old day, wound off upon his finger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they begin to descend?', 'source': 'They began to descend; Monsieur Defarge going first with the lamp, Mr. Lorry closing the little procession.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew these's hard, hard history at another time?", 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': "the maker's name"}
{'question': 'Have I had a pattern in my hand?', 'source': "I have had a pattern in my hand.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you see how composed he has become?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Whose name shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew these's hard, hard history at another time?", 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': "the maker's name"}
{'question': 'Had she laid her head upon my shoulder?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he utter this cry?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did confinement and hard fare no doubt have their part in it?', 'source': 'It was not the faintness of physical weakness, though confinement and hard fare no doubt had their part in it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the spirit of a fast-dying man remember those very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands?', 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were his few common tools and various scraps of leather at his feet and on his bench?', 'source': 'His few common tools and various scraps of leather were at his feet and on his bench.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did she sigh ``No.''?", 'source': "She sighed ``No.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did you ask me, ``I forget what it was''?", 'source': '``I forget what it was you asked me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is it a young lady's walking-shoe?", 'source': "It is a young lady's walking-shoe.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he advance his hand by little and little?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he lay the knife down softly?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the face at first I have unquestionably seen?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': 'that I once knew so well'}
{'question': 'Did invariably turn to it when she spoke?', 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was it evidently for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him?', 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they fainter?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When shall you know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history?', 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': 'at another time'}
{'question': "When shall the maker's name know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew these's hard, hard history?", 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': 'at another time'}
{'question': 'Is it in the present mode?', 'source': 'It is in the present mode.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is you good gentlemen?', 'source': "But she sat perfectly still in his grasp, and only said, in a low voice, ``I entreat you, good gentlemen, do not come near us, do not speak, do not move!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Manette see with?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'how you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now'}
{'question': 'Did he recollect what they had said to him?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go astray?', 'source': 'In the midst of the action he went astray, and, with another deep sigh, fell to work at his shoemaking.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were it the light of Freedom shining on him?', 'source': 'His cold white head mingled with her radiant hair, which warmed and lighted it as though it were the light of Freedom shining on him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the place my father?', 'source': '``You remember the place, my father?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take her hair into his hand again?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his hands not been seen in him before?', 'source': "He had a wild, lost manner of occasionally clasping his head in his hands, that had not been seen in him before; yet, he had some pleasure in the mere sound of his daughter's voice, and invariably turned to it when she spoke.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they overclouded again?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, what do I not doubt?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': 'that you will find him'}
{'question': 'Did his daughter hail his softened tone and manner?', 'source': 'Hailing his softened tone and manner, his daughter fell upon her knees before him, with her appealing hands upon his breast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they find these upon my sleeve?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he try to secure it in his breast?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could she repeat the question?', 'source': 'But, before she could repeat the question, he murmured an answer as if she had repeated it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I say those were the words?', 'source': 'Those were the words I said.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is it a lady's shoe?", 'source': "``It is a lady's shoe.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she hold him closer round the neck?', 'source': 'She held him closer round the neck, and rocked him on her breast like a child.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history at another time?', 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did I ask leave to teach myself?', 'source': "``I asked leave to teach myself, and I got it with much difficulty after a long while, and I have made shoes ever since.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she put her two hands to her lips?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he refolded his little packet?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he sunk in her arms?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she then clasp them on her breast?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he stooping to work again?', 'source': 'He had taken it up, and was stooping to work again, when his eyes caught the skirt of her dress.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I never see the mode?', 'source': 'I never saw the mode.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, do I not doubt that you will find him?', 'source': 'If you will lock the door to secure us from interruption, I do not doubt that you will find him, when you come back, as quiet as you leave him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not tell you at this time?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it the same?', 'source': '``It is the same.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Can they never help me to escape in the body? '", 'source': "They can never help me to escape in the body, though they may in the spirit. '", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his shoemaking die out of him?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do he lapse away?', 'source': 'He lapsed away, even for minutes, ringing those measured changes on his hands the whole time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he resume his work?', 'source': 'Finally, with a deep long sigh, he took the shoe up, and resumed his work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he know what had happened?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they been there?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is him monsieur?', 'source': "``Have you recognized him, monsieur?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they try speaking to him?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not say that I mean to?', 'source': '``I cannot say that I mean to.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she nestled down with him?', 'source': 'She had nestled down with him, that his head might lie upon her arm; and her hair drooping over him curtained him from the light.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they naturally large?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he readily respond to his daughter?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': 'took her hand in both his own'}
{'question': 'Did he look at it?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look at her?', 'source': 'He turned her full to the light, and looked at her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you bear a little more?', 'source': "You can bear a little more?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they come to him coherently?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he taken it up?', 'source': 'He had taken it up, and was stooping to work again, when his eyes caught the skirt of her dress.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the face that I once knew so well at first I thought it quite hopeless?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he see her face?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she know she knew she ever heard these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he go up to his white hair?', 'source': 'His hands released her as he uttered this cry, and went up to his white hair, which they tore in a frenzy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they gone?', 'source': 'They were overclouded again, they were fainter, they were gone; but they had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she hand them in?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she not yet trust the tones of her voice?', 'source': 'Not yet trusting the tones of her voice, she sat down on the bench beside him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he find spoken words for it?', 'source': 'But when he did find spoken words for it, they came to him coherently, though slowly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I feel?', 'source': 'I feel his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart.', 'answer': 'his sacred tears upon my face, and his sobs strike against my heart'}
{'question': 'Did it die out?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she kiss them to him?', 'source': 'With the tears streaming down her face, she put her two hands to her lips, and kissed them to him; then clasped them on her breast, as if she laid his ruined head there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I have none?', 'source': '``She had laid her head upon my shoulder, that night when I was summoned out-- she had a fear of my going, though I had none-- and when I was brought to the North Tower they found these upon my sleeve.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had his daughter followed him?', 'source': "The prisoner had got into a coach, and his daughter had followed him, when Mr. Lorry's feet were arrested on the step by his asking, miserably, for his shoemaking tools and the unfinished shoes.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he recoil?', 'source': 'He recoiled, but she laid her hand upon his arm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he take it up?', 'source': 'Advancing his hand by little and little, he took it up and looked at it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he raise them?', 'source': 'He raised them, and saw her face.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stoop over his labor?', 'source': 'There was something awful in his unconsciousness of the figure that could have put out its hand and touched him as he stooped over his labor.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his face drop on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it?', 'source': 'He had sunk in her arms, and his face dropped on her breast: a sight so touching, yet so terrible in the tremendous wrong and suffering which had gone before it, that the two beholders covered their faces.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry say, ``That's business'', ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it'', ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it''?", 'source': "``That's business,'' said Mr. Lorry, resuming on the shortest notice his methodical manners; ``and if business is to be done, I had better do it.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they look unnaturally so?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your name my gentle angel?', 'source': "What is your name, my gentle angel?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she stand?', 'source': 'She stood, like a spirit, beside him, and he bent over his work.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look closely at it?', 'source': 'He took her hair into his hand again, and looked closely at it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he exclaim?', 'source': 'he exclaimed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he sit staring at her?', 'source': 'A strange thrill struck him when she did so, and visibly passed over his frame; he laid the knife down softly, as he sat staring at her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I teach myself?', 'source': 'I taught myself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he drop his daughter's hand?", 'source': "On their reaching the courtyard he instinctively altered his tread, as being in expectation of a drawbridge; and when there was no drawbridge, and he saw the carriage waiting in the open street, he dropped his daughter's hand and clasped his head again.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he gloomily shake his head?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he eat?', 'source': 'In the submissive way of one long accustomed to obey under coercion, he ate and drank what they gave him to eat and drink, and put on the cloak and other wrappings, that they gave him to wear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it happen?', 'source': "It happened, at length, that he had occasion to change the instrument in his hand, for his shoemaker's knife.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she release his arm?', 'source': 'Releasing his arm, she laid her hand upon his shoulder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he know that he was free?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I suppose so?', 'source': 'I suppose so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is all that I may tell you?', 'source': 'All that I may tell you, here and now, is, that I pray to you to touch me and to bless me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she?', 'source': 'She was-- and He was-- before the slow years of the North Tower-- ages ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I not know?', 'source': "I do not know.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do you remember coming up here?', 'source': "You remember coming up here?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the face at first I thought it quite hopeless?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': 'that I once knew so well'}
{'question': 'Who did he recollect to?', 'source': 'Whether he knew what had happened, whether he recollected what they had said to him, whether he knew that he was free, were questions which no sagacity could have solved.', 'answer': 'what they had said to him'}
{'question': 'Do no I not remember?', 'source': 'No, I do not remember.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she quickly bring them down?', 'source': 'She quickly brought them down and handed them in;-- and immediately afterwards leaned against the door-post, knitting, and saw nothing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he stood?', 'source': 'When he had stood, for a minute or two, by the side of Defarge, the shoemaker looked up.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his eyes come slowly back?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he look about him?', 'source': "They heard him mutter, ``One Hundred and Five, North Tower;'' and when he looked about him, it evidently was for the strong fortress-walls which had long encompassed him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he clasp his head again?', 'source': "On their reaching the courtyard he instinctively altered his tread, as being in expectation of a drawbridge; and when there was no drawbridge, and he saw the carriage waiting in the open street, he dropped his daughter's hand and clasped his head again.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he readily respond to his daughter through?', 'source': "He readily responded to his daughter's drawing her arm through his, and took-- and kept-- her hand in both his own.", 'answer': "'s drawing her arm through his"}
{'question': 'Did he start?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can it not be?', 'source': 'It cannot be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he so confused, and so very slow to answer?', 'source': 'They tried speaking to him; but, he was so confused, and so very slow to answer, that they took fright at his bewilderment, and agreed for the time to tamper with him no more.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do you see with?', 'source': 'You see how composed he has become, and you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now.', 'answer': 'how you cannot be afraid to leave him with me now'}
{'question': 'Did he still look at her?', 'source': 'It died out, as everything but his shoemaking did die out of him, and he refolded his little packet and tried to secure it in his breast; but he still looked at her, and gloomily shook his head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they been really otherwise?', 'source': 'The hollowness and thinness of his face would have caused them to look large, under his yet dark eyebrows and his confused white hair, though they had been really otherwise; but, they were naturally large, and looked unnaturally so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they rest on it?', 'source': 'His eyes came slowly back, at last, to the face from which they had wandered; when they rested on it, he started, and resumed, in the manner of a sleeper that moment awake, reverting to a subject of last night.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it?', 'source': 'So sunken and suppressed it was, that it was like a voice underground.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will we remove him straight?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the face that I once knew so well at first I have unquestionably seen?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can I not tell you here?', 'source': 'But I cannot tell you at this time, and I cannot tell you here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the face that I once knew so well at?', 'source': 'At first I thought it quite hopeless, but I have unquestionably seen, for a single moment, the face that I once knew so well.', 'answer': 'at first I thought it quite hopeless'}
{'question': 'Do you return?', 'source': "In any case, I will take care of him until you return, and then we will remove him straight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it so very long ago?', 'source': "It was so very long ago.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall you know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history at another time?', 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Shall the maker's name know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew these's hard, hard history at another time?", 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they have?', 'source': 'She had no fear of his striking at her with the knife, though they had.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I remember them very well?', 'source': "I remember them very well.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I ask?', 'source': "I asked leave to--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the task of recalling him from the vagrancy into which he always sank when he had spoken, like recalling some very weak person from a swoon, or endeavoring?', 'source': 'The task of recalling him from the vagrancy into which he always sank when he had spoken, was like recalling some very weak person from a swoon, or endeavoring, in the hope of some disclosure, to stay the spirit of a fast-dying man.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it well?', 'source': '``It is well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is these well?', 'source': '``It is well.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What shall you know at another time?', 'source': '``O, sir, at another time you shall know my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history.', 'answer': 'my name, and who my mother was, and who my father, and how I never knew their hard, hard history'}
{'question': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, what does anything that recall!', 'source': 'If you touch, in touching my hair, anything that recalls a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free, weep for it, weep for it!', 'answer': 'a beloved head that lay on your breast when you were young and free'}
{'question': 'What did she know these are not the hands?', 'source': 'These are not the hands she knew, this is not the face she knew, this is not a voice she ever heard.', 'answer': 'she knew she ever heard'}
{'question': 'Who may be able to recognize the faces?', 'source': 'That she may be able to recognize the faces and know the persons.', 'answer': 'that she'}
{'question': 'What was he a strict man of?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': 'of business'}
{'question': 'Who may be able to know the persons?', 'source': 'That she may be able to recognize the faces and know the persons.', 'answer': 'that she'}
{'question': 'What took much heed of her?', 'source': 'She also bestowed a British cough on Madame Defarge; but, neither of the two took much heed of her.', 'answer': 'neither of the two'}
{'question': 'Who has influence around me?', 'source': 'I am well, and your father has influence around me.', 'answer': 'your father'}
{'question': 'Was the Quarter near the Banking-house?', 'source': 'She said that her father had spoken of hiring a lodging for a short term, in that Quarter, near the Banking-house.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did Mr. Lorry have?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Did the Bank close?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I come from?', 'source': "I come from Doctor Manette.''", 'answer': 'from Doctor Manette'}
{'question': "Who did all he could to propitiate, ``have the dear child here, and our good Pross''?", 'source': "``You had better, Lucie,'' said Mr. Lorry, doing all he could to propitiate, by tone and manner, ``have the dear child here, and our good Pross.", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What took to its knitting again?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': 'the hand'}
{'question': 'Who are more afraid of you than of these others?', 'source': "We are more afraid of you than of these others.''", 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Who did he leave with them?', 'source': 'He left Jerry with them, as a figure to fill a doorway that would bear considerable knocking on the head, and retained to his own occupations.', 'answer': 'Jerry'}
{'question': 'What did they go down into?', 'source': 'Scarcely noticing as yet, in what a curiously reserved and mechanical way Defarge spoke, Mr. Lorry put on his hat and they went down into the courtyard.', 'answer': 'into the courtyard'}
{'question': 'Did emphasis find two women; one?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the hand drop cold and heavy?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does two women; one's good Pross know no French?", 'source': "Our good Pross, Defarge, is an English lady, and knows no French.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he remove: giving them what comfort he could?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': 'Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'Who went down into the courtyard?', 'source': 'Scarcely noticing as yet, in what a curiously reserved and mechanical way Defarge spoke, Mr. Lorry put on his hat and they went down into the courtyard.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who cannot answer this?', 'source': 'You cannot answer this.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What did the stony manner of all the three impress upon him more and more?', 'source': "I believe,'' said Mr. Lorry, rather halting in his reassuring words, as the stony manner of all the three impressed itself upon him more and more, ``I state the case, Citizen Defarge?''", 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': 'What was my dear Lucie?', 'source': "``Courage, my dear Lucie,'' said Mr. Lorry, as he raised her.", 'answer': 'Courage'}
{'question': 'Who hopes _ you _ are pretty well!', 'source': "I hope _ you _ are pretty well!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was his anxious hand?', 'source': 'Defarge gave into his anxious hand, an open scrap of paper.', 'answer': 'an open scrap of paper'}
{'question': 'What impressed itself upon him more and more?', 'source': "I believe,'' said Mr. Lorry, rather halting in his reassuring words, as the stony manner of all the three impressed itself upon him more and more, ``I state the case, Citizen Defarge?''", 'answer': 'the stony manner of all the three'}
{'question': 'Who resumed her knitting?', 'source': 'She resumed her knitting and went out.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was emphasis the words:?', 'source': 'For answer he repeated, without any change of emphasis, the words:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge receive it as a compliment?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge received it as a compliment, and looked at her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did they find?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': 'two women; one'}
{'question': 'Did the Vengeance follow?', 'source': 'The Vengeance followed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they pass through as quickly as they might?', 'source': 'They passed through the intervening streets as quickly as they might, ascended the staircase of the new domicile, were admitted by Jerry, and found Lucie weeping, alone.', 'answer': 'through the intervening streets'}
{'question': 'What was the great trust he held not?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': 'his own'}
{'question': 'Had Mr. Lorry left her in exactly the same attitude some seventeen years ago?', 'source': 'said Mr. Lorry, who had left her in exactly the same attitude some seventeen years ago.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge turn her eyes again upon Lucie?', 'source': "``We have borne this a long time,'' said Madame Defarge, turning her eyes again upon Lucie.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I obtained from Charles to his wife?', 'source': 'I have obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife.', 'answer': 'the favor that the bearer has a short note'}
{'question': 'Who had himself?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge look down at her with perfect composure?', 'source': "``Your husband is not my business here,'' returned Madame Defarge, looking down at her with perfect composure.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Is surely for emphasis's safety?", 'source': "It is for their safety.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry answer, ``this is our poor prisoner's darling daughter, and only child''?", 'source': "``Yes, madame,'' answered Mr. Lorry; ``this is our poor prisoner's darling daughter, and only child.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who did I implore to have pity on me and not to exercise any power that you possess ``As a wife and mother''?", 'source': "``As a wife and mother,'' cried Lucie, most earnestly, ``I implore you to have pity on me and not to exercise any power that you possess, against my innocent husband, but to use it in his behalf.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he retain to?', 'source': 'He left Jerry with them, as a figure to fill a doorway that would bear considerable knocking on the head, and retained to his own occupations.', 'answer': 'to his own occupations'}
{'question': 'Who will help me to see him if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'What did she stop in?', 'source': 'She stopped in the act of putting the note in her bosom, and, with her hands yet at her neck, looked terrified at Madame Defarge.', 'answer': 'in the act of putting the note in her bosom'}
{'question': 'Who do I hope _ _ are pretty well!', 'source': "I hope _ you _ are pretty well!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What goes well with us-- much?', 'source': 'So far all goes well with us-- much, much better than it has of late gone with many poor souls.', 'answer': 'all'}
{'question': "Who observed, ``It is she''?", 'source': "``It is she,'' observed her husband.", 'answer': 'her husband'}
{'question': 'Who did his presence address by his name with a keenly observant look at him?', 'source': 'In a few moments, a man stood in his presence, who, with a keenly observant look at him, addressed him by his name.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did he remove Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': 'what comfort he could'}
{'question': 'What did Madame Defarge say ?', 'source': "``It is enough, my husband,'' said Madame Defarge.", 'answer': 'It is enough'}
{'question': 'What troubled him greatly in his secret mind?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did she look terrified at Madame Defarge?', 'source': 'She stopped in the act of putting the note in her bosom, and, with her hands yet at her neck, looked terrified at Madame Defarge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will do him no harm?', 'source': 'You will do him no harm.', 'answer': 'Mr. Lorry'}
{'question': 'Who have we seen suffer?', 'source': "All our lives, we have seen our sister-women suffer, in themselves and in their children, poverty, nakedness, hunger, thirst, sickness, misery, oppression and neglect of all kinds?''", 'answer': 'our sister-women'}
{'question': 'Who would he have hazarded for?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': 'for Lucie and her child'}
{'question': 'Who found two women; one?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who did she resume knitting?', 'source': 'She resumed her knitting and went out.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What wore him out with it?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What can I not safely leave yet?', 'source': '``Charles is safe, but I cannot safely leave this place yet.', 'answer': 'this place'}
{'question': 'What did his presence address him by with a keenly observant look at him?', 'source': 'In a few moments, a man stood in his presence, who, with a keenly observant look at him, addressed him by his name.', 'answer': 'by his name'}
{'question': 'Who did it trouble greatly in his secret mind?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did emphasis knit?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she say for?', 'source': 'She said that her father had spoken of hiring a lodging for a short term, in that Quarter, near the Banking-house.', 'answer': 'that her father had spoken of hiring a lodging for a short term'}
{'question': 'Who have we known _?', 'source': 'We have known _ their _ husbands and fathers laid in prison and kept from them, often enough?', 'answer': 'their _ husbands'}
{'question': 'Did Madame Defarge look at her husband?', 'source': 'Madame Defarge received it as a compliment, and looked at her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was not his own?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': 'the great trust Mr. Lorry held'}
{'question': 'Have I obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife?', 'source': 'I have obtained the favor that the bearer has a short note from Charles to his wife.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did it wear out with it?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did it wear out?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'itself'}
{'question': "Did Madame Defarge say ``It is enough''?", 'source': "``It is enough, my husband,'' said Madame Defarge.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does your father have?', 'source': 'I am well, and your father has influence around me.', 'answer': 'influence around me'}
{'question': 'Who has seen them?', 'source': '``I have seen them.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did it wear him out with?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': 'with it'}
{'question': 'Who was he?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': 'a strict man of business'}
{'question': 'Did he remove Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is for their safety?', 'source': "It is for their safety.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did emphasis move?', 'source': 'inquired Mr. Lorry, seeing that she moved as they moved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his presence address him by his name with?', 'source': 'In a few moments, a man stood in his presence, who, with a keenly observant look at him, addressed him by his name.', 'answer': 'with a keenly observant look at him'}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry answer, ``this is two women; one's poor prisoner's darling daughter, and only child''?", 'source': "``Yes, madame,'' answered Mr. Lorry; ``this is our poor prisoner's darling daughter, and only child.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will Mr. Lorry help to see him if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who will Mr. Lorry help me to see if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Was it dated from La Force?', 'source': 'It was dated from La Force, within an hour.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the shadow of the manner of these Defarges dark upon Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had Defarge been looking at her?', 'source': 'Defarge, who had been uneasily biting his thumb-nail and looking at her, collected his face into a sterner expression.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': 'a passionate thankful, womanly action'}
{'question': 'Did they find Lucie weeping?', 'source': 'They passed through the intervening streets as quickly as they might, ascended the staircase of the new domicile, were admitted by Jerry, and found Lucie weeping, alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they ascend the staircase of the new domicile?', 'source': 'They passed through the intervening streets as quickly as they might, ascended the staircase of the new domicile, were admitted by Jerry, and found Lucie weeping, alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do Mr. Lorry hope _!', 'source': "I hope _ you _ are pretty well!''", 'answer': 'you _ are pretty well'}
{'question': 'What can you not answer?', 'source': 'You cannot answer this.', 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'Who did a disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day lag on with?', 'source': 'A disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day lagged on with him.', 'answer': 'with him'}
{'question': "Did it bear the words in the Doctor's writing:?", 'source': "It bore the words in the Doctor's writing:", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the shadow attendant on Madame Defarge and her party seem then to fall on both the mother and the child?', 'source': 'The shadow attendant on Madame Defarge and her party seemed then to fall, threatening and dark, on both the mother and the child.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she say that her father had spoken of hiring a lodging for a short term?', 'source': 'She said that her father had spoken of hiring a lodging for a short term, in that Quarter, near the Banking-house.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who have I seen?', 'source': '``I have seen them.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did the shadow attendant on Madame Defarge and her party seem to fall so threatening and dark on the child?', 'source': 'The shadow attendant on Madame Defarge and her party seemed to fall so threatening and dark on the child, that her mother instinctively kneeled on the ground beside her, and held her to her breast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will pray you to be merciful?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What have I seen?', 'source': '``I have seen them.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did he consider?', 'source': 'He was again alone in his room of the previous night, considering what to do next, when he heard a foot upon the stair.', 'answer': 'what to do next'}
{'question': 'What was that?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': 'a passionate thankful, womanly action'}
{'question': 'What did it trouble him greatly in?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': 'in his secret mind'}
{'question': 'Who did he have?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What was he again alone in?', 'source': 'He was again alone in his room of the previous night, considering what to do next, when he heard a foot upon the stair.', 'answer': 'in his room of the previous night'}
{'question': 'Were they admitted by Jerry?', 'source': 'They passed through the intervening streets as quickly as they might, ascended the staircase of the new domicile, were admitted by Jerry, and found Lucie weeping, alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is it for?', 'source': "It is for their safety.''", 'answer': 'for their safety'}
{'question': "Was one of the first considerations which arose in the business mind of Mr. Lorry when business hours came round, this:-- that he had no right to imperil Tellson's by sheltering the wife of an emigrant prisoner under the Bank roof?", 'source': "One of the first considerations which arose in the business mind of Mr. Lorry when business hours came round, was this:-- that he had no right to imperil Tellson's by sheltering the wife of an emigrant prisoner under the Bank roof.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I come from Doctor Manette?', 'source': "I come from Doctor Manette.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a passionate thankful, womanly action?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are Miss Pross more afraid of Mr. Lorry than of these others?', 'source': "We are more afraid of you than of these others.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his anxious hand an open scrap of paper?', 'source': 'Defarge gave into his anxious hand, an open scrap of paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can Mr. Lorry not safely leave this place yet?', 'source': '``Charles is safe, but I cannot safely leave this place yet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will you be good to?', 'source': '``You will be good to my poor husband.', 'answer': 'to my poor husband'}
{'question': 'Who will she pray to be merciful?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Is our good Pross Defarge?', 'source': "Our good Pross, Defarge, is an English lady, and knows no French.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is our good Pross an English lady?', 'source': "Our good Pross, Defarge, is an English lady, and knows no French.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he a strongly made man with dark curling hair?', 'source': 'He was a strongly made man with dark curling hair, from forty-five to fifty years of age.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that a passionate thankful, womanly action?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the Vengeance return, ``We have seen nothing else''?", 'source': "``We have seen nothing else,'' returned The Vengeance.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will put her hands together?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Was the shadow of the manner of these Defarges dark upon himself?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knited?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did he think of finding out the wine-shop again?', 'source': 'At first, his mind reverted to Defarge, and he thought of finding out the wine-shop again and taking counsel with its master in reference to the safest dwelling-place in the distracted state of the city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will you help to see him if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who will you help me to see if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'May that she be able to recognize the faces?', 'source': 'That she may be able to recognize the faces and know the persons.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May that she be able to know the persons?', 'source': 'That she may be able to recognize the faces and know the persons.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did neither of the two take much heed of her?', 'source': 'She also bestowed a British cough on Madame Defarge; but, neither of the two took much heed of her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the hand take to its knitting again?', 'source': 'It was a passionate, loving, thankful, womanly action, but the hand made no response-- dropped cold and heavy, and took to its knitting again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they go down into the courtyard?', 'source': 'Scarcely noticing as yet, in what a curiously reserved and mechanical way Defarge spoke, Mr. Lorry put on his hat and they went down into the courtyard.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were Miss Pross as little as this child, and much less?', 'source': '``The wives and mothers we have been used to see, since we were as little as this child, and much less, have not been greatly considered?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Courage my dear Lucie?', 'source': "``Courage, my dear Lucie,'' said Mr. Lorry, as he raised her.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his presence address him by his name with a keenly observant look at him?', 'source': 'In a few moments, a man stood in his presence, who, with a keenly observant look at him, addressed him by his name.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have the wives and mothers we been used to see have not been greatly considered?', 'source': '``The wives and mothers we have been used to see, since we were as little as this child, and much less, have not been greatly considered?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can Mr. Lorry not answer this?', 'source': 'You cannot answer this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you be good to my poor husband?', 'source': '``You will be good to my poor husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he a strict man of business?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he leave Jerry with them?', 'source': 'He left Jerry with them, as a figure to fill a doorway that would bear considerable knocking on the head, and retained to his own occupations.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who moved?', 'source': 'inquired Mr. Lorry, seeing that she moved as they moved.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Will you help me to see him if you can?', 'source': "You will help me to see him if you can?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he think of taking counsel with its master in reference to the safest dwelling-place in the distracted state of the city?', 'source': 'At first, his mind reverted to Defarge, and he thought of finding out the wine-shop again and taking counsel with its master in reference to the safest dwelling-place in the distracted state of the city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who went out?', 'source': 'She resumed her knitting and went out.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Would he have hazarded for Lucie and her child?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she stop in the act of putting the note in her bosom?', 'source': 'She stopped in the act of putting the note in her bosom, and, with her hands yet at her neck, looked terrified at Madame Defarge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will she put together?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': 'her hands'}
{'question': 'Can I not safely leave this place yet?', 'source': '``Charles is safe, but I cannot safely leave this place yet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What lagged on with him?', 'source': 'A disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day lagged on with him.', 'answer': 'a disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day'}
{'question': 'Does our good Pross know no French?', 'source': "Our good Pross, Defarge, is an English lady, and knows no French.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he retain to his own occupations?', 'source': 'He left Jerry with them, as a figure to fill a doorway that would bear considerable knocking on the head, and retained to his own occupations.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does all go well with us-- much?', 'source': 'So far all goes well with us-- much, much better than it has of late gone with many poor souls.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do no substance in it, lucie?', 'source': "No substance in it, Lucie.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry do all he could to propitiate, ``have the dear child here, and our good Pross''?", 'source': "``You had better, Lucie,'' said Mr. Lorry, doing all he could to propitiate, by tone and manner, ``have the dear child here, and our good Pross.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they find two women; one?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I hope _!', 'source': "I hope _ you _ are pretty well!''", 'answer': 'you _ are pretty well'}
{'question': 'Who is well?', 'source': 'I am well, and your father has influence around me.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did they pass through the intervening streets as quickly as they might?', 'source': 'They passed through the intervening streets as quickly as they might, ascended the staircase of the new domicile, were admitted by Jerry, and found Lucie weeping, alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did her husband observe, ``It is she''?", 'source': "``It is she,'' observed her husband.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did I implore you to have pity on me and not to exercise any power that you possess ``As a wife and mother''?", 'source': "``As a wife and mother,'' cried Lucie, most earnestly, ``I implore you to have pity on me and not to exercise any power that you possess, against my innocent husband, but to use it in his behalf.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day lag on with him?', 'source': 'A disturbed and doleful mind he brought to bear upon them, and slowly and heavily the day lagged on with him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were we as little as this child, and much less?', 'source': '``The wives and mothers we have been used to see, since we were as little as this child, and much less, have not been greatly considered?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it trouble him greatly in his secret mind?', 'source': 'But the shadow of the manner of these Defarges was dark upon himself, for all that, and in his secret mind it troubled him greatly.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will she pray you to be merciful?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have we seen our sister-women suffer?', 'source': "All our lives, we have seen our sister-women suffer, in themselves and in their children, poverty, nakedness, hunger, thirst, sickness, misery, oppression and neglect of all kinds?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does your father have influence around me?', 'source': 'I am well, and your father has influence around me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the stony manner of all the three impress itself upon him more and more?', 'source': "I believe,'' said Mr. Lorry, rather halting in his reassuring words, as the stony manner of all the three impressed itself upon him more and more, ``I state the case, Citizen Defarge?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he consider what to do next?', 'source': 'He was again alone in his room of the previous night, considering what to do next, when he heard a foot upon the stair.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it wear him out with it?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I hope _ you _ are pretty well!', 'source': "I hope _ you _ are pretty well!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that all the writing?', 'source': 'That was all the writing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have we known _ their _ husbands?', 'source': 'We have known _ their _ husbands and fathers laid in prison and kept from them, often enough?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the great trust he held not his own?', 'source': "His own possessions, safety, life, he would have hazarded for Lucie and her child, without a moment's demur; but the great trust he held was not his own, and as to that business charge he was a strict man of business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it wear itself out?', 'source': 'It wore itself out, and wore him out with it, until the Bank closed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she resume her knitting?', 'source': 'She resumed her knitting and went out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you not answer this?', 'source': 'You cannot answer this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are we more afraid of you than of these others?', 'source': "We are more afraid of you than of these others.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he again alone in his room of the previous night?', 'source': 'He was again alone in his room of the previous night, considering what to do next, when he heard a foot upon the stair.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he repeat?', 'source': 'For answer he repeated, without any change of emphasis, the words:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she go out?', 'source': 'She resumed her knitting and went out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will she put her hands together?', 'source': 'She will put her hands together and pray you to be merciful.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they knit?', 'source': 'There, they found two women; one, knitting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I seen them?', 'source': '``I have seen them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you do him no harm?', 'source': 'You will do him no harm.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they move?', 'source': 'inquired Mr. Lorry, seeing that she moved as they moved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it for their safety?', 'source': "It is for their safety.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May we go?', 'source': "We may go.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I well?', 'source': 'I am well, and your father has influence around me.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it so much?', 'source': 'It was so much, however, to her who received it, that she turned from Defarge to his wife, and kissed one of the hands that knitted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he have himself?', 'source': 'To this lodging he at once removed Lucie and her child, and Miss Pross: giving them what comfort he could, and much more than he had himself.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was that so much?', 'source': 'It was so much, however, to her who received it, that she turned from Defarge to his wife, and kissed one of the hands that knitted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were two other passengers besides the one?', 'source': 'Two other passengers, besides the one, were plodding up the hill by the side of the mail.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the rider's horse blown?", 'source': "The rider's horse was blown, and both horse and rider were covered with mud, from the hoofs of the horse to the hat of the man.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the near leader violently shake upon it?', 'source': 'the near leader violently shook his head and everything upon it-- like an unusually emphatic horse, denying that the coach could be got up the hill.', 'answer': 'his head and everything'}
{'question': 'Was the step half in the coach and half?', 'source': 'He remained on the step, half in the coach and half out of; they remained in the road below him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Tom both listen?', 'source': 'They both listened.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who were close behind him?', 'source': 'The passenger booked by this history, was on the coach-step, getting in; the two other passengers were close behind him, and about to follow.', 'answer': 'the two other passengers'}
{'question': 'Did Shooter flounder?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the guard muse ``for Jerry made the same of that myself ?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': "That's a coincidence"}
{'question': 'Might a clammy and intensely cold mist do?', 'source': 'A clammy and intensely cold mist, it made its slow way through the air in ripples that visibly followed and overspread one another, as the waves of an unwholesome sea might do.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does a crown to drink?'s not long guard?", 'source': "It's not long, you see, guard.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What might do?', 'source': 'A clammy and intensely cold mist, it made its slow way through the air in ripples that visibly followed and overspread one another, as the waves of an unwholesome sea might do.', 'answer': 'a clammy and intensely cold mist'}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, who would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': 'the coach'}
{'question': "What did he open in the light of the coach-lamp on that side? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the guard, the coachman, and the two other passengers eye him distrustfully?', 'source': 'The guard, the coachman, and the two other passengers eyed him distrustfully.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What were the passenger's raised blunderbuss?", 'source': "The watchful guard, with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss, his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman, answered curtly, ``Sir.''", 'answer': 'his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman'}
{'question': 'Did Shooter stumble?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did he open it in on that side? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': 'in the light of the coach-lamp'}
{'question': 'Who had stopped when the coach stopped?', 'source': 'They had stopped when the coach stopped, and they kept close company with it.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did the guard sing out?', 'source': 'the guard sang out, as loud as he could roar.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': 'his fellow-passengers'}
{'question': 'One more be damned to the near leader!', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does it take the form of?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': 'of Lead'}
{'question': 'Do Jerry get you on the level?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Were the passenger's raised blunderbuss his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman?", 'source': "The watchful guard, with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss, his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman, answered curtly, ``Sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steam into?', 'source': 'It was dense enough to shut out everything from the light of the coach-lamps but these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steamed into it, as if they had made it all.', 'answer': 'into it'}
{'question': 'Who shall fire!', 'source': "I shall fire!''", 'answer': 'the guard'}
{'question': "What did the passenger open in the light of the coach-lamp on that side? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': 'a crown to drink.'}
{'question': 'Who made this rattle?', 'source': 'Whenever the leader made this rattle, the passenger started, as a nervous passenger might, and was disturbed in mind.', 'answer': 'the leader'}
{'question': 'What did the stillness consequent on the cessation of the rumbling and laboring of the coach make very quiet indeed?', 'source': 'The stillness consequent on the cessation of the rumbling and laboring of the coach, added to the stillness of the night, made it very quiet indeed.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Do Lorry make one?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I belong to?', 'source': "I belong to Tellson's Bank.", 'answer': "to Tellson's Bank"}
{'question': 'What did as often as the driver rest!', 'source': 'As often as the driver rested them and brought them to a stand, with a wary ``Wo-ho!', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did our booked passenger show in a moment that it was?', 'source': 'Our booked passenger showed in a moment that it was his name.', 'answer': 'his name'}
{'question': 'Did the rider stooped casting up his eyes at the guard, hand the passenger a small folded paper?', 'source': 'The rider stooped, and, casting up his eyes at the guard, handed the passenger a small folded paper.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he stand on?', 'source': 'With this hurried adjuration, he cocked his blunderbuss, and stood on the offensive.', 'answer': 'on the offensive'}
{'question': 'What did as bring to a stand!', 'source': 'As often as the driver rested them and brought them to a stand, with a wary ``Wo-ho!', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Did the passenger start?', 'source': 'Whenever the leader made this rattle, the passenger started, as a nervous passenger might, and was disturbed in mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is say Tom?', 'source': "``What do you say, Tom?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did he open it in the light of the coach-lamp on? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': 'on that side'}
{'question': 'Did the guard retort?', 'source': 'the guard retorted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the messenger guard?', 'source': "``I know this messenger, guard,'' said Mr. Lorry, getting down into the road-- assisted from behind more swiftly than politely by the other two passengers, who immediately scrambled into the coach, shut the door, and pulled up the window.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who may read this?', 'source': "I may read this?''", 'answer': 'the passenger'}
{'question': 'What did he turn to walk down?', 'source': 'After standing with the bridle over his heavily-splashed arm, until the wheels of the mail were no longer within hearing and the night was quite still again, he turned to walk down the hill.', 'answer': 'the hill'}
{'question': 'Did the emphatic leader look back?', 'source': 'The coachman looked back and the guard looked back, and even the emphatic leader pricked up his ears and looked back, without contradicting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they mash their way through?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': 'through the thick mud'}
{'question': 'Did the horses stop to breathe again?', 'source': 'The horses stopped to breathe again, and the guard got down to skid the wheel for the descent, and open the coach-door to let the passengers in.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they remain in below him?', 'source': 'He remained on the step, half in the coach and half out of; they remained in the road below him.', 'answer': 'in the road'}
{'question': 'Did the guard reply?', 'source': 'the guard replied.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his fellow-passengers have expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': 'in their boots'}
{'question': 'Who would much of that not do for!', 'source': 'Much of that would not do for you, Jerry!', 'answer': 'for you'}
{'question': 'What did the guard muse ``for I made the same of it myself ?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': "That's a coincidence"}
{'question': 'Did the coachman look back?', 'source': 'The coachman looked back and the guard looked back, and even the emphatic leader pricked up his ears and looked back, without contradicting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do Jerry get on the level?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he remain on out of?', 'source': 'He remained on the step, half in the coach and half out of; they remained in the road below him.', 'answer': 'on the step'}
{'question': "Must you know Tellson's Bank in London?", 'source': "You must know Tellson's Bank in London.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the passenger get in?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the coach lumber on again?', 'source': 'The coach lumbered on again, with heavier wreaths of mist closing round it as it began the descent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who do so now let's look at?", 'source': "So now let's look at you.''", 'answer': 'at you'}
{'question': 'Who gets you on the level?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Do Jerry say!', 'source': 'I say, Jerry!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who do I 'm?", 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': 'a devil at a quick mistake'}
{'question': 'What be damned to you!', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': 'one more'}
{'question': 'Did the guard look back?', 'source': 'The coachman looked back and the guard looked back, and even the emphatic leader pricked up his ears and looked back, without contradicting.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall the guard fire!', 'source': "I shall fire!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What does it take?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': 'the form of Lead'}
{'question': 'Was the pace suddenly checked?', 'source': "The pace was suddenly checked, and, with much splashing and floundering, a man's voice called from the mist, ``Is that the Dover mail?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could a mistake never be set right in your lifetime?', 'source': "``Keep where you are,'' the guard called to the voice in the mist, ``because, if I should make a mistake, it could never be set right in your lifetime.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could never be set right in your lifetime?', 'source': "``Keep where you are,'' the guard called to the voice in the mist, ``because, if I should make a mistake, it could never be set right in your lifetime.", 'answer': 'a mistake'}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, would the coach have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he read ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Whose voice did the guard to himself growl ?', 'source': "(``I do not like Jerry's voice, if it is Jerry,'' growled the guard to himself.", 'answer': "I do not like Jerry's voice"}
{'question': 'What did he cock?', 'source': 'With this hurried adjuration, he cocked his blunderbuss, and stood on the offensive.', 'answer': 'his blunderbuss'}
{'question': 'Who did the guard, the coachman, and the two other passengers eye distrustfully?', 'source': 'The guard, the coachman, and the two other passengers eyed him distrustfully.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': "What now let's look at you?", 'source': "So now let's look at you.''", 'answer': 'so'}
{'question': 'Whose voice did the guard to the coachman growl ?', 'source': "(``I do not like Jerry's voice, if it is Jerry,'' growled the guard to himself.", 'answer': "I do not like Jerry's voice"}
{'question': 'What hallo you!', 'source': "And hallo you!''", 'answer': 'and'}
{'question': 'What was Tom?', 'source': "``What did you make of it, Tom?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, who would he have put in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'Have the near leader had trouble enough to get you to it?', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did it begin?', 'source': 'The coach lumbered on again, with heavier wreaths of mist closing round it as it began the descent.', 'answer': 'the descent'}
{'question': 'What were his fellow-passengers now making?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': 'a general pretence of being asleep'}
{'question': 'Who do I get on the level?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': "Did the guard muse ``for Jerry made the same of that myself ``That's a coincidence''?", 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the guard to himself growl ?', 'source': "(``I do not like Jerry's voice, if it is Jerry,'' growled the guard to himself.", 'answer': "I do not like Jerry's voice"}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, who would the coach have put in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': 'himself'}
{'question': 'What do so now let look at you?', 'source': "So now let's look at you.''", 'answer': "'s"}
{'question': 'What may I read?', 'source': "I may read this?''", 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': "What does that's?", 'source': "That's a Blazing strange message.", 'answer': 'a Blazing strange message'}
{'question': 'What did the guard to the coachman growl ?', 'source': "(``I do not like Jerry's voice, if it is Jerry,'' growled the guard to himself.", 'answer': "I do not like Jerry's voice"}
{'question': 'Who made the same of it myself?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who did I make the same of it?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'What would not do for you!', 'source': 'Much of that would not do for you, Jerry!', 'answer': 'much of that'}
{'question': "'d you be in a Blazing bad way!", 'source': "You 'd be in a Blazing bad way, if recalling to life was to come into fashion, Jerry!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do and hallo!', 'source': "And hallo you!''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Were travellers very shy of being confidential on a short notice with robbers in those days?', 'source': 'In those days, travellers were very shy of being confidential on a short notice, for anybody on the road might be a robber or in league with robbers.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I make the same of myself?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': 'of it'}
{'question': 'Was it the Dover road that lay with whom this history has business?', 'source': 'It was the Dover road that lay, on a Friday night late in November, before the first of the persons with whom this history has business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did his fellow-passengers have in their boots?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': 'expeditiously secreted their watches and purses'}
{'question': 'Who was it?', 'source': "``What did you make of it, Tom?''", 'answer': 'Tom'}
{'question': 'What do I make?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': 'one'}
{'question': "Did these there's own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steam into it?", 'source': 'It was dense enough to shut out everything from the light of the coach-lamps but these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steamed into it, as if they had made it all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I get you on?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': 'on the level'}
{'question': 'Was the passenger booked by this history, on the coach-step?', 'source': 'The passenger booked by this history, was on the coach-step, getting in; the two other passengers were close behind him, and about to follow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has had trouble enough to get you to it?', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Did it lumber up Shooter's Hill?", 'source': "The Dover road lay, as to him, beyond the Dover mail, as it lumbered up Shooter's Hill.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What have I had enough to get you to it?', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': 'trouble'}
{'question': "Who does it's?", 'source': "It's not long, you see, guard.", 'answer': 'not long guard'}
{'question': 'Did a despatch send after you from over yonder?', 'source': '``A despatch sent after you from over yonder.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they stopped when they kept close company with it?', 'source': 'They had stopped when the coach stopped, and they kept close company with it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did our booked passenger show in a moment that it was his name?', 'source': 'Our booked passenger showed in a moment that it was his name.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who may come close?', 'source': "``He may come close; there's nothing wrong.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was it the likeliest thing upon the cards?', 'source': "As to the latter, when every posting-house and ale-house could produce somebody in ``the Captain's'' pay, ranging from the landlord to the lowest stable non-descript, it was the likeliest thing upon the cards.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do 'em nigh and if you 've got holsters to that saddle o ' yourn, do not let me see your hand go?", 'source': "And if you 've got holsters to that saddle o ' yourn, do not let me see your hand go nigh 'em.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the passenger open a crown to drink? in the light of the coach-lamp on that side? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I make myself?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': 'the same of it'}
{'question': "Do I belong to Tellson's Bank?", 'source': "I belong to Tellson's Bank.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might his hat-brim be capable of holding about half a gallon?', 'source': 'Jerry, left alone in the mist and darkness, dismounted meanwhile, not only to ease his spent horse, but to wipe the mud from his face, and shake the wet out of his hat-brim, which might be capable of holding about half a gallon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, what would he have put himself in?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': 'in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman'}
{'question': 'When could it never be set right?', 'source': "``Keep where you are,'' the guard called to the voice in the mist, ``because, if I should make a mistake, it could never be set right in your lifetime.", 'answer': 'in your lifetime'}
{'question': 'Who makes one?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did the passenger booked by this history, get in?', 'source': 'The passenger booked by this history, was on the coach-step, getting in; the two other passengers were close behind him, and about to follow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they all look from the coachman to the guard, and from the guard to the coachman?', 'source': 'They all looked from the coachman to the guard, and from the guard to the coachman, and listened.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who floundered?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Were his fellow-passengers now making a general pretence of being asleep?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they stopped when the coach stopped?', 'source': 'They had stopped when the coach stopped, and they kept close company with it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it dense enough to shut out everything from the light of the coach-lamps?', 'source': 'It was dense enough to shut out everything from the light of the coach-lamps but these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steamed into it, as if they had made it all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I going to Paris on business?', 'source': 'I am going to Paris on business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the guard to himself growl ``I do not like Jerry's voice''?", 'source': "(``I do not like Jerry's voice, if it is Jerry,'' growled the guard to himself.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn to walk down the hill?', 'source': 'After standing with the bridle over his heavily-splashed arm, until the wheels of the mail were no longer within hearing and the night was quite still again, he turned to walk down the hill.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who stumbled?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did Jerry make the same of that myself?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do I 'm a devil at a quick mistake?", 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did the guard muse ``for I made the same of it myself ``That's a coincidence''?", 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the two other passengers close behind him?', 'source': 'The passenger booked by this history, was on the coach-step, getting in; the two other passengers were close behind him, and about to follow.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he open it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side? '", 'source': "He opened it in the light of the coach-lamp on that side, and read-- first to himself and then aloud:'' ` Wait at Dover for Mam ` selle. '", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did as often as the driver rest them!', 'source': 'As often as the driver rested them and brought them to a stand, with a wary ``Wo-ho!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do so now let's look at you?", 'source': "So now let's look at you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it have roamed in its forlornness up the hill?', 'source': 'There was a steaming mist in all the hollows, and it had roamed in its forlornness up the hill, like an evil spirit, seeking rest and finding none.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he remain on the step out of?', 'source': 'He remained on the step, half in the coach and half out of; they remained in the road below him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What both listened?', 'source': 'They both listened.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did as bring them to a stand!', 'source': 'As often as the driver rested them and brought them to a stand, with a wary ``Wo-ho!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does that's a Blazing strange message?", 'source': "That's a Blazing strange message.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand on the offensive?', 'source': 'With this hurried adjuration, he cocked his blunderbuss, and stood on the offensive.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were his raised blunderbuss?', 'source': "The watchful guard, with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss, his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman, answered curtly, ``Sir.''", 'answer': 'his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman'}
{'question': 'What did it have in?', 'source': 'There was a steaming mist in all the hollows, and it had roamed in its forlornness up the hill, like an evil spirit, seeking rest and finding none.', 'answer': 'roamed in its forlornness up the hill'}
{'question': 'Did they mash their way through the thick mud?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his fellow-passengers have expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots?', 'source': 'With those words the passenger opened the coach-door and got in; not at all assisted by his fellow-passengers, who had expeditiously secreted their watches and purses in their boots, and were now making a general pretence of being asleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does it take the form of Lead?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did our booked passenger show in a moment?', 'source': 'Our booked passenger showed in a moment that it was his name.', 'answer': 'that it was his name'}
{'question': 'Were his raised blunderbuss his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman?', 'source': "The watchful guard, with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss, his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman, answered curtly, ``Sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the watchful guard with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss?', 'source': "The watchful guard, with his right hand at the stock of his raised blunderbuss, his left at the barrel, and his eye on the horseman, answered curtly, ``Sir.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who says!', 'source': 'I say, Jerry!', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did they remain in the road below him?', 'source': 'He remained on the step, half in the coach and half out of; they remained in the road below him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would much of that not do for you!', 'source': 'Much of that would not do for you, Jerry!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the leader make this rattle?', 'source': 'Whenever the leader made this rattle, the passenger started, as a nervous passenger might, and was disturbed in mind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What did the coach's booked passenger show in a moment?", 'source': 'Our booked passenger showed in a moment that it was his name.', 'answer': 'that it was his name'}
{'question': 'Did the near leader violently shake his head and everything upon it?', 'source': 'the near leader violently shook his head and everything upon it-- like an unusually emphatic horse, denying that the coach could be got up the hill.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he cock his blunderbuss?', 'source': 'With this hurried adjuration, he cocked his blunderbuss, and stood on the offensive.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it begin the descent?', 'source': 'The coach lumbered on again, with heavier wreaths of mist closing round it as it began the descent.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do and hallo you!', 'source': "And hallo you!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they all listen?', 'source': 'They all looked from the coachman to the guard, and from the guard to the coachman, and listened.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'One more be damned to you!', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Does it's not long guard?", 'source': "It's not long, you see, guard.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steam into it?', 'source': 'It was dense enough to shut out everything from the light of the coach-lamps but these its own workings, and a few yards of road; and the reek of the laboring horses steamed into it, as if they had made it all.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May the passenger read this?', 'source': "I may read this?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May I read this?', 'source': "I may read this?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it Tom?', 'source': "``What did you make of it, Tom?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May he come close?', 'source': "``He may come close; there's nothing wrong.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both listen?', 'source': 'They both listened.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I make the same of it myself?', 'source': "``That's a coincidence, too,'' the guard mused, ``for I made the same of it myself.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I had trouble enough to get you to it?', 'source': "One more pull and you 're at the top and be damned to you, for I have had trouble enough to get you to it!", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I make one?', 'source': "For I 'm a devil at a quick mistake, and when I make one it takes the form of Lead.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they flounder?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Shall I fire!', 'source': "I shall fire!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they stumble?', 'source': 'With drooping heads and tremulous tails, they mashed their way through the thick mud, floundering and stumbling between whiles, as if they were falling to pieces at the larger joints.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I get you on the level?', 'source': "``After that there gallop from Temple Bar, old lady, I will not trust your fore-legs till I get you on the level,'' said this hoarse messenger, glancing at his mare.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, would he have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman?', 'source': 'If any one of the three had had the hardihood to propose to another to walk on a little ahead into the mist and darkness, he would have put himself in a fair way of getting shot instantly as a highwayman.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could it never be set right in your lifetime?', 'source': "``Keep where you are,'' the guard called to the voice in the mist, ``because, if I should make a mistake, it could never be set right in your lifetime.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I say!', 'source': 'I say, Jerry!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What set too strong and fast for him?', 'source': 'But, though the Doctor tried hard, and never ceased trying, to get Charles Darnay set at liberty, or at least to get him brought to trial, the public current of the time set too strong and fast for him.', 'answer': 'the public current of the time'}
{'question': 'Did the Doctor try hard?', 'source': 'But, though the Doctor tried hard, and never ceased trying, to get Charles Darnay set at liberty, or at least to get him brought to trial, the public current of the time set too strong and fast for him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were models of it worn on from which it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied?', 'source': 'Models of it were worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded, and it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied.', 'answer': 'on breasts'}
{'question': 'Did the Doctor walk with a steady head: confident in his power, cautiously persistent in his end?', 'source': "Among these terrors, and the brood belonging to them, the Doctor walked with a steady head: confident in his power, cautiously persistent in his end, never doubting that he would save Lucie's husband at last.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What superseded the Cross?', 'source': 'It superseded the Cross.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the Doctor never cease trying?', 'source': 'But, though the Doctor tried hard, and never ceased trying, to get Charles Darnay set at liberty, or at least to get him brought to trial, the public current of the time set too strong and fast for him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did it all tend?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': 'to a good end'}
{'question': 'What had been accorded to him to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system?', 'source': 'That, in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system, it had been accorded to him to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': "Was the Doctor's beloved child helpful in restoring me to myself?", 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had it been accorded to to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system?', 'source': 'That, in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system, it had been accorded to him to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What was it lost in?', 'source': 'Hold of it was lost in the raging fever of a nation, as it is in the fever of one patient.', 'answer': 'in the raging fever of a nation'}
{'question': 'What did he observe as a curiosity?', 'source': 'Nothing unbecoming tinged the pride; it was a natural and worthy one; but he observed it as a curiosity.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What had it lopped off?', 'source': 'Twenty-two friends of high public mark, twenty-one living and one dead, it had lopped the heads off, in one morning, in as many minutes.', 'answer': 'the heads'}
{'question': 'Was Silent humane?', 'source': 'Silent, humane, indispensable in hospital and prison, using his art equally among assassins and victims, he was a man apart.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it taken to?', 'source': 'It was taken to pieces, like a toy-puzzle for a young Devil, and was put together again when the occasion wanted it.', 'answer': 'to pieces'}
{'question': 'What is in the fever of one patient?', 'source': 'Hold of it was lost in the raging fever of a nation, as it is in the fever of one patient.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Were and the evening and morning the first day?', 'source': 'Though days and nights circled as regularly as when time was young, and the evening and morning were the first day, other count of time there was none.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do it shear off so many?', 'source': 'It sheared off heads so many, that it, and the ground it most polluted, were a rotten red.', 'answer': 'heads'}
{'question': 'Did a misgiving arise within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did a misgiving arise within him?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': 'that such dread experiences would revive the old danger'}
{'question': 'Does the doctor communicated under an injunction of secrecy on which he had no need to dwell to Mr. Lorry?', 'source': 'To Mr. Lorry, the Doctor communicated under an injunction of secrecy on which he had no need to dwell, that the crowd had taken him through a scene of carnage to the prison of La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will do it by the aid of Heaven?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was he stronger than?', 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': 'than his namesake, and blinder'}
{'question': 'Whose husband did the Doctor doubt?', 'source': "Among these terrors, and the brood belonging to them, the Doctor walked with a steady head: confident in his power, cautiously persistent in his end, never doubting that he would save Lucie's husband at last.", 'answer': "that he would save Lucie's husband at last"}
{'question': 'What did it supersede?', 'source': 'It superseded the Cross.', 'answer': 'the Cross'}
{'question': "When did he feel that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him?", 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': 'for the first time'}
{'question': 'What was not mere waste?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did he observe it as?', 'source': 'Nothing unbecoming tinged the pride; it was a natural and worthy one; but he observed it as a curiosity.', 'answer': 'as a curiosity'}
{'question': 'What was my friend?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': 'the good end'}
{'question': 'Who had he never seen his friend in his present aspect had never at all known him in his present character?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What had he never seen his friend in his present aspect he had never at all known him in?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': 'in his present character'}
{'question': 'Who had he never seen his friend in his present aspect he had never at all known in his present character?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What had he never seen his friend in he had never at all known him in his present character?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': 'in his present aspect'}
{'question': 'Who had he never seen in his present aspect he had never at all known him in his present character?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': 'his friend'}
{'question': 'What did he seem on?', 'source': 'That, he seemed on the point of being at once released, when the tide in his favor met with some unexplained check (not intelligible to the Doctor), which led to a few words of secret conference.', 'answer': 'on the point of being at once released'}
{'question': "Did he tear away the gates of God's own Temple?", 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could reverse them?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': 'the liveliest gratitude and affection'}
{'question': 'Who could the liveliest gratitude and affection reverse?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What did the Doctor doubt?', 'source': "Among these terrors, and the brood belonging to them, the Doctor walked with a steady head: confident in his power, cautiously persistent in his end, never doubting that he would save Lucie's husband at last.", 'answer': "that he would save Lucie's husband at last"}
{'question': 'What could the liveliest gratitude and affection reverse?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What was it not?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': 'mere waste'}
{'question': 'What will I do by the aid of Heaven?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Were models of it worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded?', 'source': 'Models of it were worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded, and it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did days and nights circle as regularly as when time was young, and the evening and morning were the first day?', 'source': 'Though days and nights circled as regularly as when time was young, and the evening and morning were the first day, other count of time there was none.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would Greater things than the Doctor had at that time to contend with, have yielded before his persevering purpose?', 'source': 'Greater things than the Doctor had at that time to contend with, would have yielded before his persevering purpose.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the prisoner pass out?', 'source': 'One prisoner there was, he said, who had been discharged into the street free, but at whom a mistaken savage had thrust a pike as he passed out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was this new life of the Doctor's an anxious life?", 'source': "This new life of the Doctor's was an anxious life, no doubt; still, the sagacious Mr. Lorry saw that there was a new sustaining pride in it.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the time long?', 'source': 'And yet, observing the strange law of contradiction which obtains in all such cases, the time was long, while it flamed by so fast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him for the first time?", 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the first time flame by so fast?', 'source': 'And yet, observing the strange law of contradiction which obtains in all such cases, the time was long, while it flamed by so fast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he seen?', 'source': 'The sights he had seen there, with brief snatches of food and sleep by intervals, shall remain untold.', 'answer': 'there shall remain untold'}
{'question': 'What is it in?', 'source': 'Hold of it was lost in the raging fever of a nation, as it is in the fever of one patient.', 'answer': 'in the fever of one patient'}
{'question': 'What did he feel in for the first time?', 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': "that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him"}
{'question': "What did he feel that in, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him for the first time?", 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': 'in that sharp fire'}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'Nothing unbecoming tinged the pride; it was a natural and worthy one; but he observed it as a curiosity.', 'answer': 'a natural and worthy one'}
{'question': 'Was time young?', 'source': 'Though days and nights circled as regularly as when time was young, and the evening and morning were the first day, other count of time there was none.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were samaritans seated on the bodies of their victims?', 'source': 'Being besought to go to him and dress the wound, the Doctor had passed out at the same gate, and had found him in the arms of a company of Samaritans, who were seated on the bodies of their victims.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were the preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie reversed?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What could he have had but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': 'no pride'}
{'question': 'Had the Doctor found him in the arms of a company of Samaritans?', 'source': 'Being besought to go to him and dress the wound, the Doctor had passed out at the same gate, and had found him in the arms of a company of Samaritans, who were seated on the bodies of their victims.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she only know?', 'source': 'She only knew that there had been an attack upon the prisons, that all political prisoners had been in danger, and that some had been dragged out by the crowd and murdered.', 'answer': 'that there had been an attack upon the prisons'}
{'question': 'Was it lost in the raging fever of a nation?', 'source': 'Hold of it was lost in the raging fever of a nation, as it is in the fever of one patient.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he feel that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged for the first time?', 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': "the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him"}
{'question': 'Was it the sign of the regeneration of the human race?', 'source': 'It was the sign of the regeneration of the human race.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the Doctor besought to go to him?', 'source': 'Being besought to go to him and dress the wound, the Doctor had passed out at the same gate, and had found him in the arms of a company of Samaritans, who were seated on the bodies of their victims.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he seen there shall remain untold?', 'source': 'The sights he had seen there, with brief snatches of food and sleep by intervals, shall remain untold.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she only know that there had been an attack upon the prisons?', 'source': 'She only knew that there had been an attack upon the prisons, that all political prisoners had been in danger, and that some had been dragged out by the crowd and murdered.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did so much more wicked and distracted have the Revolution grown in that December month?', 'source': 'So much more wicked and distracted had the Revolution grown in that December month, that the rivers of the South were encumbered with the bodies of the violently drowned by night, and prisoners were shot in lines and squares under the southern wintry sun.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did it all tend to a good end?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What ruin?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What will I do it by?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': 'by the aid of Heaven'}
{'question': 'Did he seem on the point of being at once released?', 'source': 'That, he seemed on the point of being at once released, when the tide in his favor met with some unexplained check (not intelligible to the Doctor), which led to a few words of secret conference.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the appearance and the story of the Bastille Captive remove him from all other men in the exercise of his skill?', 'source': 'In the exercise of his skill, the appearance and the story of the Bastille Captive removed him from all other men.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'The mad joy over the prisoners who were saved, had astounded him scarcely less than the mad ferocity against those who were cut to pieces?', 'source': 'The mad joy over the prisoners who were saved, had astounded him scarcely less than the mad ferocity against those who were cut to pieces.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the public current of the time set too strong and fast for him?', 'source': 'But, though the Doctor tried hard, and never ceased trying, to get Charles Darnay set at liberty, or at least to get him brought to trial, the public current of the time set too strong and fast for him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it lopped the heads off?', 'source': 'Twenty-two friends of high public mark, twenty-one living and one dead, it had lopped the heads off, in one morning, in as many minutes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it taken to pieces?', 'source': 'It was taken to pieces, like a toy-puzzle for a young Devil, and was put together again when the occasion wanted it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it supersede the Cross?', 'source': 'It superseded the Cross.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What flamed by so fast?', 'source': 'And yet, observing the strange law of contradiction which obtains in all such cases, the time was long, while it flamed by so fast.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Do it shear off heads so many?', 'source': 'It sheared off heads so many, that it, and the ground it most polluted, were a rotten red.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it been accorded to him to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system?', 'source': 'That, in the first frantic greetings lavished on himself as a notable sufferer under the overthrown system, it had been accorded to him to have Charles Darnay brought before the lawless Court, and examined.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were models of it worn on breasts from which it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied?', 'source': 'Models of it were worn on breasts from which the Cross was discarded, and it was bowed down to and believed in where the Cross was denied.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could the liveliest gratitude and affection reverse them?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he not suspected or brought in question?', 'source': 'He was not suspected or brought in question, any more than if he had indeed been recalled to life some eighteen years before, or were a Spirit moving among mortals.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I do it by the aid of Heaven?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not mere waste?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he stronger than his namesake, and blinder?', 'source': "The name of the strong man of Old Scripture had descended to the chief functionary who worked it; but, so armed, he was stronger than his namesake, and blinder, and tore away the gates of God's own Temple every day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did Mr. Lorry receive these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age?', 'source': 'As Mr. Lorry received these confidences, and as he watched the face of his friend now sixty-two years of age, a misgiving arose within him that such dread experiences would revive the old danger.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it put together again when the occasion wanted it?', 'source': 'It was taken to pieces, like a toy-puzzle for a young Devil, and was put together again when the occasion wanted it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it in the fever of one patient?', 'source': 'Hold of it was lost in the raging fever of a nation, as it is in the fever of one patient.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a natural and worthy one?', 'source': 'Nothing unbecoming tinged the pride; it was a natural and worthy one; but he observed it as a curiosity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was my beloved child helpful in restoring me to myself?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the good end my friend?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he never seen his friend in his present aspect he had never at all known him in his present character?', 'source': 'But, he had never seen his friend in his present aspect: he had never at all known him in his present character.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he observe it as a curiosity?', 'source': 'Nothing unbecoming tinged the pride; it was a natural and worthy one; but he observed it as a curiosity.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her?', 'source': "As my beloved child was helpful in restoring me to myself, I will be helpful now in restoring the dearest part of herself to her; by the aid of Heaven I will do it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do it ruin?', 'source': '``It all tended to a good end, my friend; it was not mere waste and ruin.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he pass out?', 'source': 'One prisoner there was, he said, who had been discharged into the street free, but at whom a mistaken savage had thrust a pike as he passed out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'The mad joy over the prisoners who were saved, had astounded the man sitting as President scarcely less than the mad ferocity against those who were cut to pieces?', 'source': 'The mad joy over the prisoners who were saved, had astounded him scarcely less than the mad ferocity against those who were cut to pieces.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he feel that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him for the first time?", 'source': "For the first time he felt that in that sharp fire, he had slowly forged the iron which could break the prison door of his daughter's husband, and deliver him.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him?', 'source': 'The preceding relative positions of himself and Lucie were reversed, yet only as the liveliest gratitude and affection could reverse them, for he could have had no pride but in rendering some service to her who had rendered so much to him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it flame by so fast?', 'source': 'And yet, observing the strange law of contradiction which obtains in all such cases, the time was long, while it flamed by so fast.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When would she burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance was on him?', 'source': 'Sometimes, at night on kissing her father, she would burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance, under Heaven, was on him.', 'answer': 'at night on kissing her father'}
{'question': 'What did see her when the chances served she would have waited out the day?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did a cutter of wood into lengths for burning speak?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Who said: ``summoned for to-morrow?''", 'source': "To whom did he appear to repeat her faltering words, when, raising his voice and turning his head towards the door of the room from which he had issued, he said: ``Removed to the Conciergerie, and summoned for to-morrow?''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the tumbrils jolt heavily?', 'source': 'Every day, through the stony streets, the tumbrils now jolted heavily, filled with Condemned.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What fell as he spoke?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': 'the billet'}
{'question': "Who had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight?''", 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'How many more billets did he throw into his basket?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': 'two more billets'}
{'question': 'What can happen to him without my knowledge?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'nothing'}
{'question': 'Who had been true to her duties?', 'source': 'But, from the hour when she had taken the white head to her fresh young bosom in the garret of Saint Antoine, she had been true to her duties.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What do off _!', 'source': 'And off _ her _ head comes!', 'answer': 'her _ head comes'}
{'question': 'Who did this leave bewildered?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'Were such grace as was visible in a something showing how warped and perverted all things good by nature become?', 'source': 'Such grace as was visible in it, made it the uglier, showing how warped and perverted all things good by nature were become.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the staunch old gentleman save?', 'source': 'What he could save for the owners, he saved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did it see when the chances served she would have waited out the day?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': "Is a cutter of wood into lengths for burning's work my business?", 'source': 'My work is my business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who always gave him drink-money?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did Everything have its appointed place and its appointed time?', 'source': 'Everything had its appointed place and its appointed time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had got somebody to scrawl it up for him?', 'source': 'He had got somebody to scrawl it up for him, however, who had squeezed Death in with most inappropriate difficulty.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What could no fight have been as this dance?', 'source': 'No fight could have been half so terrible as this dance.', 'answer': 'half so terrible'}
{'question': 'Was the wood-sawyer at work?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who readily received drink-money?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who stood before her when she lifted up the eyes?', 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What was impossible to be in his sight?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What were they?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': 'a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags'}
{'question': 'Was all else wall?', 'source': 'The hovel of a cutter of wood into lengths for burning, was the only house at that end; all else was wall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was the delicate foot mincing in this slough of blood and dirt?', 'source': "The maidenly bosom bared to this, the pretty almost-child's head thus distracted, the delicate foot mincing in this slough of blood and dirt, were types of the disjointed time.", 'answer': "the pretty almost-child's head thus distracted"}
{'question': 'Who threw it into a basket?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did he throw two more billets into?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': 'into his basket'}
{'question': 'What had he got to scrawl it up for him?', 'source': 'He had got somebody to scrawl it up for him, however, who had squeezed Death in with most inappropriate difficulty.', 'answer': 'somebody'}
{'question': 'What did this leave frightened?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'Was Tickle tickle?', 'source': 'Tickle, tickle; Pickle, pickle!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What may you kiss your hand towards?', 'source': "You may kiss your hand towards that highest shelving roof.''", 'answer': 'towards that highest shelving roof'}
{'question': 'Was Liberty, equality, fraternity, or death; with many?', 'source': "If the suddenness of her calamity, and the whirling wheels of the time, had stunned the Doctor's daughter into awaiting the result in idle despair, it would but have been with her as it was with many.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who to make a sign of recognition?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What cannothing happen to him without?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'without my knowledge'}
{'question': 'Who were dancing like five thousand demons?', 'source': 'There could not be fewer than five hundred people, and they were dancing like five thousand demons.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What do off _?', 'source': 'And off _ its _ head comes.', 'answer': 'its _ head comes'}
{'question': 'Who did they stop to dance about?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': 'about Lucie'}
{'question': 'Who heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along?', 'source': 'But, he was not far off, for presently she heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along, which filled her with fear.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'When would he generally say?', 'source': 'he would generally say at those times, and would briskly fall to his sawing again.', 'answer': 'at those times'}
{'question': 'Who noticed her on the third day of her being there?', 'source': 'On the third day of her being there, he noticed her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who lost her color?', 'source': 'She lost her color, and the old and intent expression was a constant, not an occasional, thing; otherwise, she remained very pretty and comely.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who thinks of my husband?', 'source': "But when I think of my husband, and the mercies of these people--''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What were dancing like five thousand demons?', 'source': 'There could not be fewer than five hundred people, and they were dancing like five thousand demons.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who accosted her the moment she appeared?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who must see Lorry?', 'source': "I must see Lorry.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who had he got somebody to scrawl it up for?', 'source': 'He had got somebody to scrawl it up for him, however, who had squeezed Death in with most inappropriate difficulty.', 'answer': 'for him'}
{'question': 'When did she never miss?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'a single day'}
{'question': 'When was it?', 'source': 'It was a day of some wild rejoicing, and a festival.', 'answer': 'a day of some wild rejoicing, and a festival'}
{'question': 'Who did he stand before when she lifted up the eyes?', 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': 'before her'}
{'question': 'What you to make a sign of?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': 'of recognition'}
{'question': 'Who did he accost her the moment appeared?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did he readily receive?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': 'drink-money'}
{'question': 'Did the feathery snow fall as quietly?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who has timely information?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Does yes's not a cutter of wood into lengths for burning's business?", 'source': "But it's not my business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was looking out for her?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the clock strike two?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was he actually summoned before?', 'source': 'I am well prepared, but there are precautions to be taken, that could not be taken until he was actually summoned before the Tribunal.', 'answer': 'before the Tribunal'}
{'question': 'What had she been true to?', 'source': 'But, from the hour when she had taken the white head to her fresh young bosom in the garret of Saint Antoine, she had been true to her duties.', 'answer': 'to her duties'}
{'question': 'What is nearly ended, my darling; he shall be restored to you within a few hours?', 'source': 'Your suspense is nearly ended, my darling; he shall be restored to you within a few hours; I have encompassed him with every protection.', 'answer': 'your suspense'}
{'question': 'Who was alone at other times?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who kissed her hand?', 'source': "``No, father,'' said Lucie, yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand, ``no.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did women fill the place?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who arranged the little household as exactly as if her husband had been there?', 'source': 'As soon as they were established in their new residence, and her father had entered on the routine of his avocations, she arranged the little household as exactly as if her husband had been there.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'When was she alone?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'at other times'}
{'question': 'Who would not one of them harm?', 'source': "Not one of them would harm you.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who could he save for?', 'source': 'What he could save for the owners, he saved.', 'answer': 'for the owners'}
{'question': 'What had he got somebody to scrawl up for him?', 'source': 'He had got somebody to scrawl it up for him, however, who had squeezed Death in with most inappropriate difficulty.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated?', 'source': 'He and his books were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated and made national.', 'answer': 'he and his books'}
{'question': "Who could scarcely answer, ``I trust in you?''", 'source': "She could scarcely answer, ``I trust in you.''", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Had hazard brought women together?', 'source': 'Men and women danced together, women danced together, men danced together, as hazard had brought them together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who never missed a single day?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did he notice on the third day of her being there?', 'source': 'On the third day of her being there, he noticed her.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Who sends him my Soul with it?', 'source': "``I do so, father, and I send him my Soul with it!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he throw into a basket?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who were in frequent requisition as to property made national?', 'source': 'He and his books were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated and made national.', 'answer': 'he and his books'}
{'question': 'Who is Lucie?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who has seen it many times?', 'source': 'I have seen it many times.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What is my father?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': 'the place'}
{'question': 'Who saw her it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'her husband'}
{'question': 'Do off _ its _ head comes?', 'source': 'And off _ its _ head comes.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is nearly ended, my darling; I have encompassed him with every protection?', 'source': 'Your suspense is nearly ended, my darling; he shall be restored to you within a few hours; I have encompassed him with every protection.', 'answer': 'your suspense'}
{'question': 'Who were they dancing like?', 'source': 'There could not be fewer than five hundred people, and they were dancing like five thousand demons.', 'answer': 'like five thousand demons'}
{'question': 'What had she seen?', 'source': 'She had seen the houses, as she came along, decorated with little pikes, and with little red caps stuck upon them; also, with tricoloured ribbons; also, with the standard inscription (tricoloured letters were the favorite), Republic One and Indivisible.', 'answer': 'the houses'}
{'question': 'What did she and her child wear?', 'source': 'The plain dark dresses, akin to mourning dresses, which she and her child wore, were as neat and as well attended to as the brighter clothes of happy days.', 'answer': 'mourning dresses'}
{'question': 'Who turned resignedly away at four?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who had seen the houses?', 'source': 'She had seen the houses, as she came along, decorated with little pikes, and with little red caps stuck upon them; also, with tricoloured ribbons; also, with the standard inscription (tricoloured letters were the favorite), Republic One and Indivisible.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who came to tell you?', 'source': 'I left him climbing to the window, and I came to tell you.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did she turn resignedly away at?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': 'at four'}
{'question': 'What do I send him my Soul with?', 'source': "``I do so, father, and I send him my Soul with it!''", 'answer': 'with it'}
{'question': 'What did she hear?', 'source': 'But, he was not far off, for presently she heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along, which filled her with fear.', 'answer': 'a troubled movement and a shouting coming along'}
{'question': 'What must I see?', 'source': "I must see Lorry.''", 'answer': 'Lorry'}
{'question': 'What do I have?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': 'timely information'}
{'question': 'Who do I think of?', 'source': "But when I think of my husband, and the mercies of these people--''", 'answer': 'of my husband'}
{'question': 'What did she lose?', 'source': 'She lost her color, and the old and intent expression was a constant, not an occasional, thing; otherwise, she remained very pretty and comely.', 'answer': 'her color'}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was the dark and dirty corner of a small winding street.', 'answer': 'the dark and dirty corner of a small winding street'}
{'question': 'What did he accost she appeared?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': 'her the moment'}
{'question': 'What knew too well what it meant?', 'source': 'They both knew too well what it meant.', 'answer': 'they both'}
{'question': 'Who wore mourning dresses?', 'source': 'The plain dark dresses, akin to mourning dresses, which she and her child wore, were as neat and as well attended to as the brighter clothes of happy days.', 'answer': 'she and her child'}
{'question': 'Who is my father?', 'source': '``I am not frightened for myself, my father.', 'answer': 'myself'}
{'question': 'What did they fill?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': 'the place'}
{'question': 'What had brought them together?', 'source': 'Men and women danced together, women danced together, men danced together, as hazard had brought them together.', 'answer': 'hazard'}
{'question': 'What did he throw into his basket?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': 'two more billets'}
{'question': "What had she momentarily darkened with?''", 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': 'with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight'}
{'question': 'What were he and his books in?', 'source': 'He and his books were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated and made national.', 'answer': 'in frequent requisition as to property confiscated'}
{'question': 'What was Lucie?', 'source': "``No, father,'' said Lucie, yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand, ``no.''", 'answer': 'yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand'}
{'question': 'Who did her husband see it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Who did I come to tell?', 'source': 'I left him climbing to the window, and I came to tell you.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who always spoke to him first?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arise among them?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they dance to the popular Revolution song?', 'source': 'They danced to the popular Revolution song, keeping a ferocious time that was like a gnashing of teeth in unison.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Even if you could, what would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who knows that I can save him?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Will all the quietly loyal and good always be?', 'source': 'She was truest to them in the season of trial, as all the quietly loyal and good will always be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did not greatly alter in appearance?', 'source': 'She did not greatly alter in appearance.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who do I know that I can save?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What _ her _ head comes!', 'source': 'And off _ her _ head comes!', 'answer': 'off'}
{'question': 'What did he throw it into?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': 'into a basket'}
{'question': 'What did she not greatly alter in?', 'source': 'She did not greatly alter in appearance.', 'answer': 'in appearance'}
{'question': "Who said, ``But it's not my business''?", 'source': "``But it's not my business,'' said he.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What you to make?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': 'a sign of recognition'}
{'question': 'Did four go together?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who would burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance was on him at night on kissing her father?', 'source': 'Sometimes, at night on kissing her father, she would burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance, under Heaven, was on him.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What would he briskly fall to again?', 'source': 'he would generally say at those times, and would briskly fall to his sawing again.', 'answer': 'to his sawing'}
{'question': 'What was enough that he could?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did they keep a ferocious time that was like a gnashing of teeth in unison?', 'source': 'They danced to the popular Revolution song, keeping a ferocious time that was like a gnashing of teeth in unison.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did her husband see her it might be once in five or six times: might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did her husband see her it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What filled the place?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did her husband see her might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What is my love?', 'source': '``Give me your arm, my love.', 'answer': 'your arm'}
{'question': "Is yes's mother it not?", 'source': "Your mother, is it not, my little citizeness?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had that was well done; they left?', 'source': "That was well done;'' they had left the spot; ``it shall not be in vain.", 'answer': 'the spot; it shall not be in vain'}
{'question': 'What did she kiss?', 'source': "``No, father,'' said Lucie, yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand, ``no.''", 'answer': 'her hand'}
{'question': 'Who did she always speak to first?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'Did these occupations bring her round to the December month her father walked among the terrors with a steady head?', 'source': 'These occupations brought her round to the December month, wherein her father walked among the terrors with a steady head.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did her husband see her it might be once: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'in five or six times'}
{'question': 'Who has not received the notice yet?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who calls it my Little Guillotine?', 'source': 'I call it my Little Guillotine.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who was there?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Did she arrive at the usual corner on a lightly-snowing afternoon?', 'source': 'On a lightly-snowing afternoon she arrived at the usual corner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What has he not received yet?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': 'the notice'}
{'question': 'What is your arm?', 'source': '``Give me your arm, my love.', 'answer': 'my love'}
{'question': 'Who was this?', 'source': 'This was the Carmagnole.', 'answer': 'the Carmagnole'}
{'question': 'Was it the dark and dirty corner of a small winding street?', 'source': 'It was the dark and dirty corner of a small winding street.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will always be?', 'source': 'She was truest to them in the season of trial, as all the quietly loyal and good will always be.', 'answer': 'all the quietly loyal and good'}
{'question': 'What would harm you?', 'source': "Not one of them would harm you.''", 'answer': 'not one of them'}
{'question': 'Did she wait there two hours from that time in all weathers?', 'source': 'From that time, in all weathers, she waited there two hours.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she arrange as exactly as if her husband had been there?', 'source': 'As soon as they were established in their new residence, and her father had entered on the routine of his avocations, she arranged the little household as exactly as if her husband had been there.', 'answer': 'the little household'}
{'question': 'Who remained very pretty and comely?', 'source': 'She lost her color, and the old and intent expression was a constant, not an occasional, thing; otherwise, she remained very pretty and comely.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What had hazard brought together?', 'source': 'Men and women danced together, women danced together, men danced together, as hazard had brought them together.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Were they a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did he notice her?', 'source': 'On the third day of her being there, he noticed her.', 'answer': 'on the third day of her being there'}
{'question': 'Was Lucie never sure during all that time?', 'source': "During all that time Lucie was never sure, from hour to hour, but that the Guillotine would strike off her husband's head next day.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who always resolutely answered?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did it leave Lucie bewildered?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it a day of some wild rejoicing, and a festival?', 'source': 'It was a day of some wild rejoicing, and a festival.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is it not?', 'source': "Your mother, is it not, my little citizeness?''", 'answer': "yes's mother"}
{'question': 'Did it leave Lucie frightened?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say: ``Removed to the Conciergerie?''", 'source': "To whom did he appear to repeat her faltering words, when, raising his voice and turning his head towards the door of the room from which he had issued, he said: ``Removed to the Conciergerie, and summoned for to-morrow?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is your mother not?', 'source': "Your mother, is it not, my little citizeness?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was this mode of address now prescribed by decree?', 'source': 'This mode of address was now prescribed by decree.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is him?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'Did the billet fall as he threw it into a basket?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who taught?', 'source': 'Little Lucie she taught, as regularly, as if they had all been united in their English home.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who is myself?', 'source': '``I am not frightened for myself, my father.', 'answer': 'my father'}
{'question': "What's not my business?", 'source': "But it's not my business.", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the maidenly bosom bare to this?', 'source': "The maidenly bosom bared to this, the pretty almost-child's head thus distracted, the delicate foot mincing in this slough of blood and dirt, were types of the disjointed time.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is my work?', 'source': 'My work is my business.', 'answer': 'my business'}
{'question': 'When will I go there?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': 'every day'}
{'question': 'Did this leave Lucie bewildered?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is citizen?', 'source': "``You see me, citizen!''", 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Did this leave Lucie frightened?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she taken the white head to her fresh young bosom in the garret of Saint Antoine?', 'source': 'But, from the hour when she had taken the white head to her fresh young bosom in the garret of Saint Antoine, she had been true to her duties.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When do I know?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': 'that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie'}
{'question': 'Was it impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is me?', 'source': "``You see me, citizen!''", 'answer': 'citizen'}
{'question': 'Who will not be able to see him?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who is well prepared?', 'source': 'I am well prepared, but there are precautions to be taken, that could not be taken until he was actually summoned before the Tribunal.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Would Thenceforth generally say at those times?', 'source': 'he would generally say at those times, and would briskly fall to his sawing again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the Doctor turn her another way?', 'source': "``I must see Lorry,'' the Doctor repeated, turning her another way.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do O show me the place?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say: ``summoned for to-morrow?''", 'source': "To whom did he appear to repeat her faltering words, when, raising his voice and turning his head towards the door of the room from which he had issued, he said: ``Removed to the Conciergerie, and summoned for to-morrow?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he accost her the moment?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': 'she appeared'}
{'question': 'Was it almost dark when they arrived at the Bank?', 'source': 'It was almost dark when they arrived at the Bank.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will set him above their mercies very soon?', 'source': '``We will set him above their mercies very soon.', 'answer': 'we'}
{'question': 'Who will go there every day?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who is your suspense nearly ended, ?', 'source': 'Your suspense is nearly ended, my darling; he shall be restored to you within a few hours; I have encompassed him with every protection.', 'answer': 'my darling; he shall be restored to you within a few hours'}
{'question': 'Do I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could no fight have been half so terrible as this dance?', 'source': 'No fight could have been half so terrible as this dance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the billet fall as he spoke?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were such grace as was visible in it showing how warped and perverted all things good by nature become?', 'source': 'Such grace as was visible in it, made it the uglier, showing how warped and perverted all things good by nature were become.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he got somebody to scrawl it up for him?', 'source': 'He had got somebody to scrawl it up for him, however, who had squeezed Death in with most inappropriate difficulty.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What is yes's mother not?", 'source': "Your mother, is it not, my little citizeness?''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did they stop to dance about Lucie?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had this mode of address been established voluntarily some time ago?', 'source': 'It had been established voluntarily some time ago, among the more thorough patriots; but, was now law for everybody.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the hovel of a cutter of wood into lengths for burning, the only house at that end?', 'source': 'The hovel of a cutter of wood into lengths for burning, was the only house at that end; all else was wall.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What does it's not?", 'source': "But it's not my business.", 'answer': 'my business'}
{'question': 'May you kiss your hand towards that highest shelving roof?', 'source': "You may kiss your hand towards that highest shelving roof.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she and her child wear mourning dresses?', 'source': 'The plain dark dresses, akin to mourning dresses, which she and her child wore, were as neat and as well attended to as the brighter clothes of happy days.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is not afraid?', 'source': "You are not afraid?''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who stopped?', 'source': 'He stopped.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who was not far off?', 'source': 'But, he was not far off, for presently she heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along, which filled her with fear.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who will we set above their mercies very soon?', 'source': '``We will set him above their mercies very soon.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did he readily receive drink-money?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Was the pretty almost-child's head thus distracted the delicate foot mincing in this slough of blood and dirt?", 'source': "The maidenly bosom bared to this, the pretty almost-child's head thus distracted, the delicate foot mincing in this slough of blood and dirt, were types of the disjointed time.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were they dancing like five thousand demons?', 'source': 'There could not be fewer than five hundred people, and they were dancing like five thousand demons.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it been established voluntarily some time ago?', 'source': 'It had been established voluntarily some time ago, among the more thorough patriots; but, was now law for everybody.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was not there?', 'source': 'His shop was shut and he was not there, which was a relief to Lucie, and left her quite alone.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Was he actually summoned before the Tribunal?', 'source': 'I am well prepared, but there are precautions to be taken, that could not be taken until he was actually summoned before the Tribunal.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who thinks?', 'source': 'When he can get to it-- which depends on many uncertainties and incidents-- he might see you in the street, he thinks, if you stood in a certain place that I can show you.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What was it enough?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': 'that he could'}
{'question': 'Do I send him my Soul with it?', 'source': "``I do so, father, and I send him my Soul with it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she hear a troubled movement and a shouting coming along?', 'source': 'But, he was not far off, for presently she heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along, which filled her with fear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I call myself the Samson of the firewood guillotine?', 'source': '``I call myself the Samson of the firewood guillotine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he generally say at those times?', 'source': 'he would generally say at those times, and would briskly fall to his sawing again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stand before her when she lifted up the eyes?', 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were he and his books in frequent requisition as to property confiscated?', 'source': 'He and his books were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated and made national.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Lucie yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand?', 'source': "``No, father,'' said Lucie, yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand, ``no.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who went together?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Were he and his books in frequent requisition as to property made national?', 'source': 'He and his books were in frequent requisition as to property confiscated and made national.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must I see Lorry?', 'source': "I must see Lorry.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did a cutter of wood into lengths for burning say, ``But this mode of address's not my business''?", 'source': "``But it's not my business,'' said he.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I leave him climbing to the window?', 'source': 'I left him climbing to the window, and I came to tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I have timely information?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it see her when the chances served she would have waited out the day?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he accost her the moment she appeared?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will we set him above very soon?', 'source': '``We will set him above their mercies very soon.', 'answer': 'above their mercies'}
{'question': 'Was she alone at other times?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can nothing happen to him without my knowledge?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Even if you could, would it be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she never miss a single day?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was it not too wet or inclement for?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': 'for her child to be with her'}
{'question': 'Who does so?', 'source': "``I do so, father, and I send him my Soul with it!''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Had she seen the houses?', 'source': 'She had seen the houses, as she came along, decorated with little pikes, and with little red caps stuck upon them; also, with tricoloured ribbons; also, with the standard inscription (tricoloured letters were the favorite), Republic One and Indivisible.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had that was well done; they left the spot; it shall not be in vain?', 'source': "That was well done;'' they had left the spot; ``it shall not be in vain.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she been true to her duties?', 'source': 'But, from the hour when she had taken the white head to her fresh young bosom in the garret of Saint Antoine, she had been true to her duties.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she truest to them in the season of trial?', 'source': 'She was truest to them in the season of trial, as all the quietly loyal and good will always be.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could he save for the owners?', 'source': 'What he could save for the owners, he saved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I go there every day?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his shop shut?', 'source': 'His shop was shut and he was not there, which was a relief to Lucie, and left her quite alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was this the Carmagnole?', 'source': 'This was the Carmagnole.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they both know?', 'source': 'They both knew too well what it meant.', 'answer': 'too well what it meant'}
{'question': 'Did he notice her on the third day of her being there?', 'source': 'On the third day of her being there, he noticed her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had she momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight?''", 'source': "for he stood before her when she lifted up the eyes she had momentarily darkened with her hand; ``such a cruel, bad sight.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she turn resignedly away at four?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it impossible to be in his sight?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he throw two more billets into his basket?', 'source': 'Lucie shuddered as he threw two more billets into his basket, but it was impossible to be there while the wood-sawyer was at work, and not be in his sight.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do off _ her _ head comes!', 'source': 'And off _ her _ head comes!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What would she burst into at night on kissing her father?', 'source': 'Sometimes, at night on kissing her father, she would burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance, under Heaven, was on him.', 'answer': 'into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance was on him'}
{'question': 'Did they fill the place?', 'source': 'At first, they were a mere storm of coarse red caps and coarse woollen rags; but, as they filled the place, and stopped to dance about Lucie, some ghastly apparition of a dance-figure gone raving mad arose among them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she remain very pretty and comely?', 'source': 'She lost her color, and the old and intent expression was a constant, not an occasional, thing; otherwise, she remained very pretty and comely.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would he briskly fall to his sawing again?', 'source': 'he would generally say at those times, and would briskly fall to his sawing again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When did her husband see her?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': 'it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be'}
{'question': "Could she scarcely answer, ``I trust in you?''", 'source': "She could scarcely answer, ``I trust in you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she not greatly alter in appearance?', 'source': 'She did not greatly alter in appearance.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is the place my father?', 'source': "``O show me the place, my father, and I will go there every day.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they not made the round of their changed life many weeks:?', 'source': 'They had not made the round of their changed life many weeks, when her father said to her, on coming home one evening:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is him Lucie?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had hazard brought them together?', 'source': 'Men and women danced together, women danced together, men danced together, as hazard had brought them together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she lose her color?', 'source': 'She lost her color, and the old and intent expression was a constant, not an occasional, thing; otherwise, she remained very pretty and comely.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I well prepared?', 'source': 'I am well prepared, but there are precautions to be taken, that could not be taken until he was actually summoned before the Tribunal.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will we set him above their mercies very soon?', 'source': '``We will set him above their mercies very soon.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who came along?', 'source': 'She had seen the houses, as she came along, decorated with little pikes, and with little red caps stuck upon them; also, with tricoloured ribbons; also, with the standard inscription (tricoloured letters were the favorite), Republic One and Indivisible.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Do he always resolutely answered?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she teach?', 'source': 'Little Lucie she taught, as regularly, as if they had all been united in their English home.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know that I can save him?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did her husband see her it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be?', 'source': 'Her husband saw her (so she learned from her father) it might be once in five or six times: it might be twice or thrice running: it might be, not for a week or a fortnight together.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they both know too well what it meant?', 'source': 'They both knew too well what it meant.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she always give him drink-money?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I think of my husband?', 'source': "But when I think of my husband, and the mercies of these people--''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has he not received the notice yet?', 'source': 'He has not received the notice yet, but I know that he will presently be summoned for to-morrow, and removed to the Conciergerie; I have timely information.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she there?', 'source': 'As the clock struck two, she was there, and at four she turned resignedly away.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he looking out for her?', 'source': 'Next day he was looking out for her, and accosted her the moment she appeared.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will you not be able to see him?', 'source': "But you will not be able to see him, my poor child, and even if you could, it would be unsafe for you to make a sign of recognition.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they go together?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does his head come!', 'source': "And off his head comes!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he throw it into a basket?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he say, ``But it's not my business''?", 'source': "``But it's not my business,'' said he.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he save?', 'source': 'What he could save for the owners, he saved.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she kiss her hand?', 'source': "``No, father,'' said Lucie, yearning and weeping as she kissed her hand, ``no.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would not one of them harm you?', 'source': "Not one of them would harm you.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I come to tell you?', 'source': 'I left him climbing to the window, and I came to tell you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it with many?', 'source': "If the suddenness of her calamity, and the whirling wheels of the time, had stunned the Doctor's daughter into awaiting the result in idle despair, it would but have been with her as it was with many.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Would she burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance was on him at night on kissing her father?', 'source': 'Sometimes, at night on kissing her father, she would burst into the grief she had repressed all day, and would say that her sole reliance, under Heaven, was on him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your arm my love?', 'source': '``Give me your arm, my love.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is myself my father?', 'source': '``I am not frightened for myself, my father.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she arrange the little household as exactly as if her husband had been there?', 'source': 'As soon as they were established in their new residence, and her father had entered on the routine of his avocations, she arranged the little household as exactly as if her husband had been there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are you not afraid?', 'source': "You are not afraid?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she always speak to him first?', 'source': 'Thenceforth, to secure his good will, she always spoke to him first, and often gave him drink-money, which he readily received.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I do so?', 'source': "``I do so, father, and I send him my Soul with it!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her?', 'source': 'When it was not too wet or inclement for her child to be with her, they went together; at other times she was alone; but, she never missed a single day.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I call it my Little Guillotine?', 'source': 'I call it my Little Guillotine.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he not far off?', 'source': 'But, he was not far off, for presently she heard a troubled movement and a shouting coming along, which filled her with fear.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he stop?', 'source': 'He stopped.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I seen it many times?', 'source': 'I have seen it many times.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he not there?', 'source': 'His shop was shut and he was not there, which was a relief to Lucie, and left her quite alone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is me citizen?', 'source': "``You see me, citizen!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it enough that he could?', 'source': 'It was enough that he could and did see her when the chances served, and on that possibility she would have waited out the day, seven days a week.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it pass?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does he think?', 'source': 'When he can get to it-- which depends on many uncertainties and incidents-- he might see you in the street, he thinks, if you stood in a certain place that I can show you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he speak?', 'source': 'The billet fell as he spoke, and he threw it into a basket.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this pass?', 'source': "As it passed, leaving Lucie frightened and bewildered in the doorway of the wood-sawyer's house, the feathery snow fell as quietly and lay as white and soft, as if it had never been.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is my work my business?', 'source': 'My work is my business.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she come along?', 'source': 'She had seen the houses, as she came along, decorated with little pikes, and with little red caps stuck upon them; also, with tricoloured ribbons; also, with the standard inscription (tricoloured letters were the favorite), Republic One and Indivisible.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your mother it not?', 'source': "Your mother, is it not, my little citizeness?''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I know?', 'source': "He always resolutely answered: ``Nothing can happen to him without my knowledge, and I know that I can save him, Lucie.''", 'answer': 'that I can save him'}
{'question': "Does it's not my business?", 'source': "But it's not my business.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What did their ways arise out of?', 'source': 'The prisoners were far from insensible or unfeeling; their ways arose out of the condition of the time.', 'answer': 'of the condition of the time'}
{'question': 'Did the President desire to know?', 'source': 'the President desired to know.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was in a front row?', 'source': 'She was in a front row, by the side of a man whom he had never seen since his arrival at the Barrier, but whom he directly remembered as Defarge.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who had they reddened below the snow with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What put him into a great chair which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Did the populace cry enthusiastically, ``No!''", 'source': "The populace cried enthusiastically, ``No!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were knives some daggers?', 'source': 'Of the men, the greater part were armed in various ways; of the women, some wore knives, some daggers, some ate and drank as they looked on, many knitted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President remind him?', 'source': 'the President reminded him.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did they carry thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Was whatever personal hazard to the truth?', 'source': "He had come back, to save a citizen's life, and to bear his testimony, at whatever personal hazard, to the truth.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did his bloated gaoler glance over to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Were all the fifteen condemned?', 'source': 'All the fifteen were condemned, and the trials of the whole occupied an hour and a half.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'When was it read?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': 'at this stage of the proceedings'}
{'question': 'What did he hand in?', 'source': 'He handed in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette.', 'answer': 'in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette'}
{'question': 'When did their lists go forth?', 'source': 'Their lists went forth every evening, and were read out by the gaolers of the various prisons to their prisoners.', 'answer': 'every evening'}
{'question': 'Who did the first of them tell so?', 'source': "The first of them told him so, with the customary prison sign of Death-- a raised finger-- and they all added in words, ``Long live the Republic!''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What did the same cautious counsel direct?', 'source': 'The same cautious counsel directed every step that lay before him, and had prepared every inch of his road.', 'answer': 'every step that lay before him, and had prepared every inch of his road'}
{'question': 'When was it produced?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': 'at this stage of the proceedings'}
{'question': 'What had they reddened below the snow with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'Who did they put into a great chair which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who does all of us need circumstances to evoke?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'When was it not true that he had lived in England?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'many years'}
{'question': 'What did his bloated gaoler glance over to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': "Who laid her head upon her father's breast?", 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did they look at?', 'source': 'They seemed to be waiting for something with a dogged determination, and they looked at the Jury, but at nothing else.', 'answer': 'at the Jury'}
{'question': 'What did this answer have?', 'source': 'This answer had a happy effect upon the audience.', 'answer': 'a happy effect upon the audience'}
{'question': 'Who had the streets reddened below the snow with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What does all of us need circumstances to evoke?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What had the streets reddened below the snow with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What have all of us like wonders hidden in?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'in our breasts'}
{'question': 'Did President reply?', 'source': 'He had not returned sooner, he replied, simply because he had no means of living in France, save those he had resigned; whereas, in England, he lived by giving instruction in the French language and literature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was she in?', 'source': 'She was in a front row, by the side of a man whom he had never seen since his arrival at the Barrier, but whom he directly remembered as Defarge.', 'answer': 'in a front row'}
{'question': 'What needs circumstances to evoke them?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'all of us'}
{'question': 'What had they bound to the back of it?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': 'a pike with a red cap on its top'}
{'question': 'Had President come back?', 'source': "He had come back, to save a citizen's life, and to bear his testimony, at whatever personal hazard, to the truth.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had two already been guillotined?', 'source': 'There were twenty-three names, but only twenty were responded to; for one of the prisoners so summoned had died in gaol and been forgotten, and two had already been guillotined and forgotten.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the list read?', 'source': 'The list was read, in the vaulted chamber where Darnay had seen the associated prisoners on the night of his arrival.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had not assisted it by word or deed?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had they reddened them below with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'below the snow'}
{'question': 'Whose breast did she lay her head upon?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': "upon her father's breast"}
{'question': 'What was embracing whom they met?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who was embracing whom they met?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had not assisted it by word or deed?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Do enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had he married in?', 'source': 'But he had married in England?', 'answer': 'in England'}
{'question': 'Who had bound a pike with a red cap on its top to the back of it?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who is probable?', 'source': 'No man can decide now to which of these motives such extraordinary scenes were referable; it is probable, to a blending of all the three, with the second predominating.', 'answer': 'one of the prisoners so summoned had died in gaol and been forgotten'}
{'question': 'What reverently bowed their heads and hearts?', 'source': 'They all reverently bowed their heads and hearts.', 'answer': 'they all'}
{'question': 'Who had laid his poor head on her own breast?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'Who did the President remind?', 'source': 'the President reminded him.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'What have all of us like hidden in our breasts?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'like wonders'}
{'question': 'What had they reddened them below the snow with?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'with a deeper dye'}
{'question': 'What did the President ask the prisoner whether it was not true in?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'that he had lived many years in England'}
{'question': 'Had two already been forgotten?', 'source': 'There were twenty-three names, but only twenty were responded to; for one of the prisoners so summoned had died in gaol and been forgotten, and two had already been guillotined and forgotten.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did President not doubt?', 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had bound a pike with a red cap on its top to the back of it?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What did they carry him on in?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'in wild dreamlike procession'}
{'question': 'What had they bound a pike with a red cap on its top to?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': 'to the back of it'}
{'question': 'What does all of us need to evoke them?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': 'circumstances'}
{'question': 'Who stood upon his feet?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': 'her husband'}
{'question': 'What was it not true that he had lived many years in?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'in England'}
{'question': 'Who said to her?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who is your father?', 'source': '``And now speak to your father, dearest.', 'answer': 'dearest'}
{'question': 'What was it nothing since?', 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': 'that the decree bore date since his return to France'}
{'question': 'What had he seen pass away so?', 'source': 'Charles Evremonde, called Darnay, had reason to know the usage; he had seen hundreds pass away so.', 'answer': 'hundreds'}
{'question': "What did she lay upon her father's breast?", 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': 'her head'}
{'question': 'What had they not assisted by word or deed?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Was a name called?', 'source': 'When a name was called, its owner stepped apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it in seasons of pestilence?', 'source': 'In seasons of pestilence, some of us will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it.', 'answer': 'some of us'}
{'question': 'Who did he say to?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': 'to her'}
{'question': 'Did he hand in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette?', 'source': 'He handed in the names of two witnesses; Theophile Gabelle, and Alexandre Manette.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who looked on, many knitted?', 'source': 'Of the men, the greater part were armed in various ways; of the women, some wore knives, some daggers, some ate and drank as they looked on, many knitted.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': "Is now's father dearest?", 'source': '``And now speak to your father, dearest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did they all add in words ``Long live the Republic''?", 'source': "The first of them told him so, with the customary prison sign of Death-- a raised finger-- and they all added in words, ``Long live the Republic!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What looked on, many knitted?', 'source': 'Of the men, the greater part were armed in various ways; of the women, some wore knives, some daggers, some ate and drank as they looked on, many knitted.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'When will some of us have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it?', 'source': 'In seasons of pestilence, some of us will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it.', 'answer': 'in seasons of pestilence'}
{'question': 'What did he have?', 'source': 'He had not returned sooner, he replied, simply because he had no means of living in France, save those he had resigned; whereas, in England, he lived by giving instruction in the French language and literature.', 'answer': 'no means of living in France'}
{'question': 'Who has prayed to Him?', 'source': "``O dearest Charles, let me thank God for this on my knees as I have prayed to Him.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he leave?', 'source': 'So quick was the Tribunal to compensate itself and the nation for a chance lost, that these five came down to him before he left the place, condemned to die within twenty-four hours.', 'answer': 'the place'}
{'question': 'What did she lay her head upon?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': "upon her father's breast"}
{'question': 'What was it?', 'source': 'It was the incident of every day, and the society of La Force were engaged in the preparation of some games of forfeits and a little concert, for that evening.', 'answer': 'the incident of every day'}
{'question': 'What told him so?', 'source': "The first of them told him so, with the customary prison sign of Death-- a raised finger-- and they all added in words, ``Long live the Republic!''", 'answer': 'the first of them'}
{'question': 'What did they all reverently bow?', 'source': 'They all reverently bowed their heads and hearts.', 'answer': 'their heads and hearts'}
{'question': 'Who was pointing him out?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was the parting soon over?', 'source': 'There were hurried words of farewell and kindness, but the parting was soon over.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did she drop?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': 'insensible in his arms'}
{'question': 'Was it nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France?', 'source': 'It was nothing that the decree bore date since his return to France.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were five to be tried together?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who left the place?', 'source': 'So quick was the Tribunal to compensate itself and the nation for a chance lost, that these five came down to him before he left the place, condemned to die within twenty-four hours.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Had the citizen's letter been taken from him at the Barrier?", 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was pointing him out?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Who has saved him?', 'source': "I have saved him.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did her husband stand upon?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': 'upon his feet'}
{'question': 'What might he have thought?', 'source': 'Looking at the Jury and the turbulent audience, he might have thought that the usual order of things was reversed, and that the felons were trying the honest men.', 'answer': 'that the usual order of things was reversed'}
{'question': 'What had she laid on her own breast?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': 'his poor head'}
{'question': 'Who was again in his arms?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What had she laid his poor head on?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': 'on her own breast'}
{'question': 'Who was they pointing out?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who have I prayed to?', 'source': "``O dearest Charles, let me thank God for this on my knees as I have prayed to Him.''", 'answer': 'to Him'}
{'question': 'Did his judges sit upon the Bench in feathered hats?', 'source': 'His judges sat upon the Bench in feathered hats; but the rough red cap and tricoloured cockade was the head-dress otherwise prevailing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who held her to his heart?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Did the President require the name of that citizen?', 'source': 'The President required the name of that citizen.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did its owner step apart into?', 'source': 'When a name was called, its owner stepped apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded.', 'answer': 'into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded'}
{'question': 'Who could no other man in all this France have done for?', 'source': "No other man in all this France could have done what he has done for me.''", 'answer': 'what he has done for me'}
{'question': 'Can no man decide now to which of these motives such extraordinary scenes were referable?', 'source': 'No man can decide now to which of these motives such extraordinary scenes were referable; it is probable, to a blending of all the three, with the second predominating.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was Citizen Gabelle called to confirm it?', 'source': 'Citizen Gabelle was called to confirm it, and did so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who have I saved?', 'source': "I have saved him.''", 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Did the Tribunal wear their usual clothes?', 'source': 'As well as the prisoner could see, he and Mr. Lorry were the only men there, unconnected with the Tribunal, who wore their usual clothes, and had not assumed the coarse garb of the Carmagnole.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his bloated gaoler wear spectacles to read with?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President ring his bell to silence those cries?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might he have thought that the usual order of things was reversed?', 'source': 'Looking at the Jury and the turbulent audience, he might have thought that the usual order of things was reversed, and that the felons were trying the honest men.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had Charles Darnay set Doctor Manette's foot according to Doctor Manette's reiterated instructions on these few steps of his dangerous way?", 'source': "On these few steps of his dangerous way, Charles Darnay had set his foot according to Doctor Manette's reiterated instructions.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the night in its vermin-haunted cells long and cold?', 'source': 'The passage to the Conciergerie was short and dark; the night in its vermin-haunted cells was long and cold.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who until left off?', 'source': 'until they left off, of their own will.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Did this answer have a happy effect upon the audience?', 'source': 'This answer had a happy effect upon the audience.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did he hold to his heart?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'What had they not assisted it by?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': 'by word or deed'}
{'question': 'Did they seem to be waiting for something with a dogged determination?', 'source': 'They seemed to be waiting for something with a dogged determination, and they looked at the Jury, but at nothing else.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Might he have thought that the felons were trying the honest men?', 'source': 'Looking at the Jury and the turbulent audience, he might have thought that the usual order of things was reversed, and that the felons were trying the honest men.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they thrown a red flag over the chair?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were he and Mr. Lorry the only men there?', 'source': 'As well as the prisoner could see, he and Mr. Lorry were the only men there, unconnected with the Tribunal, who wore their usual clothes, and had not assumed the coarse garb of the Carmagnole.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What had the Doctor taken care?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': 'that it should be there'}
{'question': 'Did the President ask the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Could no other man in all this France have done what he has done for me?', 'source': "No other man in all this France could have done what he has done for me.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did its owner step apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded?', 'source': 'When a name was called, its owner stepped apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Had Charles Darnay set his foot according to Doctor Manette's reiterated instructions on these few steps of his dangerous way?", 'source': "On these few steps of his dangerous way, Charles Darnay had set his foot according to Doctor Manette's reiterated instructions.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his removal rescue him from these caresses for the moment?', 'source': 'His removal, to make way for other accused persons who were to be tried, rescued him from these caresses for the moment.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he been taken in France?', 'source': 'There he was, and there was the decree; he had been taken in France, and his head was demanded.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was she again in?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': 'in his arms'}
{'question': 'Did the accuse explained that the citizen was his first witness?', 'source': 'The accused explained that the citizen was his first witness.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he hold her to?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': 'to his heart'}
{'question': 'Did their ways arise out of the condition of the time?', 'source': 'The prisoners were far from insensible or unfeeling; their ways arose out of the condition of the time.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will some of us have a secret attraction to in seasons of pestilence?', 'source': 'In seasons of pestilence, some of us will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it.', 'answer': 'to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it'}
{'question': 'Did they redden the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President ring his bell to quiet that?', 'source': 'and the President rang his bell to quiet them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the French citizen represent that his life was endangered by his absence?', 'source': 'He had returned when he did, on the pressing and written entreaty of a French citizen, who represented that his life was endangered by his absence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who hoped?', 'source': 'Not an emigrant, he hoped, within the sense and spirit of the law.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Will some of us have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it in seasons of pestilence?', 'source': 'In seasons of pestilence, some of us will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President declare him free?', 'source': "All the voices were in the prisoner's favor, and the President declared him free.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What will some of us have to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it in seasons of pestilence?', 'source': 'In seasons of pestilence, some of us will have a secret attraction to the disease-- a terrible passing inclination to die of it.', 'answer': 'a secret attraction'}
{'question': 'Did they put him into a great chair they had among them?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it read at this stage of the proceedings?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it produced at this stage of the proceedings?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he make a similar short pause at each name?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had every one of those perished in the massacre?', 'source': 'Every one of those had perished in the massacre; every human creature he had since cared for and parted with, had died on the scaffold.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they look at the Jury?', 'source': 'They seemed to be waiting for something with a dogged determination, and they looked at the Jury, but at nothing else.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where did the President ask the prisoner?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England'}
{'question': 'Was care read at this stage of the proceedings?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was they embracing?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': 'whom they met'}
{'question': 'Was care produced at this stage of the proceedings?', 'source': 'The Doctor had taken care that it should be there-- had assured him that it would be there-- and at this stage of the proceedings it was produced and read.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he also refer with confidence to the citizen's letter?", 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where was it not true?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'that he had lived many years in England'}
{'question': 'What did his bloated gaoler glance over them to assure himself through?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': 'that he had taken his place, and went through the list'}
{'question': 'Did he have no means of living in France?', 'source': 'He had not returned sooner, he replied, simply because he had no means of living in France, save those he had resigned; whereas, in England, he lived by giving instruction in the French language and literature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he live by giving instruction in the French language and literature in England?', 'source': 'He had not returned sooner, he replied, simply because he had no means of living in France, save those he had resigned; whereas, in England, he lived by giving instruction in the French language and literature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who must not be weak?', 'source': "``You must not be weak, my darling,'' he remonstrated; ``do not tremble so.", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Was she in a front row?', 'source': 'She was in a front row, by the side of a man whom he had never seen since his arrival at the Barrier, but whom he directly remembered as Defarge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it the incident of every day?', 'source': 'It was the incident of every day, and the society of La Force were engaged in the preparation of some games of forfeits and a little concert, for that evening.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he married in England?', 'source': 'But he had married in England?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did a name's owner step apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded?", 'source': 'When a name was called, its owner stepped apart into a spot reserved for those who were announced as being thus fatally recorded.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his bloated gaoler glance over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list?', 'source': 'His bloated gaoler, who wore spectacles to read with, glanced over them to assure himself that he had taken his place, and went through the list, making a similar short pause at each name.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they carry him on in wild dreamlike procession?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What is probable?', 'source': 'No man can decide now to which of these motives such extraordinary scenes were referable; it is probable, to a blending of all the three, with the second predominating.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did they carry him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the President ring his bell to quiet them?', 'source': 'and the President rang his bell to quiet them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who is safe?', 'source': "I am safe.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Did their lists go forth every evening?', 'source': 'Their lists went forth every evening, and were read out by the gaolers of the various prisons to their prisoners.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they put him into a great chair which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who worked?', 'source': 'Among these last, was one, with a spare piece of knitting under her arm as she worked.', 'answer': 'she'}
{'question': 'What did they carry him thus into?', 'source': 'Reddening the snowy streets with the prevailing Republican color, in winding and tramping through them, as they had reddened them below the snow with a deeper dye, they carried him thus into the courtyard of the building where he lived.', 'answer': 'into the courtyard of the building where he lived'}
{'question': 'Were their lists read out by the gaolers of the various prisons to their prisoners?', 'source': 'Their lists went forth every evening, and were read out by the gaolers of the various prisons to their prisoners.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he seen hundreds pass away so?', 'source': 'Charles Evremonde, called Darnay, had reason to know the usage; he had seen hundreds pass away so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is your father dearest?', 'source': '``And now speak to your father, dearest.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did she lay her head upon her father's breast?", 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did the President ask the prisoner in?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England'}
{'question': 'Did they look on, many knitted?', 'source': 'Of the men, the greater part were armed in various ways; of the women, some wore knives, some daggers, some ate and drank as they looked on, many knitted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What was it not true in?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': 'that he had lived many years in England'}
{'question': 'Had he returned when he did?', 'source': 'He had returned when he did, on the pressing and written entreaty of a French citizen, who represented that his life was endangered by his absence.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they bound a pike with a red cap on its top to the back of it?', 'source': 'Over the chair they had thrown a red flag, and to the back of it they had bound a pike with a red cap on its top.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she drop insensible in his arms?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did until they leave off?', 'source': 'until they left off, of their own will.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had her father gone on before?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'source': 'The President rang his bell to silence those cries, and asked the prisoner whether it was not true that he had lived many years in England?', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had she laid his poor head on her own breast?', 'source': "She laid her head upon her father's breast, as she had laid his poor head on her own breast, long, long ago.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he turn?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': 'her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd'}
{'question': 'Was his head demanded?', 'source': 'There he was, and there was the decree; he had been taken in France, and his head was demanded.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he leave the place?', 'source': 'So quick was the Tribunal to compensate itself and the nation for a chance lost, that these five came down to him before he left the place, condemned to die within twenty-four hours.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they all reverently bow their heads and hearts?', 'source': 'They all reverently bowed their heads and hearts.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have all of us like wonders hidden in our breasts?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the first of them tell him so?', 'source': "The first of them told him so, with the customary prison sign of Death-- a raised finger-- and they all added in words, ``Long live the Republic!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he turn her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Does all of us need circumstances to evoke them?', 'source': 'And all of us have like wonders hidden in our breasts, only needing circumstances to evoke them.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did until that leave off?', 'source': 'until they left off, of their own will.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was they embracing whom they met?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did not?', 'source': "Which it did not, for they continued to cry ``No!''", 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did he say to her?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did they put him into a great chair among?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': 'they had among them'}
{'question': 'Was so quick the Tribunal to compensate itself and the nation for a chance lost, that these five came down to him before he left the place?', 'source': 'So quick was the Tribunal to compensate itself and the nation for a chance lost, that these five came down to him before he left the place, condemned to die within twenty-four hours.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they put him into a great chair among?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': 'they had among them'}
{'question': 'Did her husband stand upon his feet?', 'source': 'Her father had gone on before, to prepare her, and when her husband stood upon his feet, she dropped insensible in his arms.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had they not assisted it by word or deed?', 'source': 'Five were to be tried together, next, as enemies of the Republic, forasmuch as they had not assisted it by word or deed.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he reply?', 'source': 'He had not returned sooner, he replied, simply because he had no means of living in France, save those he had resigned; whereas, in England, he lived by giving instruction in the French language and literature.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hope?', 'source': 'Not an emigrant, he hoped, within the sense and spirit of the law.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he come back?', 'source': "He had come back, to save a citizen's life, and to bear his testimony, at whatever personal hazard, to the truth.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Am I safe?', 'source': "I am safe.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must you not be weak?', 'source': "``You must not be weak, my darling,'' he remonstrated; ``do not tremble so.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hold her to his heart?', 'source': 'As he held her to his heart and turned her beautiful head between his face and the brawling crowd, so that his tears and her lips might come together unseen, a few of the people fell to dancing.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is it probable?', 'source': 'No man can decide now to which of these motives such extraordinary scenes were referable; it is probable, to a blending of all the three, with the second predominating.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I prayed to Him?', 'source': "``O dearest Charles, let me thank God for this on my knees as I have prayed to Him.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was they pointing him out?', 'source': 'In wild dreamlike procession, embracing whom they met and pointing him out, they carried him on.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he not doubt?', 'source': "He also referred with confidence to the citizen's letter, which had been taken from him at the Barrier, but which he did not doubt would be found among the papers then before the President.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they put him into a great chair of?', 'source': 'They put him into a great chair they had among them, and which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages.', 'answer': 'which they had taken either out of the Court itself, or one of its rooms or passages'}
{'question': 'Have I saved him?', 'source': "I have saved him.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was she again in his arms?', 'source': 'When she was again in his arms, he said to her:', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did she work?', 'source': 'Among these last, was one, with a spare piece of knitting under her arm as she worked.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it do not?', 'source': "Which it did not, for they continued to cry ``No!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it?', 'source': 'Undoubtedly it was.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What were hatchets all red with?', 'source': 'Hatchets, knives, bayonets, swords, all brought to be sharpened, were all red with it.', 'answer': 'with it'}
{'question': 'What do I say is the hardest thing to do of all?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'this'}
{'question': 'What do I say this is the hardest thing to do of?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'of all'}
{'question': 'Do the Doctor know you are true?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were hatchets knives?', 'source': 'Hatchets, knives, bayonets, swords, all brought to be sharpened, were all red with it.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the people in possession of the house let there in at the gate?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did a thousand answering close the window and the curtain?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who says this is the hardest thing to do of all?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'When did it never occur to him to be surprised by their appearance as the night knew?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': 'until a long time afterwards'}
{'question': 'What must you let me put you in a room at here?', 'source': 'You must let me put you in a room at the back here.', 'answer': 'at the back'}
{'question': 'Who are for your life?', 'source': "Manette, for your life, do not touch the blind!''", 'answer': 'manette'}
{'question': 'Was Lucie affrighted?', 'source': 'cried Lucie, affrighted.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did they draw back from?', 'source': "They drew back from the window, and the Doctor looked for explanation in his friend's ashy face.", 'answer': 'from the window'}
{'question': 'What must you let me put you in at the back here?', 'source': 'You must let me put you in a room at the back here.', 'answer': 'in a room'}
{'question': "Who do the Doctor see in there's face that you know can do nothing else than this?", 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did it chance from?', 'source': 'It chanced that they derived a kind of security from the patriotic occupation of the main building, but the true-hearted old gentleman never calculated about that.', 'answer': 'that they derived a kind of security from the patriotic occupation of the main building'}
{'question': 'Who had rushed in to work at the grindstone?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'When was all this seen?', 'source': 'All this was seen in a moment, as the vision of a drowning man, or of any human creature at any very great pass, could see a world if it were there.', 'answer': 'in a moment'}
{'question': 'What had her head gradually fallen on beside her pretty charge?', 'source': 'Miss Pross had laid the child down on his own bed, and her head had gradually fallen on the pillow beside her pretty charge.', 'answer': 'on the pillow'}
{'question': 'What had they rushed in to work at?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'at the grindstone'}
{'question': 'Who made a flight from the troubles?', 'source': "The house belonged to a great nobleman who had lived in it until he made a flight from the troubles, in his own cook's dress, and got across the borders.", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'If the Doctor are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who do you think to?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you have make hatchets known to these devils, and get taken to La Force'}
{'question': 'Who drew back from the window?', 'source': "They drew back from the window, and the Doctor looked for explanation in his friend's ashy face.", 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'What had rushed in to work at the grindstone?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'they'}
{'question': 'Was the irruption repeated?', 'source': 'Twice more in the darkness the bell at the great gate sounded, and the irruption was repeated, and the grindstone whirled and spluttered.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who descried in the imperfect light one of the carriages of Monseigneur staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions?', 'source': 'Shortly, this worn-out murderer descried in the imperfect light one of the carriages of Monseigneur, and, staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions.', 'answer': 'this worn-out murderer'}
{'question': 'Did May hear the gate clash again?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who was stopped at the barrier?', 'source': "An errand of generosity brought him here unknown to us; he was stopped at the barrier, and sent to prison.''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did he tell that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Do the look fixed upon May?', 'source': 'With the look fixed upon him, in her paleness and wildness, she panted out in his arms, imploringly, ``O my dear friend!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did this draw back from?', 'source': "They drew back from the window, and the Doctor looked for explanation in his friend's ashy face.", 'answer': 'from the window'}
{'question': "Is armoury a thousand answering's love?", 'source': "``The place is national property now, and used as a kind of armoury, my love.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can the Doctor not possibly stir out?', 'source': 'There is no help for you in any action on your part to-night; you cannot possibly stir out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'than this'}
{'question': 'Who sees in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What do May He have!', 'source': "May He have mercy on all who are in danger!''", 'answer': 'mercy on all who are in danger'}
{'question': 'Who must you let put you in a room at the back here?', 'source': 'You must let me put you in a room at the back here.', 'answer': 'me'}
{'question': 'Who must you let me put in a room at the back here?', 'source': 'You must let me put you in a room at the back here.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who had the people in possession of the house let in at the gate?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'What was he stopped at?', 'source': "An errand of generosity brought him here unknown to us; he was stopped at the barrier, and sent to prison.''", 'answer': 'at the barrier'}
{'question': 'Must the Doctor not delay?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did I tell so?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'Lucie'}
{'question': 'What had the people in possession of the house let in at the gate?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'them'}
{'question': 'When did his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, carry him to the heart of the concourse at the stone?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': 'in an instant'}
{'question': 'What brought him here unknown to us?', 'source': "An errand of generosity brought him here unknown to us; he was stopped at the barrier, and sent to prison.''", 'answer': 'an errand of generosity'}
{'question': 'Who was the man so besmeared that he might have been?', 'source': 'A man, so besmeared that he might have been a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain, was rising from the pavement by the side of the grindstone, and looking about him with a vacant air.', 'answer': 'a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain'}
{'question': 'What did he shiver through?', 'source': 'He had opened, not only the glass window, but the lattice blind outside it, and he had closed both again, and he shivered through his frame.', 'answer': 'through his frame'}
{'question': 'Who do the Doctor know are true?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who has been a Bastille prisoner?', 'source': 'I have been a Bastille prisoner.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What was he still to be seen on the ceiling at?', 'source': "Tellson's had whitewashed the Cupid, but he was still to be seen on the ceiling, in the coolest linen, aiming (as he very often does) at money from morning to night.", 'answer': 'at money from morning to night'}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor say this is?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'the hardest thing to do of all'}
{'question': 'Who do I see in your face that you know can do nothing else than this?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What look fixed upon him?', 'source': 'With the look fixed upon him, in her paleness and wildness, she panted out in his arms, imploringly, ``O my dear friend!', 'answer': 'the'}
{'question': "Who thought, ``They have come back''?", 'source': "Soon afterwards, the bell at the great gate sounded, and he thought, ``They have come back!''", 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'What is my love?', 'source': "``The place is national property now, and used as a kind of armoury, my love.''", 'answer': 'armoury'}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor see in that you know I can do nothing else than this?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': "in there's face"}
{'question': 'Was Mr. Lorry looking out of window at these harmless objects?', 'source': 'Rising and looking out of window at these harmless objects, Mr. Lorry shivered, and retired to his seat by the fire.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'no suspicion even of his being'}
{'question': 'What did he close?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': 'the window and the curtain'}
{'question': 'Does a thousand answering shout?', 'source': 'and a thousand answering shouts.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards as the night knew?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'What did this worn-out murderer descry in one of the carriages of Monseigneur staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions?', 'source': 'Shortly, this worn-out murderer descried in the imperfect light one of the carriages of Monseigneur, and, staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions.', 'answer': 'in the imperfect light'}
{'question': 'Who have I been?', 'source': 'I have been a Bastille prisoner.', 'answer': 'a Bastille prisoner'}
{'question': 'If the Doctor are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who thinks you have make hatchets known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who did it never occur to to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards as the night knew?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': 'to him'}
{'question': 'What had evidently been set up there for their purpose?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Did the nervousness and dread that were upon him inspire that vague uneasiness respecting the Bank roused?', 'source': 'The nervousness and dread that were upon him inspired that vague uneasiness respecting the Bank, which a great change would naturally awaken, with such feelings roused.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who knows you are true?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'What did he make?', 'source': "The house belonged to a great nobleman who had lived in it until he made a flight from the troubles, in his own cook's dress, and got across the borders.", 'answer': 'a flight from the troubles'}
{'question': 'What did his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, carry him in an instant to at the stone?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': 'to the heart of the concourse'}
{'question': 'What carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': 'his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner,'}
{'question': 'Who knew it would be so?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': "Would a place of business in London like Tellson's place of business in Paris, soon have driven the House out of its mind and into the Gazette?", 'source': "A place of business in London like Tellson's place of business in Paris, would soon have driven the House out of its mind and into the Gazette.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I say this is?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'the hardest thing to do of all'}
{'question': 'What do I see in that you know I can do nothing else than this?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'in your face'}
{'question': 'Who got his arm round her?', 'source': 'He got his arm round her, and held her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who heard the gate clash again?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'Who did he find with her?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': 'her child and Miss Pross'}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'no suspicion even of his being'}
{'question': 'What was his hand again upon?', 'source': 'His hand was again upon the window.', 'answer': 'upon the window'}
{'question': 'When must you leave your father and me alone?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': 'for two minutes'}
{'question': 'Did cautiously look out again?', 'source': 'Soon afterwards the day began to dawn, and he softly detached himself from the clasping hand, and cautiously looked out again.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had May expected?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who thinks you have make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What do my dear friend I have?', 'source': '``My dear friend, I have a charmed life in this city.', 'answer': 'a charmed life in this city'}
{'question': 'What did it never occur to him to be surprised by until a long time afterwards as the night knew?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': 'by their appearance'}
{'question': 'If the Doctor are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who do you think have make hatchets known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Who did he hold?', 'source': 'He got his arm round her, and held her.', 'answer': 'her'}
{'question': 'Who must leave your father and me alone for two minutes?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'Did the night know?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had Miss Pross laid the child down on his own bed?', 'source': 'Miss Pross had laid the child down on his own bed, and her head had gradually fallen on the pillow beside her pretty charge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do May He have mercy on all who are in danger!', 'source': "May He have mercy on all who are in danger!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who do I know are true?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What had it evidently been set up there for?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': 'for their purpose'}
{'question': 'What did he hear again?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': 'the gate clash'}
{'question': 'Where do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'What did his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, carry him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': 'at the stone'}
{'question': 'Who do the look fixed upon?', 'source': 'With the look fixed upon him, in her paleness and wildness, she panted out in his arms, imploringly, ``O my dear friend!', 'answer': 'upon him'}
{'question': 'Who will be submissive to you?', 'source': '``I will be submissive to you.', 'answer': 'the Doctor'}
{'question': 'What did the Doctor know of?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'I could help Charles out of all danger'}
{'question': 'Who held her?', 'source': 'He got his arm round her, and held her.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who do you think have make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you'}
{'question': 'What did he get up to go among?', 'source': 'It was well guarded, and he got up to go among the trusty people who were watching it, when his door suddenly opened, and two figures rushed in, at sight of which he fell back in amazement.', 'answer': 'among the trusty people who were watching it'}
{'question': 'Did Doctor Manette press his hand?', 'source': 'Doctor Manette pressed his hand, hastened bareheaded out of the room, and was in the courtyard when Mr. Lorry regained the blind.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Where do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles;?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'What did I know would be so?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Who solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'the Doctor'}
{'question': 'What must you instantly be?', 'source': 'You must instantly be obedient, still, and quiet.', 'answer': 'obedient, still, and quiet'}
{'question': 'Was all quiet?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were such things?', 'source': 'Yet such things were.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who did his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, carry in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': 'him'}
{'question': 'Who will the Doctor be submissive to?', 'source': '``I will be submissive to you.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'of no harm'}
{'question': "What do the Doctor see in there's face that you know than?", 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'I can do nothing else than this'}
{'question': 'Who do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'to Charles'}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor know?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': 'you are true'}
{'question': 'Did it chance that they derived a kind of security from the patriotic occupation of the main building?', 'source': 'It chanced that they derived a kind of security from the patriotic occupation of the main building, but the true-hearted old gentleman never calculated about that.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was a man looking about him with a vacant air?', 'source': 'A man, so besmeared that he might have been a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain, was rising from the pavement by the side of the grindstone, and looking about him with a vacant air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who solemnly swears to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'I'}
{'question': 'Who do the Doctor solemnly swear to that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you that I know of having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'of no harm'}
{'question': 'Did he occupy rooms in the Bank?', 'source': 'He occupied rooms in the Bank, in his fidelity to the House of which he had grown to be a part, like strong root-ivy.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'What did I know of?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'I could help Charles out of all danger'}
{'question': 'Who do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'to Charles'}
{'question': 'Did I know I could help Charles out of all danger?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he close the lattice again with a fluttering heart?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Do the Doctor's dear friend I have a charmed life in this city?", 'source': '``My dear friend, I have a charmed life in this city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; in?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'Did this worn-out murderer descry in the imperfect light one of the carriages of Monseigneur staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions?', 'source': 'Shortly, this worn-out murderer descried in the imperfect light one of the carriages of Monseigneur, and, staggering to that gorgeous vehicle, climbed in at the door, and shut himself up to take his rest on its dainty cushions.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'of his being'}
{'question': 'What was well guarded?', 'source': 'It was well guarded, and he got up to go among the trusty people who were watching it, when his door suddenly opened, and two figures rushed in, at sight of which he fell back in amazement.', 'answer': 'it'}
{'question': 'Where do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles;?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'Were some of the hacked swords tied to the wrists of those who carried them of the one color?', 'source': 'Some of the hacked swords were tied to the wrists of those who carried them, with strips of linen and fragments of dress: ligatures various in kind, but all deep of the one color.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor solemnly swear to you of?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'Who do I solemnly swear to that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Had they rushed in to work at the grindstone?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Were their hideous countenances all bloody and sweaty?', 'source': 'False eyebrows and false moustaches were stuck upon them, and their hideous countenances were all bloody and sweaty, and all awry with howling, and all staring and glaring with beastly excitement and want of sleep.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power who do you think to?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': 'you have make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force'}
{'question': 'Who must you leave alone for two minutes?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': 'your father and me'}
{'question': 'Were all such circumstances indifferent to him?', 'source': 'All such circumstances were indifferent to him, so that he did his duty.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did they draw back from the window?', 'source': "They drew back from the window, and the Doctor looked for explanation in his friend's ashy face.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he find her child and Miss Pross with her?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who will I be submissive to?', 'source': '``I will be submissive to you.', 'answer': 'to you'}
{'question': 'Did I tell Lucie so?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did the house belong to a great nobleman who had lived in it until he made a flight from the troubles, and got across the borders?', 'source': "The house belonged to a great nobleman who had lived in it until he made a flight from the troubles, in his own cook's dress, and got across the borders.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did Mr. Lorry clasp his hands, ``that no one near and dear to me is in this dreadful town to-night''?", 'source': "``Thank God,'' said Mr. Lorry, clasping his hands, ``that no one near and dear to me is in this dreadful town to-night.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the Doctor say this is the hardest thing to do of all?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was he still to be seen on the ceiling at money from morning to night?', 'source': "Tellson's had whitewashed the Cupid, but he was still to be seen on the ceiling, in the coolest linen, aiming (as he very often does) at money from morning to night.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'of his being'}
{'question': 'Did he make a flight from the troubles?', 'source': "The house belonged to a great nobleman who had lived in it until he made a flight from the troubles, in his own cook's dress, and got across the borders.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did this draw back from the window?', 'source': "They drew back from the window, and the Doctor looked for explanation in his friend's ashy face.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was all this seen in a moment?', 'source': 'All this was seen in a moment, as the vision of a drowning man, or of any human creature at any very great pass, could see a world if it were there.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I know?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': 'you are true'}
{'question': 'Was he stopped at the barrier?', 'source': "An errand of generosity brought him here unknown to us; he was stopped at the barrier, and sent to prison.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Are manette for your life?', 'source': "Manette, for your life, do not touch the blind!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he close the window and the curtain?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he get up to go among the trusty people who were watching it?', 'source': 'It was well guarded, and he got up to go among the trusty people who were watching it, when his door suddenly opened, and two figures rushed in, at sight of which he fell back in amazement.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had the people in possession of the house let them in at the gate?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he tell her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did he tell her by?', 'source': 'He closed the lattice again with a fluttering heart, closed the window and the curtain, hastened to Lucie, and told her that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband.', 'answer': 'that her father was assisted by the people, and gone in search of her husband'}
{'question': 'Do I say this is the hardest thing to do of all?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Have I been a Bastille prisoner?', 'source': 'I have been a Bastille prisoner.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Who had expected?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': 'he'}
{'question': "Do the Doctor see in there's face that you know I can do nothing else than this?", 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Is armoury my love?', 'source': "``The place is national property now, and used as a kind of armoury, my love.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had her head gradually fallen on the pillow beside her pretty charge?', 'source': 'Miss Pross had laid the child down on his own bed, and her head had gradually fallen on the pillow beside her pretty charge.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was the man so besmeared that he might have been a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain?', 'source': 'A man, so besmeared that he might have been a sorely wounded soldier creeping back to consciousness on a field of slain, was rising from the pavement by the side of the grindstone, and looking about him with a vacant air.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must you let me put you in a room at the back here?', 'source': 'You must let me put you in a room at the back here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What did I know?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': 'it would be so'}
{'question': 'Did an errand of generosity bring him here unknown to us?', 'source': "An errand of generosity brought him here unknown to us; he was stopped at the barrier, and sent to prison.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I see in your face that you know than?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'I can do nothing else than this'}
{'question': 'What do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; in?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'Did he shiver through his frame?', 'source': 'He had opened, not only the glass window, but the lattice blind outside it, and he had closed both again, and he shivered through his frame.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must you instantly be obedient, still, and quiet?', 'source': 'You must instantly be obedient, still, and quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do my dear friend I have a charmed life in this city?', 'source': '``My dear friend, I have a charmed life in this city.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I say?', 'source': "I say this, because what I must bid you to do for Charles's sake, is the hardest thing to do of all.", 'answer': 'this is the hardest thing to do of all'}
{'question': 'Did he hear the gate clash again?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the look fixed upon him?', 'source': 'With the look fixed upon him, in her paleness and wildness, she panted out in his arms, imploringly, ``O my dear friend!', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was his hand again upon the window?', 'source': 'His hand was again upon the window.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did it never occur to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards as the night knew?', 'source': 'He found her child and Miss Pross with her; but, it never occurred to him to be surprised by their appearance until a long time afterwards, when he sat watching them in such quiet as the night knew.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I solemnly swear to you of?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': 'that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place'}
{'question': 'If the Doctor are sure of what you say; if you really have the power do you think you have make hatchets known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he closed both again?', 'source': 'He had opened, not only the glass window, but the lattice blind outside it, and he had closed both again, and he shivered through his frame.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May it be too late?', 'source': "It may be too late, I do not know, but let it not be a minute later!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he get his arm round her?', 'source': 'He got his arm round her, and held her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Has my old pain given me a power that has brought us through the barrier, and gained us news of Charles there, and brought us here?', 'source': 'My old pain has given me a power that has brought us through the barrier, and gained us news of Charles there, and brought us here.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "Did he think, ``They have come back''?", 'source': "Soon afterwards, the bell at the great gate sounded, and he thought, ``They have come back!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Was it well guarded?', 'source': 'It was well guarded, and he got up to go among the trusty people who were watching it, when his door suddenly opened, and two figures rushed in, at sight of which he fell back in amazement.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power do you think you have make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force?', 'source': 'If you are sure of what you say; if you really have the power you think you have-- as I believe you have-- make yourself known to these devils, and get taken to La Force.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'May this be too late?', 'source': "It may be too late, I do not know, but let it not be a minute later!''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had it evidently been set up there for their purpose?', 'source': 'The people in possession of the house had let them in at the gate, and they had rushed in to work at the grindstone; it had evidently been set up there for their purpose, as in a convenient and retired spot.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Can you not possibly stir out?', 'source': 'There is no help for you in any action on your part to-night; you cannot possibly stir out.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Will I be submissive to you?', 'source': '``I will be submissive to you.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he opened?', 'source': 'He had opened, not only the glass window, but the lattice blind outside it, and he had closed both again, and he shivered through his frame.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': "What do the Doctor see in there's face than?", 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'that you know I can do nothing else than this'}
{'question': 'Must you leave your father and me alone for two minutes?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Must you not delay?', 'source': "You must leave your father and me alone for two minutes, and as there are Life and Death in the world you must not delay.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did he hold her?', 'source': 'He got his arm round her, and held her.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I know you are true?', 'source': "I know you are true.''", 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did I know it would be so?', 'source': 'I knew it would be so; I knew I could help Charles out of all danger; I told Lucie so.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Did his streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, carry him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone?', 'source': 'His streaming white hair, his remarkable face, and the impetuous confidence of his manner, as he put the weapons aside like water, carried him in an instant to the heart of the concourse at the stone.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Had he expected?', 'source': 'But, there was no loud irruption into the courtyard, as he had expected, and he heard the gate clash again, and all was quiet.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do the Doctor solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'Do I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place?', 'source': 'I solemnly swear to you that I know of no harm having happened to Charles; that I had no suspicion even of his being in this fatal place.', 'answer': ''}
{'question': 'What do I see in your face than?', 'source': 'I see in your face that you know I can do nothing else than this.', 'answer': 'that you know I can do nothing else than this'}
